<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>I&#39;m Rich from Planet MicroISV</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/im-rich-from-planet-microisv/760</link>
    <description>Hi, I&#39;m Rich. Some of you know me as the guy who&#39;s kept [Planet MicroISV][1] running for the last few years.

About a year ago I decided to make building a SaaS product a priority. After nine months I decided to kill off my first idea - partly because it was proving to be too big and partly due to stories about HIPA fines. It taught me a lot about what I don&#39;t want to do.

I&#39;m currently looking at some ideas in the advertising/ecommerce space. It&#39;s a space that I&#39;m more familiar with. This time I&#39;ll spend more time audience building first.

  [1]: http://www.planet-microisv.com/</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 06:56:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/im-rich-from-planet-microisv/760.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>I&#39;m Rich from Planet MicroISV</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[buggy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi, I’m Rich. Some of you know me as the guy who’s kept <a href="http://www.planet-microisv.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">Planet MicroISV</a> running for the last few years.</p>
<p>About a year ago I decided to make building a SaaS product a priority. After nine months I decided to kill off my first idea - partly because it was proving to be too big and partly due to stories about HIPA fines. It taught me a lot about what I don’t want to do.</p>
<p>I’m currently looking at some ideas in the advertising/ecommerce space. It’s a space that I’m more familiar with. This time I’ll spend more time audience building first.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/im-rich-from-planet-microisv/760/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/im-rich-from-planet-microisv/760/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 06:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-760-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/im-rich-from-planet-microisv/760.rss">I&#39;m Rich from Planet MicroISV</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
