<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Lalitha from the NITL team</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-lalitha-from-the-nitl-team/7148</link>
    <description>Hi everyone,

I&#39;m Lalitha, and I&#39;m part of the NITL team. NITL is a news aggregator app **that serves curated news summarised in 3 sentences or less**  - hence the name News in Three Lines (NITL). At NITL, we want to empower you to read and consume content that is intellectually stimulating, and enables you to stay updated with the latest global news.

Our news stories are aggregated from  **60+ sources**  carefully curated for breadth of perspective and geographical coverage. You can choose the topics you’re interested in, and enjoy reading news related to them. We deliver fact-based news that you can read quickly in our user-friendly application, and think critically for yourself.

**It’s free for life, no login or personal info required.**

We launched on 17th August and crossed 500 downloads recently, so far the response has been really good!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 20:17:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-lalitha-from-the-nitl-team/7148.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Lalitha from the NITL team</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[team_nitl]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi everyone,</p>
<p>I’m Lalitha, and I’m part of the NITL team. NITL is a news aggregator app <strong>that serves curated news summarised in 3 sentences or less</strong>  - hence the name News in Three Lines (NITL). At NITL, we want to empower you to read and consume content that is intellectually stimulating, and enables you to stay updated with the latest global news.</p>
<p>Our news stories are aggregated from  <strong>60+ sources</strong>  carefully curated for breadth of perspective and geographical coverage. You can choose the topics you’re interested in, and enjoy reading news related to them. We deliver fact-based news that you can read quickly in our user-friendly application, and think critically for yourself.</p>
<p><strong>It’s free for life, no login or personal info required.</strong></p>
<p>We launched on 17th August and crossed 500 downloads recently, so far the response has been really good!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-lalitha-from-the-nitl-team/7148/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-lalitha-from-the-nitl-team/7148/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 20:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-7148-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-lalitha-from-the-nitl-team/7148.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Lalitha from the NITL team</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
