<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Its been a while but I&#39;m bootstrapping again!</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/its-been-a-while-but-im-bootstrapping-again/5484</link>
    <description>Hi everyone!

My name is Greg, I had some success early in my tech career creating and selling a small sass business, since then no such luck! I&#39;ve started, stopped, failed, picked stuff up, failed again, pivoted, re-started etc. again and again. (sound familiar? - I really hope it&#39;s not just me!!)

So here I am chasing the dragon again, this time I am tackling the recruitment industry, this is through my own experience as a hiring manager (and hiring over 16 people in a 6 month period) and directly feeling the challenges in doing so.

I have started building [https://www.simplygrow.io](https://www.simplygrow.io), which is a `conversation driven` recruitment platform - the idea being that recruitment is losing the personal touch through too much automation among other things, I want to give people the tools to improve the experience for companies, recruiters and candidates and make it very personal &amp; importantly transparent again.

At this stage the only publicly facing page is the beta landing page, I am hoping for some feedback on the copy and messaging, does the message come across clearly?

Thanks so much, looking forward to being part of this community as I go through the process.

Cheers

G</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:03:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/its-been-a-while-but-im-bootstrapping-again/5484.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Its been a while but I&#39;m bootstrapping again!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[shenku]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi everyone!</p>
<p>My name is Greg, I had some success early in my tech career creating and selling a small sass business, since then no such luck! I’ve started, stopped, failed, picked stuff up, failed again, pivoted, re-started etc. again and again. (sound familiar? - I really hope it’s not just me!!)</p>
<p>So here I am chasing the dragon again, this time I am tackling the recruitment industry, this is through my own experience as a hiring manager (and hiring over 16 people in a 6 month period) and directly feeling the challenges in doing so.</p>
<p>I have started building <a href="https://www.simplygrow.io" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.simplygrow.io</a>, which is a <code>conversation driven</code> recruitment platform - the idea being that recruitment is losing the personal touch through too much automation among other things, I want to give people the tools to improve the experience for companies, recruiters and candidates and make it very personal &amp; importantly transparent again.</p>
<p>At this stage the only publicly facing page is the beta landing page, I am hoping for some feedback on the copy and messaging, does the message come across clearly?</p>
<p>Thanks so much, looking forward to being part of this community as I go through the process.</p>
<p>Cheers</p>
<p>G</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/its-been-a-while-but-im-bootstrapping-again/5484/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/its-been-a-while-but-im-bootstrapping-again/5484/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-5484-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/its-been-a-while-but-im-bootstrapping-again/5484.rss">Its been a while but I&#39;m bootstrapping again!</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
