<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Wealth creation</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415</link>
    <description>Somebody mentioned this article to me yesterday:
http://paulgraham.com/wealth.html

It&#39;s pretty interesting - has some good nuggets in there. As a bootstrapper, whenever I read PG I feel like I&#39;m being lured to the dark side or something - haha. 

His bit on wealth creation and the pie fallacy though was really helpful and actually a bit inspiring for me. 

This article was brought up in the context of talking about how we feel about competitors. I don&#39;t pay much attention to my competitors which is as it should be I think. But I still do kind of suffer from the mindset that there&#39;s a finite amount of pie. 

So this was a good reminder. Would be interesting to hear other people&#39;s thoughts on the article.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 04:32:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Wealth creation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hahahahaha.</p>
<p>"I don’t have a SaaS.</p>
<p>AMA"</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/9</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 04:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2415-9</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415.rss">Wealth creation</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Wealth creation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[scojo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="4" data-topic="2415">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/pjc/40/2627_1.png" class="avatar"> pjc:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I don’t have a Saas.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I have a sudden urge to make that into a T-shirt. <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/8</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 04:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2415-8</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415.rss">Wealth creation</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Wealth creation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Ya I mean I think that as far as larger industry trends go, you will probably find out about them if you’re paying attention generally to the industry. Not necessarily to your competitors.</p>
<p>Like for example in my field, an example of a larger change that could impact (destroy?) email marketing was gmail’s promotion tab.</p>
<p>But things that are truly innovative and disruptive in a field you’ll find out about pretty easily I think.</p>
<p>Whereas for example I used to follow my competitors on twitter and sign up for their email lists so I could keep an eye on them.</p>
<p>I have since unfollowed all of them because it was just distracting.</p>
<p>(Sent from phone)</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/7</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 20:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2415-7</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415.rss">Wealth creation</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Wealth creation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pjc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Yes. So the indirect competitors are the ones you should look at to see disruption of your business model coming, the direct competition is less interesting to track as you say.</p>
<p>Peter Thiel summarizes this much ore eloquently is his latest book where he warns that not only do you need to generate $x in value, you need to be able to capture y% of that.</p>
<p>Don’t assume the y% for your business will always be as high as it is today, is what I have been trying to say.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/6</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 16:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2415-6</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415.rss">Wealth creation</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Wealth creation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Gotcha.  So in other words what you’re saying is - you kind of have to pay attention to the competition because if not you won’t be aware of changes in technology that could impact your business in the long term.</p>
<p>I think that it probably comes back to listening to your customers.  If you see customers moving to other services, then it probably does make sense to take a close look at the competitor that they’re moving to.  Or at least to understand why they’re moving.</p>
<p>But 99% of the time, when bootstrappers are worrying about their competitors, it doesn’t have anything to do with a custom having left, and so it’s not that productive.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/5</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 15:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2415-5</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415.rss">Wealth creation</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Wealth creation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pjc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I was commenting on your statement that you don’t pay much attention to competitors.</p>
<p>I don’t have a Saas.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/4</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 18:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2415-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415.rss">Wealth creation</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Wealth creation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Ya I thought that PG’s comments on barrier to entry were pretty interesting.  I’m not sure if that’s what you’re commenting on when you talk about making the business defensible.</p>
<p>Not sure I follow the example about stripe analytics.</p>
<p>AppointmentReminder - I think I follow what you’re saying here.  Would be interesting to get <a class="mention" href="/u/patio11">@patio11</a>’s thoughts on that, but my hunch is that even on a feature level, AR is probably a lot more than Twilio + TrueVault.  I think what you find when bootstrapping and paying attention to your customers, is that you build a feature set around your niche’s needs, and that’s most likely going to be unique amongst other competitors.</p>
<p>I’m curious whether you’re coming at this from a practical perspective or more of a theoretical one.  Do you currently make a living from SaaS?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 17:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2415-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415.rss">Wealth creation</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Wealth creation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pjc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I agree that a growth mindset is what you should aim for but at the same time think about how to make your business defensible. I see a lot of “charge for value” talk in this area of the internet without any consideration for long term sustainability of the business model.</p>
<p>Take Stripe metrics for example. A lot of very nice solutions out there which add tremendous value to people running a Saas, but as this market matures why wouldn’t the ARPU go down drastically? Especially as there are complementary high margin services that can be sold based on knowing the metrics.</p>
<p>Another example is AppointmentReminder. I like how Patrick McKenzie is targeting HIPAA regulated enterprises which protects his earnings due to the high transaction costs in making a sale (which prevents perfect competition so you get monopolistic competition at ‘worst’). But for how long? With solutions like TrueVault his business now is basically Twilio + TrueVault + enterprise sales. I get that the last of those 3 is the most important one, but again, how long until an app breaks through that makes enterprise radically more efficient?</p>
<p>Maybe I just worry too much about those things but I feel this aspect of Saas or entrepreneurship in general is not covered enough here.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 16:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2415-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415.rss">Wealth creation</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Wealth creation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Somebody mentioned this article to me yesterday:<br>
<a href="http://paulgraham.com/wealth.html" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://paulgraham.com/wealth.html</a></p>
<p>It’s pretty interesting - has some good nuggets in there. As a bootstrapper, whenever I read PG I feel like I’m being lured to the dark side or something - haha.</p>
<p>His bit on wealth creation and the pie fallacy though was really helpful and actually a bit inspiring for me.</p>
<p>This article was brought up in the context of talking about how we feel about competitors. I don’t pay much attention to my competitors which is as it should be I think. But I still do kind of suffer from the mindset that there’s a finite amount of pie.</p>
<p>So this was a good reminder. Would be interesting to hear other people’s thoughts on the article.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 12:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2415-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/wealth-creation/2415.rss">Wealth creation</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
