<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>What to do with old never-launched desktop project?</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507</link>
    <description>I&#39;m hoping to get some up-to-date perspective on a quandary of mine: **what to do with an old software project I worked on, off and on, for more time than I&#39;d care to admit (years).** 

It&#39;s desktop software in the personal development domain, definitely B2C, tested on Windows and Linux but could be made to run on OSX (if I bought a used Mac). I started off as a non-coder and taught myself enough to get the project to this point, worked on it 100% just me through some tough years,  and then for various reasons let it go into never-launched abandonware. 

Checking just now, it seems I have about 60 bugs left, but would like to _maybe_ add a few more features (though I know the wisdom on this is launch, not add more). But even just these 60 bugs would probably take me 6 months of committed effort to do on my own (history has shown that bug-fixing often uncovers new bugs, so it&#39;s like kill 3 and uncover 2 more). And my life has other areas that need serious attention. In fact, after years of saying, &quot;this _has_ to be done by December 31st&quot; I no longer trust my ability much to follow through with that.

**I&#39;d love to be able to say this project amounted to something**. But I first got the idea for this so long ago that the tech scene was a completely different ecosystem (pre-iPhone!). I&#39;m wondering if desktop, B2C, low-price ($20-$40?) software sold via a website and payment processor is still viable to make even humble side money? ($200/mo?). 

If this forum is only for SaaS or mobile apps now, pardon my bumbling, but I wasn&#39;t sure where else to ask. Thanks for any insight!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 04:28:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>What to do with old never-launched desktop project?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[dgrigg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>100% agree, get a landing page and marketing started to see if there’s traction before spending any more dev time. Even if it’s just collected emails and testing interest, it could save you a lot of time and aggravation.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507/5</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 04:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4507-5</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507.rss">What to do with old never-launched desktop project?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What to do with old never-launched desktop project?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[rfctr]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="4507">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/p/dbc845/40.png" class="avatar"> pinebarron:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>But even just these 60 bugs would probably take me 6 months of committed effort to do on my own</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Tell you this: writing code is the simplest part. I can produce an enormous  amount of a quality code (and being paid for that in consulting very well), but I yet to see my first dollar coming from online sales – because it is so different and so hard.</p>
<p>So forget about fixing the bugs (unless they make the app totally unusable, not just ugly), build a site and learn the marketing stuff. If you get people to your site and then start to download and buy – then you can return to the code and fix it.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507/4</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 02:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4507-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507.rss">What to do with old never-launched desktop project?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What to do with old never-launched desktop project?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jim_Wright]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Are you familiar with the term ‘minimum viable product’?  If I were you I’d get to that - something that runs and does what it  promises, but without extra features and dare I say without polish.  Prioritize the bugs, if you there’s a bug in a feature that many will not use, nix the feature.</p>
<p>Remember, you could post it on a website as it is RIGHT NOW, and if nobody downloads it, it doesn’t matter that it’s unfinished!  Not saying you should do exactly that, but you get the point, if a tree falls in the woods…</p>
<p>If you get traction, excellent, you’ll be motivated and validated to spend time getting it polished.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507/3</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 18:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4507-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507.rss">What to do with old never-launched desktop project?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What to do with old never-launched desktop project?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <ol>
<li>
<p>What’s the product? That would make it much easier to give advice</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>There are plenty of people making a decent living selling B2C desktop software. I stand before you as evidence!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>It is cheaper and easier than ever to run a website that sells your desktop software. It will cost you close to nothing except some time to make your product as it is now available to download and buy.</p>
</li>
</ol>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 08:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4507-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507.rss">What to do with old never-launched desktop project?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What to do with old never-launched desktop project?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pinebarron]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m hoping to get some up-to-date perspective on a quandary of mine: <strong>what to do with an old software project I worked on, off and on, for more time than I’d care to admit (years).</strong></p>
<p>It’s desktop software in the personal development domain, definitely B2C, tested on Windows and Linux but could be made to run on OSX (if I bought a used Mac). I started off as a non-coder and taught myself enough to get the project to this point, worked on it 100% just me through some tough years,  and then for various reasons let it go into never-launched abandonware.</p>
<p>Checking just now, it seems I have about 60 bugs left, but would like to <em>maybe</em> add a few more features (though I know the wisdom on this is launch, not add more). But even just these 60 bugs would probably take me 6 months of committed effort to do on my own (history has shown that bug-fixing often uncovers new bugs, so it’s like kill 3 and uncover 2 more). And my life has other areas that need serious attention. In fact, after years of saying, “this <em>has</em> to be done by December 31st” I no longer trust my ability much to follow through with that.</p>
<p><strong>I’d love to be able to say this project amounted to something</strong>. But I first got the idea for this so long ago that the tech scene was a completely different ecosystem (pre-iPhone!). I’m wondering if desktop, B2C, low-price ($20-$40?) software sold via a website and payment processor is still viable to make even humble side money? ($200/mo?).</p>
<p>If this forum is only for SaaS or mobile apps now, pardon my bumbling, but I wasn’t sure where else to ask. Thanks for any insight!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 22:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4507-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-to-do-with-old-never-launched-desktop-project/4507.rss">What to do with old never-launched desktop project?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
