<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Use Programming to create Content for my Blog and Clients</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/use-programming-to-create-content-for-my-blog-and-clients/5775</link>
    <description>Hi everyone,

I&#39;m the founder of Growista. A site where I use my programming skills to analyze data and write about it.

I also offer this service to clients, most of whom have been SaaS companies.

I&#39;ve managed to score some decent publicity, managed to get some write-ups, and even got mentioned in Forbes.

You can check out my site (growista DOT com) if you&#39;re curious about my process.

Though I&#39;m doing consulting work now, I hope to switch to products of some kind as I build my audience. Happy to meet and connect with all of you.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 01:23:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/use-programming-to-create-content-for-my-blog-and-clients/5775.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Use Programming to create Content for my Blog and Clients</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[NielMalhotra]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi everyone,</p>
<p>I’m the founder of Growista. A site where I use my programming skills to analyze data and write about it.</p>
<p>I also offer this service to clients, most of whom have been SaaS companies.</p>
<p>I’ve managed to score some decent publicity, managed to get some write-ups, and even got mentioned in Forbes.</p>
<p>You can check out my site (growista DOT com) if you’re curious about my process.</p>
<p>Though I’m doing consulting work now, I hope to switch to products of some kind as I build my audience. Happy to meet and connect with all of you.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/use-programming-to-create-content-for-my-blog-and-clients/5775/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/use-programming-to-create-content-for-my-blog-and-clients/5775/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 01:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-5775-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/use-programming-to-create-content-for-my-blog-and-clients/5775.rss">Use Programming to create Content for my Blog and Clients</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
