<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363</link>
    <description>Hi everyone,

I would be thankful if you could have a look at my startup, it&#39;s trying to fix the pains related to product management, planning, roadmap, user feedback.

**Product**: Roadmap - https://roadmap.space

**Why I built it**: I quit my position as CTO of previous startup (I have a blog post describing how being [overwhelmed made me build Roadmap](https://roadmap.space/blog/2016-08-28-feeling-overwhelmed-made-me-quit-build-roadmap/)). Having a product roadmap, making sure all teams have the same vision for the product future and making sure the focus is set on the _right_ things was suddenly a must have for my next startup, so I decided to build a tool for that.

**Stage**: It was still private beta until yesterday. I&#39;m trying to get as much feedback as I can. For me, based on what I felt at previous companies, having key indicators to help decide what should be the next focus is the primary problem I would like Roadmap to solve.

In any case, I would be happy to get your feedback on the website, pricing. If you have time and are interested in having a product roadmap for your product or just want to check it out, please do not hesitate and let me know your feedback (good and bad).

I&#39;m planning for a public launch soon, once I have more detail regarding which direction to go etc.

Thanks for your time, highly appreciate.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 08:39:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Show Bootstrapped</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[dominicstpierre]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks for the comment. Engineers / Developers won’t probably see much value in Roadmap at first, because they immediately compare with a project management tool or issue tracker and similar.</p>
<p>Data-driven customer feedback is important to add data point to take decisions on what a product should accept to implement. A product roadmap is a quick and easy way for execs, Product Managers, Product Owners, Customer Success, Stakeholders to see what’s going on now and in future and making sure the company’s objectives are respected.</p>
<p>It’s a way to manage the evolution of the product thinking about problems the product is solving and not in terms of tasks (like project management tool do).</p>
<p>One problem at the moment is that our own roadmap is not very verbose, once we have a full roadmap it might start to help seeing the value.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363/7</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 08:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4363-7</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363.rss">I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Serge]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Dominic,</p>
<p>Hmm… I am an old developer and looking at the site I just don’t get it… I thing it looks great, but I just don’t get the benefit… I think that you should do some form of evangelizing… more by example maybe?</p>
<p>Or maybe I am just not your audience …</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363/6</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 03:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4363-6</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363.rss">I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[dominicstpierre]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thank you for the feedback.</p>
<p>Re: Screenshots, yep agreed, for violet, well are you talking about the widget or the general theme of Roadmap’s color? The violet for the widget is the default, there’s a blue theme as well already available.</p>
<p>The widget is optional, but is recommended as this is what gives the quantitative data like MRR when your users are voting or suggesting idea.</p>
<p>Good point for custom CSS on free plan. I’m still trying to decide what features and price tag go where.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363/5</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 09:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4363-5</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363.rss">I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[rfctr]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="4363">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/dominicstpierre/40/2990_1.png" class="avatar"> dominicstpierre:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I would be happy to get your feedback on the website</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Screenshots made my eyes hurt immediately. They are unreadable. It is better to have a portion of the UI with large font.</p>
<p>I do not like the violet background, but that might be a personal thing. Dark colours IMHO are fitting for roadmaps that ended up in a death and desolation.</p>
<p>The idea is an interesting one. Do I understand correctly the UI should be integrated into a customer site to be a part of their content?</p>
<p>I wouldn’t give the free layer the custom CSS option. Push business users to use their branded CSS - and pay for that.</p>
<p>I would also moved free layer down.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363/4</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 19:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4363-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363.rss">I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[dominicstpierre]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thank you for the kind words.</p>
<p>Pricing: Yes, the 4 columns was something I was not liking, I will put some thoughts into this for sure, agree that the free plan should be more “hidden” after pricing table.</p>
<p>Public Roadmap: Yes, in fact that will soon be the core aspect of the product (waiting for designer to get back from vacation). Hopefully, the external facing roadmap will need to produce a “wow” effect/moment. Still lots of work to do.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363/3</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 18:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4363-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363.rss">I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Megano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Looks really solid product!</p>
<p>I’ve received a lot of customer’s emails asking for an ETA for specific functionality, etc. Also, have all the customer feedback in one place is key to integrate it in the roadmap!</p>
<p>My comments:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>I’ve seen companies doing the ‘Public Roadmaps’ thing, and it’s really interesting! And most of them are using Trello boards, because it’s a good way to see clearly in which stage the functionality is (researching, doing, beta testing, etc). Did you think on something like that?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Pricing: with 4 pricing plans, I need to think a lot before deciding which one I need. You can put the free plan below (because all the plans have a free trial anyway) and reduce the noise. BTW, this is more personal opinion based on my experience with your website.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>And loved your post and the story behind Roadmap!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 16:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4363-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363.rss">I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[dominicstpierre]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi everyone,</p>
<p>I would be thankful if you could have a look at my startup, it’s trying to fix the pains related to product management, planning, roadmap, user feedback.</p>
<p><strong>Product</strong>: Roadmap - <a href="https://roadmap.space" rel="nofollow noopener">https://roadmap.space</a></p>
<p><strong>Why I built it</strong>: I quit my position as CTO of previous startup (I have a blog post describing how being <a href="https://roadmap.space/blog/2016-08-28-feeling-overwhelmed-made-me-quit-build-roadmap/" rel="nofollow noopener">overwhelmed made me build Roadmap</a>). Having a product roadmap, making sure all teams have the same vision for the product future and making sure the focus is set on the <em>right</em> things was suddenly a must have for my next startup, so I decided to build a tool for that.</p>
<p><strong>Stage</strong>: It was still private beta until yesterday. I’m trying to get as much feedback as I can. For me, based on what I felt at previous companies, having key indicators to help decide what should be the next focus is the primary problem I would like Roadmap to solve.</p>
<p>In any case, I would be happy to get your feedback on the website, pricing. If you have time and are interested in having a product roadmap for your product or just want to check it out, please do not hesitate and let me know your feedback (good and bad).</p>
<p>I’m planning for a public launch soon, once I have more detail regarding which direction to go etc.</p>
<p>Thanks for your time, highly appreciate.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 10:52:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4363-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-would-appreciate-your-feedback-on-my-saas-roadmap/4363.rss">I would appreciate your feedback on my SaaS Roadmap</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
