<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Data protection laws in the US</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/data-protection-laws-in-the-us/4911</link>
    <description>Imagine there is a company that is headquartered out of the US. They have a desktop CRM type system and the database is encrypted to make access difficult, which they could argue it a valid security measure. However, if the user of the software no longer wishes to use the software and asks to be given a dump in CSV, Excel or similar the company refuses. They could have years of important business information and if they don&#39;t pay the ongoing fee this would be lost. 

Has anyone dealt with this and have any ideas what can be done to force them to allow exporting of the information?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 10:11:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/data-protection-laws-in-the-us/4911.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Data protection laws in the US</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[craigvn]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Imagine there is a company that is headquartered out of the US. They have a desktop CRM type system and the database is encrypted to make access difficult, which they could argue it a valid security measure. However, if the user of the software no longer wishes to use the software and asks to be given a dump in CSV, Excel or similar the company refuses. They could have years of important business information and if they don’t pay the ongoing fee this would be lost.</p>
<p>Has anyone dealt with this and have any ideas what can be done to force them to allow exporting of the information?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/data-protection-laws-in-the-us/4911/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/data-protection-laws-in-the-us/4911/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 10:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4911-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/data-protection-laws-in-the-us/4911.rss">Data protection laws in the US</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
