<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Discuss @ Bootstrapped.fm - Latest posts</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm</link>
    <description>Latest posts</description>
      <item>
        <title>Dark mode: how to disable?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SteveMcLeod Steve McLeod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>The dark theme is to commemorate that we’ll be shutting down soon.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/dark-mode-how-to-disable/7690/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 06:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28043</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Dark mode: how to disable?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul1970]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi, it seems Dark Mode has been enabled for these forums… how do I turn it off again? There’s no option in the Settings that I can see. Thanks.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/dark-mode-how-to-disable/7690/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 11:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28042</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Did you ever try socks are marketing material?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@xavier]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I discovered <a href="https://sockratescustom.com/">Sockrates</a> a few weeks ago, it looks like a fun way to send a gift to your customers or in a tradeshow. They seems to work with big companies like Dell.</p>
<p>Did you tried this kind of gift already? I’m curious of the “ROI” of it</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/did-you-ever-try-socks-are-marketing-material/7689/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 19:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28041</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Future of the Bootstrapped community forum</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jwr Jan Rychter]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Well, this is really sad news — I always enjoyed visiting this forum. I don’t think there is an equivalent for people with slightly more mature businesses (not necessarily larger, just more mature, as in not just starting to build something). I visit Indie Hackers sometimes, but I don’t feel like it’s the forum for me, it’s a bit too, shall we say, indie hackery. Also, I do not believe in paid communities and have a strong initial mistrust of anything that asks me for money just so that I can contact other people like me. I do realize some of those communities could work and provide great value, but it’s difficult to judge from the outside.</p>
<p>As a bootstrapper with a mature bootstrapped business, I feel lonely most of the time: there aren’t many people in a similar situation around me, so online forums are the only place where I can find peers that I can learn from.</p>
<p>All that said, thank you <a class="mention" href="/u/stevemcleod">@SteveMcLeod</a> for running this forum for so long and for all your contributions! Your work is very much appreciated and your podcast is a great resource as well.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/future-of-the-bootstrapped-community-forum/7665/21</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 11:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28040</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Payment/hosting providers for desktop software?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@NickM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Yes, exactly. That’s what we’re after as well.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/payment-hosting-providers-for-desktop-software/7686/11</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 22:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28039</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Payment/hosting providers for desktop software?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Andy Andy Brice]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>A lot of people use Stripe. But they aren’t a ‘merchant of record’. Which means you are responsible for collecting and remitting tax. I want a merchant of record payment processor to do that for me, even if it costs more.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/payment-hosting-providers-for-desktop-software/7686/10</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 11:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28038</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Payment/hosting providers for desktop software?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@NickM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Thanks. It seems like none of the options are exactly a slam dunk.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/payment-hosting-providers-for-desktop-software/7686/9</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 10:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28037</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Payment/hosting providers for desktop software?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Andy Andy Brice]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>They were great when they were Avangate. Unfortunately they get less great with each acquisition. They recently took over a week to give me a substantive answer to a question about a customer refund, which is clearly nowhere near good enough.</p>
<p>Fastspring also used to be well regarded, but now seem famous mainly for their predatory sales practises.</p>
<p>Have heard good things about Paddle, but they aren’t the cheapest.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/payment-hosting-providers-for-desktop-software/7686/8</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 09:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28036</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Payment/hosting providers for desktop software?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@NickM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Thanks, good to know - 2Checkout was recommended in a MicroISV book which is now out of date in general, and I saw they were still going under a new name and wondered if they were any good. Considering that some of the other payment processors recommended in the book are now long gone, I kind of like the idea of someone who’s been around for a good long while. Where possible I’d rather avoid the disruption of having to switch providers.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/payment-hosting-providers-for-desktop-software/7686/7</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 10:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28031</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Payment/hosting providers for desktop software?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@NickM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Many thanks - I’ll put them on my list!</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/payment-hosting-providers-for-desktop-software/7686/6</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 10:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28030</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Payment/hosting providers for desktop software?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@charles]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I have used Paddle (<a href="https://paddle.com/">https://paddle.com/</a>) in the past – quite a wonderful solution. Nothing but good things to say about them.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/payment-hosting-providers-for-desktop-software/7686/5</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 09:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28029</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Payment/hosting providers for desktop software?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@grujicd Dejan Grujic]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>We’re using <a href="https://www.mycommerce.com/">https://www.mycommerce.com/</a> since 2005 (they were ShareIt then), without much trouble.</p>
<p>We also used Avangate, which was acquired by 2checkout, which is now called Verifone? If we forget about name changes, Avangate was also very good, with better control panel, shopping cart and support, but with occasional glitches as well.</p>
<p>They both do what you need, handle taxes, etc. For a while we used both, but we needed to integrate a bit more with payment processor, to insert new orders into our database automatically, etc. and we settled with MyCommerce.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/payment-hosting-providers-for-desktop-software/7686/4</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 19:25:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28028</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Payment/hosting providers for desktop software?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@NickM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi Gareth, that would be great. For the life of me I can’t find a way to DM you on this site, so my business partner Natasha has sent you a LinkedIn request with more info. Many thanks.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/payment-hosting-providers-for-desktop-software/7686/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 06:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28027</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Payment/hosting providers for desktop software?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gareth Gareth Hayter]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi Nick. I’m in a similar situation to you. I’m also in New Zealand, selling downloadable software products globally. Happy to have a phone-call - just reach out to me with your number via DM.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/payment-hosting-providers-for-desktop-software/7686/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 05:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28026</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Payment/hosting providers for desktop software?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@NickM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi all, sorry to be joining you at the last minute! We are a New Zealand company wanting to start selling a desktop B2B software product. As this is an old-skool downloaded item and most providers now seem to be expecting SaaS, we would really appreciate any recommendations for providers who can still deal with software downloads. Many thanks!</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/payment-hosting-providers-for-desktop-software/7686/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 02:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28025</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Future of the Bootstrapped community forum</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@unboot]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p><a class="mention" href="/u/stevemcleod">@SteveMcLeod</a> It worked by following: <a href="https://h-rd.org/archiving-a-discourse-forum/" class="inline-onebox">Archiving a Discourse Forum – H-RD.ORG</a> .</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/future-of-the-bootstrapped-community-forum/7665/20</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 12:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28020</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Future of the Bootstrapped community forum</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@unboot]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p><a class="mention" href="/u/stevemcleod">@SteveMcLeod</a> I’m trying the mirroring, and indeed it is not straightforward.  Will let you know if/when I was successful.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/future-of-the-bootstrapped-community-forum/7665/19</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 19:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28017</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Documentation app demo - feedback please</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dgrigg Derrick Grigg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Looks like an interesting idea. I really like how easy the screen shots/videos are. I think the biggest issue I see would be SEO benefit. The self hosting would get around that but then it’s most setup and moving parts.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/documentation-app-demo-feedback-please/7674/4</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 13:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28016</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>#159: Enterprise sales hell, SEO frustration and self-doubt</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@regof Reginald O.]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Awesome, many thanks <a class="mention" href="/u/stevemcleod">@SteveMcLeod</a>!</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/159-enterprise-sales-hell-seo-frustration-and-self-doubt/7345/9</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 16:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28015</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>#159: Enterprise sales hell, SEO frustration and self-doubt</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SteveMcLeod Steve McLeod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Welcome!</p>
<p>The content agency I use is <a href="https://www.scribly.io/">https://www.scribly.io/</a></p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/159-enterprise-sales-hell-seo-frustration-and-self-doubt/7345/8</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 14:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28014</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>#159: Enterprise sales hell, SEO frustration and self-doubt</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@regof Reginald O.]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hey <a class="mention" href="/u/stevemcleod">@SteveMcLeod</a></p>
<p>I am new to the bootstrapped.fm podcast as I’m a fresh SaaS entrepreneur. I am loving it and much appeciae time invested to create such a helpful resource.<br>
Towards the end of the episode you guys discussed having success with a content production agency. Any chance that you could share which agency this is/was?</p>
<p>Keep up the great work!</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/159-enterprise-sales-hell-seo-frustration-and-self-doubt/7345/7</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 13:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28013</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Documentation app demo - feedback please</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mattbearman Matt Bearman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Thanks <a class="mention" href="/u/serge">@Serge</a>, it’s awesome to get an enterprise perspective. That’s a great point about the people writing the docs not being those creating the screenshots. That’s exactly how it was when I worked at FreeAgent (a 250+ person company).</p>
<p>I’m primarily aiming at small/1 person web apps, simply because that’s something I know about from running Saber. I found it hard to keep on top of docs, with screenshots and videos taking a lot of time. Of course in those companies it is mostly likely the same person writing the docs and taking screenshots.</p>
<p>That said if this tool could be useful to large companies that would also be great <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>The demo I’ve built is doesn’t interfere with the customer site at all, and doesn’t require a browser plugin. Instead it loads the site being documented in an iframe. Of course that could be a problem depending on the customer’s <code>Content-Security-Policy</code>, I’m hoping for the majority of users it will be fine as they’ll be able to run the docs app on their own subdomain. Worst case scenario they’ll have to modify their <code>frame-src</code> directive to include that domain.</p>
<p>When you say yearly licence do you mean for an entirely self-hosted on site version (ie: both the docs <em>and</em> the tool to create them are self-hosted)? As that’s a road I definitely do not want to go down. The back end service is required even if you’re exporting doc’s HTML for self hosting, as the screenshots and videos are initially saved locally as blobs, those blobs need to be uploaded to a server for the rest of the world to see.</p>
<p>Thanks again for filling in the form, and Open Source Drums looks really cool, I’ll definitely be following that <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/blush.png?v=9" title=":blush:" class="emoji" alt=":blush:"></p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/documentation-app-demo-feedback-please/7674/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 05:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28011</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Documentation app demo - feedback please</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Serge Serge]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Interesting idea. I gave you some feedback from my Enterprize point of view. Might not be the target customer but the problem exists in large dev shops too. Documentation is always a poor child and the biggest hurdle is that the people writing the documentation are always asking for screen shots…and no one in the team has time to do those screen shot for them… and often times, they don’t have full access to a customer version of the app (we do custom dev too…large enterprises…) Nice also that you can get a movie out of it simply… That is way cool… It should not interfere with our app though, so it is a browser extension? That would be the best…</p>
<p>I sure would have our doc team look at it. Not sure about the monthly model though. Much easier to get a licence price for it… even if it is for one year maintenance… 300$ per seat is a no brainer… even more is possible I think … I would actually try it at 799$ a seat with enterprise and see what you get…</p>
<p>Naturally, self hosting is a must for usecases like the one I am talking about. Even if I was documenting one of my own apps, I would want to self host… Splits my brain to have my doc hosted on another host…</p>
<p>Hope this helps.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/documentation-app-demo-feedback-please/7674/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 19:34:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28010</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Future of the Bootstrapped community forum</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SteveMcLeod Steve McLeod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Seems it can be done, but it is not straightforward.</p>
<p>There’s info on Discourse’s own site here: <a href="https://meta.discourse.org/t/a-basic-discourse-archival-tool/62614/48" class="inline-onebox">A basic Discourse archival tool - #48 by kamcc - dev - Discourse Meta</a></p>
<p>If someone is brave enough to give this a try, I’m happy to take care of hosting.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/future-of-the-bootstrapped-community-forum/7665/18</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 12:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28007</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Future of the Bootstrapped community forum</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@unboot]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Not sure if its feasible, but maybe it’s possible to keep a static copy of the content online?</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/future-of-the-bootstrapped-community-forum/7665/17</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 14:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28003</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Future of the Bootstrapped community forum</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul1970]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I came here when “The Business of Software” forum shut down, and to be honest this place just never felt the same as what it was over there, so it doesn’t really surprise me that you’re shutting down. Seems that online forums for bootstrappers / micro ISVs just aren’t a happening thing anymore. Thanks anyway! <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/future-of-the-bootstrapped-community-forum/7665/16</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 04:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-28002</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Documentation app demo - feedback please</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mattbearman Matt Bearman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi all, some of you may remember me as the former owner of Saber Feedback. I’ve been living the 9-5 life for a couple of years now, but the old side project itch has returned <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/blush.png?v=9" title=":blush:" class="emoji" alt=":blush:"></p>
<p>I realise this community is not long for this world, but I’d really appreciate feedback from you all on my <em>very</em> early stage project. (It’s just a demo video and some basic questions at the moment)</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric" data-onebox-src="https://forms.gle/aNiw1Wp5gejjqGPy9">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/spreadsheets/forms/favicon_qp2.png" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">

      <a href="https://forms.gle/aNiw1Wp5gejjqGPy9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Docs</a>
  </header>

  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/362;"><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/DQMjlyZPy7hM31OXUp6EIyXm3M3fxwjKdaqZkx7eVguzVi8Ka5sHthYnIoDuyORySpw4IWvJ7Lo=w1200-h630-p" class="thumbnail" width="690" height="362"></div>

<h3><a href="https://forms.gle/aNiw1Wp5gejjqGPy9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Documentation tool research</a></h3>

  <p>I'm currently developing a tool which aims to be the quickest and easiest way to create and manage documentation and knowledge bases for web apps. Basically it's the tool I wish I had when I was running Saber Feedback.

I've got as far as building a...</p>


  </article>

  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>

  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>Thanks<br>
Matt</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/documentation-app-demo-feedback-please/7674/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 07:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-27999</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Future of the Bootstrapped community forum</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mattbearman Matt Bearman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Like most people here, I think it’s sad but completely understandable news. Especially sad for me as I’ve been planning to get back into the bootstrapped side project world and so was planning to be more active again here in the near future</p>
<p>Incidentally I started a small slack group for solo bootstrappers a few years ago, if anyone here would be interested in joining send me a message.</p>
<p>Thanks for everything you’ve done <a class="mention" href="/u/stevemcleod">@SteveMcLeod</a> <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/blush.png?v=9" title=":blush:" class="emoji" alt=":blush:"></p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/future-of-the-bootstrapped-community-forum/7665/15</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 07:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-27998</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Future of the Bootstrapped community forum</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Sergey_Kornilov Sergey Kornilov]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>It is a bit sad but fully understandable. Totally appreciate all the time and effort you put into this, Steve.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/future-of-the-bootstrapped-community-forum/7665/14</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 16:16:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-27997</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Future of the Bootstrapped community forum</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Andy Andy Brice]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>That is sad news. But I haven’t been very active myself. I completely understand your decision and would probably do the same, if I was you. I appreciate you keeping it going this long.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/future-of-the-bootstrapped-community-forum/7665/13</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:24:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-27996</guid>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
