<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Inside MageMail</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/inside-magemail/2416</link>
    <description>Hey guys, I was kind of inspired by Rob Walling&#39;s startup documentary and also have been getting a little addicted to podcasting as me and a buddy started one in our niche a couple months ago.

So I setup a tag on my blog called &quot;Inside MageMail&quot; and I&#39;ve started putting quick audio clips up:
http://kalenjordan.com/tagged/insidemagemail

There&#39;s also a podcast RSS feed that you can subscribe to.

Basically the plan is to talk about startup life / bootstrapping topics and whatever random ideas come to mind from time to time :smile:   

This isn&#39;t a business opportunity type thing - just kind of a way to vent some of the ideas I have from time to time, and maybe if there are one or two people that could benefit from it, that&#39;s cool as well.

Not really looking for critiques per se, but any feedback / discussion around the topics mentioned in there would be welcome.  :smile:</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 17:50:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/inside-magemail/2416.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Inside MageMail</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey guys, I was kind of inspired by Rob Walling’s startup documentary and also have been getting a little addicted to podcasting as me and a buddy started one in our niche a couple months ago.</p>
<p>So I setup a tag on my blog called “Inside MageMail” and I’ve started putting quick audio clips up:<br>
<a href="http://kalenjordan.com/tagged/insidemagemail" class="onebox" target="_blank">http://kalenjordan.com/tagged/insidemagemail</a></p>
<p>There’s also a podcast RSS feed that you can subscribe to.</p>
<p>Basically the plan is to talk about startup life / bootstrapping topics and whatever random ideas come to mind from time to time <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=9" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
<p>This isn’t a business opportunity type thing - just kind of a way to vent some of the ideas I have from time to time, and maybe if there are one or two people that could benefit from it, that’s cool as well.</p>
<p>Not really looking for critiques per se, but any feedback / discussion around the topics mentioned in there would be welcome.  <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=9" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/inside-magemail/2416/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/inside-magemail/2416/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 17:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2416-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/inside-magemail/2416.rss">Inside MageMail</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
