<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jack Johnson from Pivotal Knowledge</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jack-johnson-from-pivotal-knowledge/639</link>
    <description>Hi, all -

Coming out of Lurk Mode long enough for a brief introduction...

I&#39;ve been a self-employed IT / Network Consultant &amp; sometime software developer for a bit over 20 years - yes, I&#39;m a literal Graybeard Geek. I used to sell a couple of desktop apps, but they didn&#39;t generate enough profit to justify the time I put into them, so I shut them down. 

I&#39;ve been wanting to do another product-oriented business for a while now, but:
a) It seems the best ways to generate new consulting work are to either start working on an app or schedule a vacation...
and
b) I suffer from both TMIA (Too Many Ideas Affliction) and SOS (Shiny Object Syndrome).
:smiley:

I&#39;m taking a few (OK, too many) steps to jumpstart things, including listening to some new-to-me podcasts such as e.g. bootstrapped, which is how I got here... I see a number of familiar faces from places like the old BOS forum, ASP, Micropreneur Academy, and others, so I&#39;m feeling pretty much at home already.

I&#39;m enjoying the podcast &amp; the forum, and I look forward to many fruitful discussions here!

- Jack  

P.S. I just realized my account / gravatar points to my photography website - among the Too Many Things I do, I&#39;m a landscape / nature photographer...  so naturally, I have a couple of photography-related things in my TMIA list... :smiley:
 </description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 15:10:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jack-johnson-from-pivotal-knowledge/639.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jack Johnson from Pivotal Knowledge</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack_V_Johnson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi, all -</p>
<p>Coming out of Lurk Mode long enough for a brief introduction…</p>
<p>I’ve been a self-employed IT / Network Consultant &amp; sometime software developer for a bit over 20 years - yes, I’m a literal Graybeard Geek. I used to sell a couple of desktop apps, but they didn’t generate enough profit to justify the time I put into them, so I shut them down.</p>
<p>I’ve been wanting to do another product-oriented business for a while now, but:<br>
a) It seems the best ways to generate new consulting work are to either start working on an app or schedule a vacation…<br>
and<br>
b) I suffer from both TMIA (Too Many Ideas Affliction) and SOS (Shiny Object Syndrome).<br>
<img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smiley.png?v=5" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:"></p>
<p>I’m taking a few (OK, too many) steps to jumpstart things, including listening to some new-to-me podcasts such as e.g. bootstrapped, which is how I got here… I see a number of familiar faces from places like the old BOS forum, ASP, Micropreneur Academy, and others, so I’m feeling pretty much at home already.</p>
<p>I’m enjoying the podcast &amp; the forum, and I look forward to many fruitful discussions here!</p>
<ul>
<li>Jack</li>
</ul>
<p>P.S. I just realized my account / gravatar points to my photography website - among the Too Many Things I do, I’m a landscape / nature photographer…  so naturally, I have a couple of photography-related things in my TMIA list… <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smiley.png?v=5" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jack-johnson-from-pivotal-knowledge/639/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jack-johnson-from-pivotal-knowledge/639/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 15:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-639-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jack-johnson-from-pivotal-knowledge/639.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jack Johnson from Pivotal Knowledge</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
