<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Building an email list</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/building-an-email-list/5245</link>
    <description>I&#39;m working on writing a free guide about how to build an email list. Perhaps somewhat ironically, the purpose of this free guide will be to help build my own email list for my new business, [Landing Page Breakdowns](https://www.landingpagebreakdowns.com/).

I think the guide will cover things like:
- How to get traffic (huge topic, I know - I&#39;ll just touch on basics)
- What a lead magnet is and how to use one to get people to sign up for your list
- How to design your landing page so that it converts well
- What tools to use to build your landing page and measure its performance
- How to communicate with subscribers once they&#39;ve signed up for your list

Here&#39;s what I want to ask you guys:

1. Does this sound like something you&#39;d want to read?
2. What kinds of questions would you have about building an email list?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 14:07:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/building-an-email-list/5245.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Building an email list</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jasonswett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m working on writing a free guide about how to build an email list. Perhaps somewhat ironically, the purpose of this free guide will be to help build my own email list for my new business, <a href="https://www.landingpagebreakdowns.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">Landing Page Breakdowns</a>.</p>
<p>I think the guide will cover things like:</p>
<ul>
<li>How to get traffic (huge topic, I know - I’ll just touch on basics)</li>
<li>What a lead magnet is and how to use one to get people to sign up for your list</li>
<li>How to design your landing page so that it converts well</li>
<li>What tools to use to build your landing page and measure its performance</li>
<li>How to communicate with subscribers once they’ve signed up for your list</li>
</ul>
<p>Here’s what I want to ask you guys:</p>
<ol>
<li>Does this sound like something you’d want to read?</li>
<li>What kinds of questions would you have about building an email list?</li>
</ol>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/building-an-email-list/5245/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/building-an-email-list/5245/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 14:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-5245-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/building-an-email-list/5245.rss">Building an email list</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
