<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745</link>
    <description>Now that Digital River has announced they are discontinuing Software 
Passport / Armadillo as of 1 July, I&#39;m looking for a replacement - just a
 “remind honest people they&#39;re honest” solution for some new Delphi 
Windows desktop apps I&#39;m starting. Anybody care to share what you&#39;re 
using?



Thanks,



Jack</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 02:42:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[rfctr]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="28" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/u/dfb087/40.png" class="avatar"> unicorm:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>And honestly I think you are not fully disclosing who you are.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Well, the same applies to you, eh.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/33</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 02:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-33</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[unicorm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Listen buddy, a software protection that is blocked by every second antivirus on the planet doesn’t help us on Windows. Maybe it’s no issue for you, but in most major developed markets, it is.</p>
<p>PELock is not helping us out on Mac or Linux. So it’s virtually useless for us.</p>
<p>And its funny that every time I prove you wrong you come up with some other accusations. Why don’t you address all the problems I pointed out instead? Proof me wrong, not Wyatt.</p>
<p>My points are</p>
<ul>
<li>Gets blocked by antivirus</li>
<li>Doesn’t work for Mac or Linux</li>
</ul>
<p>Maybe you can help me better understand:</p>
<ul>
<li>How can I revoke licenses in PELock (credit card fraud does happen, as do cancelled orders)?</li>
<li>Are licenses hardware locked? Or can a user use the license key as often as he wants (which is exactly what Wyatt addresses and that is more important to us than cracks - people are more likely to share a license key than to download a crack)</li>
<li>Is there an activation server? Can I manage my licenses online?</li>
<li>How are Virtual Machines handled in PELock?</li>
<li>What about offline/online activations, trials and trial extensions?</li>
</ul>
<p>I didn’t find these answers on the webpage directly. Maybe you can help me answer them.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/32</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 10:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-32</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[MarcWells]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Listen, Wyatt’s <strong>fanboy</strong> - just because you love this guy, <strong>doesn’t automatically make his product great</strong>. Look at this thread from the very top, he did make the accusations and I just can’t agree with it, because our approach is working for us good, we <strong>are free from cracks, keygens, serials</strong>. We stopped piracy with Armadillo too in the past, it’s not just PELock.</p>
<p>Most of my developer friends actually care about their software NOT BEING CRACKED, PATCHED OR KEYGENNED, and they don’t care what means are neccessarry to achieve that - if it’s an exe protection, virtualization, just long as it resists cracking attempts or delays them.</p>
<p>Now - I write here about our experiences and our approach that works for us for many years and people like Wyatt and his fanboys are trying to convince me that we are doing it all wrong. <strong>How we are doing it all wrong, if it just works?</strong></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/31</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 09:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-31</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[MarcWells]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>We are using built-in PHP keygen integrated with our website:</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://assets-cdn.github.com/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://github.com/PELock/PELock-Software-Protection-and-Licensing-SDK/tree/master/Examples/English/4.%20Keygen" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">GitHub</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/7449321?s=400&amp;v=4" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="279" height="279">

<h3><a href="https://github.com/PELock/PELock-Software-Protection-and-Licensing-SDK/tree/master/Examples/English/4.%20Keygen" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">PELock/PELock-Software-Protection-and-Licensing-SDK</a></h3>

<p>PELock-Software-Protection-and-Licensing-SDK - Software copy protection against cracking &amp; reverse engineering with anti-cracking &amp; anti-debugging techniques. Software license key system wi...</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/30</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 09:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-30</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[unicorm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Btw: how can I dynamically create and revoke licenses and integrate PELock into my shopping system? With LimeLM and Fastspring it literally took me 3h to have everything up and running. Dynamic key generation with different license models. Who else can do THAT?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/29</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 06:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-29</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[unicorm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Sorry, Marc, but I think you have very little idea what you are talking about.</p>
<ol>
<li>Your friends software got cracked because the license check verification in machine code of the executable was replaced. It’s not LimeLMs fault. EVERY license protection has this problem - unless you mix up the code and then get flagged by Antivirus.</li>
<li>ALL those issues you mention in the forum are either customers’ faults or have been resolved.</li>
</ol>
<aside class="quote" data-post="27" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/m/8797f3/40.png" class="avatar"> MarcWells:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Windows 10 Anniversary Update breaks all Lime activations</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Nobody else had this problem, other users immediately tested and could not confirm.[quote=“MarcWells, post:27, topic:1745”]<br>
Customers can’t connect to verify the license (Australia / New Zealand)<br>
[/quote]<br>
Has been resolved with 3.4.7</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="27" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/m/8797f3/40.png" class="avatar"> MarcWells:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Virtual Machine Error (TA_E_IN_VM, VirtualMachineException, Window 10, Hyper-V)</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Well, Hyper-VM in Windows IS a virtual machine by definition, so you have to allow them…</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="27" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/m/8797f3/40.png" class="avatar"> MarcWells:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>URGENT: IsGenuine returns InternetError</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>For the 4 years we have been using LimeLM, the servers have been down for maybe 3 hours. TWO customers had a problem. TWO.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="27" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/m/8797f3/40.png" class="avatar"> MarcWells:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>limelm dashboard not working</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Never really experienced that.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="27" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/m/8797f3/40.png" class="avatar"> MarcWells:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>TurboActivate 3.4.7 on Linux Static - new dependency?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>PELock doesn’t even support Linux… So why complain?</p>
<p>You are a troll, Marc. And honestly I think you are not fully disclosing who you are. [quote=“MarcWells, post:27, topic:1745”]<br>
it doesn’t protect anything from cracking - it’s just a licensing solution<br>
it’s not compatible with latest Windows 10 operating system<br>
it’s buggy as hell from the forum entries<br>
its network is DDoSed on a regular basis and the entire thing is down for EVERYONE</p>
<p>poor SDK, it doesn’t even support Delphi<br>
[/quote]<br>
LimeLM protects from casual piracy. It does that very well. Casual piracy - <strong>as I and Wyatt pointed out</strong> - is that a license key cannot be used beyond the number of legit activations. <strong>EVERY software can be cracked if the machine code of the executable is manipulated</strong>. <strong>Obsfurcating and bullshittig whatever the machine code is not possible in real life because antivirus solutions F</strong>** y** ** It is compatible with Win 10 and the latest Win 10 update, it is not buggy as hell - but in real life, software licensing is f***** complex. It is not correct that regular DDoS attacks cause problems. There has been one incident in my four years of using it - and it has been resolved through CloudFlare. SDK is not poor - although I don’t know how well Delphi is supported.</p>
<p>Since you are such a m***** about other people’s products, let me be one as well:</p>
<ul>
<li>PELock cannot be used in mass markets because it is blocked by antivirus</li>
<li>PELock works for Windows only and is useless for Mac and Linux</li>
</ul>
<p>In theory, PELock <strong>MAY</strong> appear like a great solution, but it simply doesn’t work in real life. Let me quote the founder of PELock again:</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="22" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/u/dfb087/40.png" class="avatar"> unicorm:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>But when someone wants to use our products they usually find themselves in troubles because of the low quality antivirus products who tags protected software as a virus.</p>
<p>I have lost many customers because they wouldn’t accept this to happen to their final products (imagine someone downloads their software and antivirus warning pops up – it’s a disaster for software maker), and there are so many antivirus products on the market it’s virtually impossible to cooperate even with a small number of their developers (I don’t even have to tell you it’s hard or even impossible to reach them and work out some solution)."</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p><strong>Marc, I think it is funny, that you ONLY comment about this very one topic. It seems like you signed up for this forum only to badmouth Wyatt. You have lost all credibility.</strong></p>
<p>In my experience:</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="23" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/gareth/40/2547_1.png" class="avatar"> Gareth:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Obfuscate your code to prevent ‘easy’ stealing of your IP. (everything can be reverse engineered in the end)<br>
Implement some sort of licensing.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I am not sure how obfuscating helps - maybe for NET compiled software which can be easily reverse engineered. But in practice, reverse engineering of executables is essentially impossible. Obfuscation can cause problems with antivirus software actually. So a lot of credible people I know actually recommend not to do.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="23" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/gareth/40/2547_1.png" class="avatar"> Gareth:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Check for valid license in multiple places in your code.<br>
Change the name and signature of your license checking function with each release.<br>
Change the location of checks in each release - do this by adding placeholders (maybe special comments eg /* LICENSE_CHECK_LOCATION */) where license checks CAN be added.<br>
Create a pre-build process that modifies your source-code files by randomly selecting a sub-set of these locations and replacing the placeholders with a call to the license check function.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<ul>
<li>Checking valid licenses in multiple places doesn’t really realistically solve the problem in our experience. Machine code calls stay very similar, rather not so hard for the crackers</li>
<li>Name and signature of license: I do not know what you mean by that. Does help (aka crackers need a new crack), but for popular software it happens very quickly. It is not so easy for an executable to check whether it has been tampered (e.g. whether its certificate is valid). For my understanding its impossible.</li>
<li>Change location of checks: yes, makes life a little bit harder for crackers, but like I said, for popular software it doesn’t help.</li>
<li>I don’t know how this random location selection would work - but I think that many of the suggestions here come at cost for testing and usability. You don’t want your legit customers run into issues, and I do not know how randomizing the process makes testing etc. easier and reliable.</li>
</ul>
<aside class="quote" data-post="26" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/cadbloke/40/1341_1.png" class="avatar"> cadbloke:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Get a code-signing certificate and sign your code. If it is tampered with then everybody will know. Make a point of telling everybody that if the code isn’t signed (show them how to check) then it has been hacked, they are vulnerable to malware (hackers are bad, m’kaaaaay) and they bear that risk alone. This risk-aversion will work better in B2B than B2C because the freetards are overrepresented in “C” and so understand / care less about the malware risk.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Actually, we had people sending us screenshots of the cracked version complaining that Windows detected a tampered code signing certificate calling US out for it. And they sent it from their corporate accounts. We started going after the filesharers and that really reduced the cracking problem by 70% or so. Which is enough for us. Code signing certificates help quite a bit with antivirus false positives - but not always… Funny enough those cracks are usually infected by spyware. But people are cheap and often don’t care. People will never be fully honest with software.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="27" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/m/8797f3/40.png" class="avatar"> MarcWells:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>So mr. Wyatt - you’re good at one thing. Selling bullsh*t.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>You are a troll. You only signed up in this forum to spread FALSE rumours about Wyatt. Actually, you probably committed a crime depending on where you live - placing false information to financially harm somebody is called defamation. But I guess in Russia they don’t care so much about that <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
<p>Yeah, now it’s 8 am here in Southern France. Just getting up to do some flying and enjoying my vacation <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> Big Wyatt fan.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/28</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 06:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-28</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[MarcWells]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>You made me to look into this LimeLM. And what do we find on their own offical forums? A long list of bugs that’s for sure:</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Windows 10 Anniversary Update breaks all Lime activations</strong><br>
<a href="http://wyday.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=27050" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">wyday.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=27050</a></p>
<p>That must be good for all of LimeLM customers users <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/sleepy.png?v=5" title=":sleepy:" class="emoji" alt=":sleepy:"></p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Customers can’t connect to verify the license (Australia / New Zealand)</strong><br>
<a href="http://wyday.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=26970" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">wyday.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=26970</a></p>
<p>They must be happy too :), but I guess USA is the only country in the world worth support.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Virtual Machine Error (TA_E_IN_VM, VirtualMachineException, Window 10, Hyper-V)</strong><br>
<a href="http://wyday.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=27035" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">wyday.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=27035</a></p>
<p>Problems on Windows 10?</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>URGENT: IsGenuine returns InternetError</strong><br>
<a href="http://wyday.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=27027" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">wyday.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=27027</a></p>
<p>So you got DDoSed frequently? That must be also good for the entire operation working <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
<hr>
<p><strong>limelm dashboard not working</strong><br>
<a href="http://wyday.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=27025" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">wyday.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=27025</a></p>
<p>Who cares, right?</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>TurboActivate 3.4.7 on Linux Static - new dependency?</strong><br>
<a href="http://wyday.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=27071" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">wyday.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=27071</a></p>
<p>Doesn’t work on Linux?</p>
<hr>
<p>So lets bring all those features of LimeLM into one nice picture:</p>
<ul>
<li>it doesn’t protect anything from cracking - it’s just a licensing solution</li>
<li>it’s not compatible with latest Windows 10 operating system</li>
<li>it’s buggy as hell from the forum entries</li>
<li>its network is DDoSed on a regular basis and the entire thing is down for <strong>EVERYONE</strong>
</li>
<li>poor SDK, it doesn’t even support Delphi</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>So mr. Wyatt - you’re good at one thing. Selling bullsh*t</strong></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/27</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 00:11:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-27</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[cadbloke]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Get a code-signing certificate and sign your code. If it is tampered with then everybody will know. Make a point of telling everybody that if the code isn’t signed (show them how to check) then it has been hacked, they are vulnerable to malware (hackers are bad, m’kaaaaay) and they bear that risk alone. This risk-aversion will work better in B2B than B2C because the <a href="http://www.seobook.com/freetards" rel="nofollow noopener">freetards</a> are overrepresented in “C” and so understand / care less about the malware risk.</p>
<p>It also helps to understand the difference between licensing and crack-protection - one makes being honest the most-painless workflow, the other is the war against drugs.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/26</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 22:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-26</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[MarcWells]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Gareth let’s wait for the Wyatt tirade about how obfuscation is ineffective (he wrote about it), so we all just STFU and use his software without <em>any</em> reason at all hehe <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/25</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 22:24:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-25</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[MarcWells]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="22" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/u/dfb087/40.png" class="avatar"> unicorm:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>limit casual piracy</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Limit casual piracy with no protection? Sounds like a snake oil :). You have missed a really important point - LimeLM is not a software proteciton at all, so why argue about software protection, when all you want to do is to be able to use easy licensing features?</p>
<p>My friend got <strong>f****d up by LimeLM</strong> licensing feature the day he released his software, the next day to be honest (a cracked version popped up). Well - <strong>reality</strong> isn’t what Wyatt thinks it is and your ignorance is really interesting to me, because it seems you don’t care about cracked copies of your software, just a fancy way to activate it <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> <strong>AGAIN THIS ISN’T SOFTWARE PROTECTION</strong></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/24</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 22:22:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-24</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Gareth]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <ul>
<li>Obfuscate your code to prevent ‘easy’ stealing of your IP. (everything can be reverse engineered in the end)</li>
<li>Implement some sort of licensing.</li>
</ul>
<p>Then, to reduce the ease of someone creating a crack for ALL versions of your product:</p>
<ul>
<li>Check for valid license in multiple places in your code.</li>
<li>Change the name <strong>and signature</strong> of your license checking function with each release.</li>
<li>Change the location of checks in each release - do this by adding placeholders (maybe special comments eg /* LICENSE_CHECK_LOCATION */) where license checks CAN be added.</li>
<li>Create a pre-build process that modifies your source-code files by randomly selecting a sub-set of these locations and replacing the placeholders with a call to the license check function.</li>
</ul>
<p>The steps above will make it fairly difficult (not impossible) for someone to create a crack for all versions of your product. Due to the different check locations and the license checking function name and signature changing with every release, any crack will only apply to a specific version. So then, you just need to release new versions more frequently.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/23</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 22:07:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-23</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[unicorm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Well, I suppose that if you are so successful and rich as you are implying you are thanks to your obviously superior software protection PELock my only question is: why do you waste your time in online forums? At least I do drive a fancy BMW and enjoy 8 weeks of vacation every year. And I spend it flying around expensive planes. Well, the reason why I BOTHER to reply here is because thanks to Wyatt I am not driving a Chrysler.</p>
<p>We cannot use PELock (like probably a lot of companies with software products) because it is Windows only. Our market is 50% Mac. Probably you missed that detail. Oh, and it also does Linux. Wyatt delivers what he promises. A reliable software solution that can be used to reduce / limit casual piracy on essentially any platform. Let me do the math for you: we use PELock - we lose 50% of our market. Will we double our Windows sales because PELock is so much better than LimeLM? No. Why? Well, because as mentioned earlier, the biggest problem are currently filesharers for “cracked” software - and those can be taken down quite effectively. Unless you turn the executable file in a mess - in essence every software can be cracked because its machine code. And to be quite honest: I don’t want to deal with all these antivirus programs blocking this mess. We have enough funny surprises with legit libraries (e.g. Qt). I would guess that 50% of our potential Windows customers could not run the file because their antivirus blocks it. Ah, funny story, the owner of PELock actually admits this:<br>
"Brian – me and my friends who develops software protection technologies (aka exe-protectors, exe-packers, code virtualizers, license key systems) are innocent victims of those antivirus engines who tags anything suspicious as a potential virus (false positive detection).</p>
<p>Software like PELock, Themida, VMprotect, Armadillo, Obsidium are used to protect legit software products against cracks, patches, keygens and all kind of nasty stuff from the hands of crackers.</p>
<p><strong>But when someone wants to use our products they usually find themselves in troubles because of the low quality antivirus products who tags protected software as a virus.</strong></p>
<p><strong>I have lost many customers because they wouldn’t accept this to happen to their final products (imagine someone downloads their software and antivirus warning pops up – it’s a disaster for software maker), and there are so many antivirus products on the market it’s virtually impossible to cooperate even with a small number of their developers (I don’t even have to tell you it’s hard or even impossible to reach them and work out some solution).</strong>"<br>
(<a href="http://krebsonsecurity.com/2014/05/antivirus-is-dead-long-live-antivirus/" rel="nofollow noopener">http://krebsonsecurity.com/2014/05/antivirus-is-dead-long-live-antivirus/</a>)</p>
<p>Well, guess what. If we used PELock, we would have shit our pants many years ago because of random crazy users sh*** about antivirus warnings in forums. <strong>You can’t use it in a mass market and the founder admits it.</strong></p>
<p>Wyatt is probably the ONLY one who does not claim what you say. He doesn’t say he has the only solution. He doesn’t say his solution is the best. He is simply honest. He has a great product. A good friend works for a very large company selling software products that bill hundreds of k USD per license (you know, the kind that makes nuclear powerplants work) and has been working on software protection for over a decade. He said the same thing. “Every mechanism a human invents can be circumvented by humans. There is no perfect protection”. And last but not least: We are selling a product that has to run fast and efficient. High CPU/GPU usage. LimeLM really is slick and lean. And it does not get killed by security software.</p>
<p>It’s remarkable that Wyatt still puts so much effort into replying to trolls trowing around with whatever accusations. I wouldn’t. I doubt you are actually selling anything close to what you are stating. Otherwise you would have run into these issues.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/22</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 21:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-22</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[MarcWells]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Sir, you’re selling licensing solution and I understand your frustration over the competition products, from our exeprience with PELock <strong>it protects against cracking or at least stops those attempts</strong> and it works, it works in real life conditions.</p>
<p>I know many stories from fellow programmers about their software cracked in no time (including my friend who used <strong>YOUR LimeLM</strong> system!).</p>
<p>You are right, there’s no thing as uncrackable protection, but your misinterpretation of the PELock’s page headers is just wrong and harmful. If any protection will help me to delay or discourage crackers from trying to crack our software - I’ll be more than happy to pay for it!</p>
<p>Your solution <strong>doesn’t even try to stop it</strong>. You don’t even try to hide this fact. Even your own customers says LimeLM doesn’t protect from cracks! <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/joy.png?v=5" title=":joy:" class="emoji" alt=":joy:"> By reading your articles I have doubts you have any decent knowledge about software protection and how it works on the <strong>battlefield</strong>.</p>
<p>You are selling a lie in a nice package and you try to convince everyone else your solution is the correct one and anything else is flawed. Well you know what? You’re simply wrong. There are better solutions that try to address some important issues, they might be not perfect, not uncrackable, but it just works. Even if you don’t agree with it.</p>
<p>And there’s no reason to argue with a person who thinks there’s no point in software protection just because everything can be cracked.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/21</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 20:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-21</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[wyattoday]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="18" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/m/8797f3/40.png" class="avatar"> MarcWells:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Why would anyone use LimeLM if it doesn’t protect against cracking?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Well, this is explained in the 2nd and 3rd paragraphs in <a href="https://wyday.com/limelm/features/why/" rel="nofollow noopener">the article I linked to</a>, under the headline “<strong>What is software licensing?</strong>”:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Software licensing allows you to get paid for each copy of your software. The types of software licensing come in a few general forms which I’ll be covering in the next section. With few exceptions the “hardware-locked” licensing is best for businesses because it allows you to have absolute control over where your software is installed.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The point of licensing <em>isn’t</em> to stop crackers from cracking your software. <strong>The point of licensing is to increase your revenue by preventing casual piracy</strong> (using serials over and over again). There is real money to be made by stopping casual piracy.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Nowhere on our site do we claim to stop cracking. If customers ask about it we explicitly tell them our product does not stop cracking. <strong>No product can stop cracking.</strong> Trust me, if it were possible to stop cracking we would make a product and sell it in a heartbeat. <strong>It’s not possible.</strong></p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="18" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/m/8797f3/40.png" class="avatar"> MarcWells:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Why would anyone use LimeLM if it doesn’t protect against cracking?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Because nothing protects against cracking. Because that’s not the point of licensing. You will occasionally get companies claiming to stop cracking (e.g. PELock, and a handful of others), but it’s not actually possible.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="18" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/m/8797f3/40.png" class="avatar"> MarcWells:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>LimeLM looks like a snake oil to me, especially when its founder tries to undermine his more technologically advanced competition.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>OK, we’ll just have to agree to disagree on the “more technologically advanced competition” point.</p>
<p>Regarding me trying to “undermine [our] competition”, I would disagree with that characterization. A company that you recommend is selling a lie (either through ignorance or malice), and I have more than a decade in the software licensing field. So I was trying to bring reality to the discussion. If that company had not claimed an impossible thing (i.e. being uncrackable) I wouldn’t have commented on them one way or another.</p>
<p>I do make a point at shaming companies that lie; specifically licensing companies because that’s where my area of expertise is. Whether that’s a good business decision or not (to even risk looking like that I’m “lashing out” at companies just because they compete with us, even despite that not being true) is another discussion.</p>
<h2>Brief aside: commenting on competition</h2>
<p>I know some business owners take the position that you should never mention your competition, and never publicly talk about them one way or another. And I take that view for our legitimate competition (i.e. the many software licensing companies that do not claim they provide an uncrackable solution: i.e. our competition that does not lie to customers).</p>
<p>But since I started my business more than a decade ago now, I have always called out the lies of our competition whether they were a bigger company or a smaller company. My ultimate goal is to bring reality to the software licensing market.</p>
<p>I know some of our customer like it, some of our customers are indifferent, and some of our customer are decidedly turned off by me doing this.</p>
<h2>Back to the topic at hand…</h2>
<aside class="quote" data-post="18" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/m/8797f3/40.png" class="avatar"> MarcWells:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>On the other hand, PELock protects application against modifications</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<aside class="quote" data-post="18" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/m/8797f3/40.png" class="avatar"> MarcWells:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>and I don’t see any claims on their website it’s uncrackable…</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Well, this is the headline on their homepage:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Software copy protection against reverse engineering with anti-cracking &amp; anti-debugging techniques.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>I, and I think any reasonable person, would take that to mean they stop reverse engineering (i.e. cracking). But I guess you do have to click their “PELock” product to get the “money quote”:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>PELock is a software security solution <strong>designed for protection of any 32 bit Windows applications against cracking</strong>, tampering and reverse engineering analysis.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>They can’t both claim that they can “protect against cracking” and that they’re not claiming they’re uncrackable. Those two ideas are inherently at odds with each other. You’re either “uncrackable” or you’re not. “Protection […] against cracking” is useless if it can be cracked (<strong>and it <em>can</em> be</strong>): it’s an inherently binary thing.</p>
<p>Long story short: cracking is both a reality (for any product, including PELock) and for popular products cracking is inevitable.</p>
<p>I get that you’re a fan of PELock, and I’m sorry if anything I said insulted you, that wasn’t my intention. My goal was to inform you of the reality of software, cracking, and licensing in general. And, I guess, my only hope is if you take this away from the discussion:</p>
<ol>
<li>Nothing can stop cracking.</li>
<li>Legitimate software licensing companies do not infer or “wink” in any way to customers that their product can stop cracking.</li>
<li>The point of software licensing isn’t to stop cracking.</li>
</ol>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/20</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 19:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-20</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[MarcWells]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Why do you even use it, when you say LimeLM can be cracked :), where’s the logic in that <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/fearful.png?v=5" title=":fearful:" class="emoji" alt=":fearful:"> ? You choose it just because it has nice interface?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/19</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 18:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-19</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[MarcWells]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>You are right, there were cracked PELock copies, <strong>from 10 years ago</strong> <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/joy.png?v=5" title=":joy:" class="emoji" alt=":joy:"> and I don’t see any claims on their website it’s uncrackable…</p>
<p>I’ve heard about LimeLM, my friend in Sweden tried LimeLM and his software was cracked in the next day his software was released (audio processing, very popular). Not a very good memory.</p>
<p><strong>LimeLM looks like a snake oil to me, especially when its founder tries to undermine his more technologically advanced competition.</strong></p>
<p>Licensing != Protection</p>
<p>If you don’t know the difference between those two technolgies I guess you’re already in big troubles.</p>
<p>Basically cracking LimeLM is as simple as patching any other licensing code.</p>
<p>On the other hand, PELock protects application against modifications, provides selected code encryption (LimeLM can’t do that) and has extended licensing API all working together. We’ve been using those features <strong>for years</strong> and it’s proven to be working fine against cracking, we have thousands of users and millions of downloads.</p>
<p>Hell, even people on this forums claims LimeLM won’t protect you against cracks.</p>
<p><em>“LimeLM (and other similar solutions) can ONLY protect you from “people using a VALID license on more machines than intended by you”. It does not protect you from cracks.”</em></p>
<p>Why would anyone use LimeLM if it doesn’t protect against cracking?</p>
<p>Get your facts straight, read about application file protection (exe protection) and licensing. Real world application needs both of those, not just some licensing library that get cracked in no time like LimeLM.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/18</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 17:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-18</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[wyattoday]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Well, that’s a naïve article. If it was written by someone in the software licensing industry I’d call it outright bad, but looking at the guy’s “About me” it looks as though he doesn’t have experience in this field, so it’s understandable he gets just about everything wrong.</p>
<p>There are a lot of problems there (with every platform). I’ll just focus on Windows.</p>
<ul>
<li>getMachineName() and getVolumeHash() are worse than useless: <a href="https://wyday.com/limelm/features/why/#wrong-id" rel="nofollow noopener">https://wyday.com/limelm/features/why/#wrong-id</a>
</li>
<li>getCpuHash() will not return a unique value.</li>
<li>You’re left with a single “unique” identifier (the MAC address of 2 adapters) but even that code is disastrously incorrect.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My advice if you’re building this yourself:</strong> Get yourself access to about 100 or so real computers, make sure they all have different hardware configurations (laptops, desktops, devices of all shapes and sizes), make sure they’re in different parts of the world, and then test your algorithm. That will be a good start (but if I’m being honest, it’s just the start).</p>
<p><strong>My secondary advice</strong>: you’re not going to find a good fingerprinting algorithm by a google search. It’s simply a case of you don’t know what you don’t know. If you haven’t been developing software licensing for a decade then you don’t know what works and what doesn’t. I immediately recognized that article as simplistic and wrong, but if you don’t have that experience then it looks like you hit the mother lode.</p>
<p><strong>Last piece of advice</strong>: keep at it, don’t be discouraged, but also be realistic. If your goal is to learn more about computers and to learn more about developing resilient algorithms, then I’d recommend you give developing your own licensing a shot. If your goal is to make your product and sell it to more than a handful of people, then you’re making a pretty big mistake developing your licensing yourself. But it’s a catch 22: you won’t realize you’re making a mistake until you have enough experience (or enough customers) for it to become obvious.</p>
<p>I’ll just end by saying some of our most loyal customers are those who made licensing themselves, realized what a hard (and ongoing!) problem it is to solve, and were able to recognize our licensing for being very high-quality. Without that real-world insight about what it takes to make good licensing it’s hard (sometimes impossible) to tell garbage licensing products from good ones.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/17</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 16:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-17</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Victory]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>In case anybody wants to try implementing their own, the following reference may help in getting started.</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://oroboro.com/unique-machine-fingerprint/" target="_blank" title="11:29AM - 31 May 2013" rel="nofollow noopener">Programmer's Notebook – 31 May 13</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://oroboro.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/machine.png" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="500" height="500">

<h3><a href="https://oroboro.com/unique-machine-fingerprint/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Generating a Cross-Platform Unique Machine Fingerprint</a></h3>

<p>Sometimes you need a program to know if it is running on the same machine. There are a lot of purposes for this, but a common one is if you are writing a l</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/16</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 15:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-16</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[rfctr]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="14" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/rhino/40/1254_1.png" class="avatar"> Rhino:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>this is a great example of why its hard to sell to developers</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>True.</p>
<p>Having said that, many of the complexities argued above are around the “call home” functionality, which to me seem not necessary (nice to have but not necessary). And if you remove the call home (along with firewall bypass, proxies, servers to receive those requests, DB to store them and an UI to review them) the basic license implementation is pretty simple – decrypt the license file with a public key and off you go.</p>
<p>So yes, 2 days of work.</p>
<p>P.S. It may not work for all applications, but for mine – which requires an unique server IP – it works fine. The IP is in license key, and the application only binds to the provided IP. Of course there is still a way to work around that for a dedicated sysadmin, but why bother?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/15</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 14:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-15</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhino]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Strongly worded but all this is a great example of why its hard to sell to developers. “Pah! I can do better than that, couple of days max!”</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/14</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 07:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-14</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[cadbloke]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m using LimeLM too and it’s working fine. The support is good. If you want a non-saas solution then <a href="http://www.infralution.com/products/licensing_system.html" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.infralution.com/products/licensing_system.html</a> is a good option, also with <a href="http://www.infralution.com/phpBB2/viewforum.php?f=6" rel="nofollow noopener">good support forums</a>. You will need to build and host your own activation server if you want one where LimeLM provide one as a service.</p>
<p>I looked into this extensively and these seemed are the two best options I found. <a href="http://www.ssware.com/cryptolicensing/cryptolicensing_net.htm" rel="nofollow noopener">CryptoLicensing</a> is another option but I prefer Infralution.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/13</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 03:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-13</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[rfctr]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>What’s your product, Jan?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/12</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 01:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-12</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[unicorm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi guys,</p>
<p>don’t get me wrong - but badly copying the principle from Wyatts page and then seriously suggesting that 800 USD equals 2 weeks of salary and would be enough to implement even a rudimentary solution is just beyond my comprehension. Either you have no valuable product or you have no idea what you are talking about. Why don’t you make it even simpler by allowing any valid key that is matching some checksum.<br>
I mean, you cannot be serious and mean what you are talking about… Testing happens like how many days? Zero? Customer does it for you?</p>
<p>Just for starters, the following things could happen: firewalls blocking activations, hackers hammering your verification servers, customers being unable to verify the license because they are offline for a few days, customers changing a couple of components, customers wanting to try out your software and maybe get an extension, customers installing the software on 32, 64 bit Windows, Mac, Linux, customers running VMs, customers changing to Win 10 with Hyper VM enabled, etc. Even if you get a hold of all those items and implement it just like Wyatt explains it on his homepage - good luck running your activation and verification server 24/7, good luck not having some script sh*** itself, good luck not having people bomb your servers or whatever random thing could possibly happen. Sure, you only have 5 sales a month those things don’t bother you. But then just do a checksum - or even simply accept anything a customer enters. That is still better than a badly implemented software protection mechanism. And you forgot to include the cost in support for dealing with your “homebuilt” licensing system.</p>
<p>With all due respect, but license management (including trials) based on server-verification with fuzzy hardware matching that does not annoy consumers and works reliably is probably one of the most complex endeavours in software development. Even if you believe that you outsmart everybody on the planet by thinking about this problem for 2 weeks max - at least give the credit to the people who thought about those things in detail and made them publicly available when explaining “how you came up with everything”.</p>
<p>But ok, everyone has different standards. However, I cannot possibly understand how these responses have any valuable information a reasonable developer can take serious. You want to know how to do it? Here is a nice technical explanation of the process. It’s more detailed that what you offer and its more reflected also pointing out a number of possible issues…<br>
<a href="https://wyday.com/limelm/features/why/" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://wyday.com/limelm/features/why/</a></p>
<p>I am a paying customer. For the 10 sales per month products, for which the suggestions above are obviously intended, the single plan is probably good enough and just costs 11 USD/month. Implementation can be done in a couple of days and I’d say supporting issues related to the software protection maybe happens 1 / 1000 installs. Probably less. Resetting activation slots, customers entering invalid keys etc. excluded.</p>
<p>Best,<br>
Jan</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/11</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 20:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-11</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Victory]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/rfctr">@rfctr</a>: Yes, if it was a reasonable, fixed, one-time cost, paying the amount in exchange for 2 weeks time can be a good trade-off. What bothered me when I looked into it about 2 years ago was that some of the good solutions had very high fixed cost (More than 2 weeks typical salary of an engineer) or wanted a cut as percentage of sales. Hopefully, the situation has improved now and there are more attractive alternatives.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/10</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 15:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-10</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[rfctr]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="8" data-topic="1745">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/v/53a042/40.png" class="avatar"> Victory:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Save $$</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>2 weeks time work is not “save $$” in my books. Even at a minimal wage it is some $800.</p>
<p>Having said that, I did implemented my own – but a much simpler one.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745/9</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 02:07:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1745-9</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/looking-for-replacement-for-software-passport-armadillo/1745.rss">Looking for replacement for Software Passport / Armadillo</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
