<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>I&#39;ll build and give a SaaS MVP to get my 1st paying customer at StaticBackend</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/ill-build-and-give-a-saas-mvp-to-get-my-1st-paying-customer-at-staticbackend/6725</link>
    <description>Hi all,

Currently doing the non scalable things to get first paying customers. I decided to build and give a functional SaaS MVP using my backend as a service product [StaticBackend](https://staticbackend.com).

It&#39;s a great opportunity for non technical founder to get their idea in front of real users testing their hypothesis.

I&#39;m doing this to demonstrate how uisng my product helps launch a SaaS product faster.

I&#39;ve [tweeted this](https://twitter.com/dominicstpierre/status/1216673403450601472) to get idea suggestions. Feel free to jump in and give your suggestion.

The most liked suggestion and the one I feel confident of building in a short amount of time will be selected. The winner of the SaaS will be selected randomly from another tweet&#39;s retweets.

I&#39;m doing this to get initial traction and eye balls on my  product as well as helphing a non technical founder to get their business up and running for non development investment.

Any comments / thoughts highly appreciated, I&#39;m really to go very far to have this product succeed, passion project I finally found after so many years building products.

Thanks,
Dominic</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 10:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/ill-build-and-give-a-saas-mvp-to-get-my-1st-paying-customer-at-staticbackend/6725.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>I&#39;ll build and give a SaaS MVP to get my 1st paying customer at StaticBackend</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[dominicstpierre]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Yes, the database export was part of the deal.</p>
<p>That being said, after talking for the last days with devs and non-tech people I think I might need to pivot the product a little.</p>
<p>Maybe the database as a service and user management, in fact the vs. Firebase is just very hard way to enter the market.</p>
<p>I’ll need to think more about this and sadly probably have to removed the components I had for now at least.</p>
<p>I might have gone too horizontal. I just need to think more about the product offering.</p>
<p>Thanks for your feedback.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/ill-build-and-give-a-saas-mvp-to-get-my-1st-paying-customer-at-staticbackend/6725/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/ill-build-and-give-a-saas-mvp-to-get-my-1st-paying-customer-at-staticbackend/6725/4</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 10:20:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6725-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/ill-build-and-give-a-saas-mvp-to-get-my-1st-paying-customer-at-staticbackend/6725.rss">I&#39;ll build and give a SaaS MVP to get my 1st paying customer at StaticBackend</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I&#39;ll build and give a SaaS MVP to get my 1st paying customer at StaticBackend</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[aeden]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>So as I’ve understood it, “no vendor lock in” means use HTTP not a library client.</p>
<p>FWIW, I see “no vendor lock in” as: you will give me a full database dump of all of my data whenever I ask for it.</p>
<p>Regarding the marketing idea itself, it’s interesting. I agree though that you should be selective and look for someone who has the potential to actually succeed (if possible), rather than selecting randomly.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/ill-build-and-give-a-saas-mvp-to-get-my-1st-paying-customer-at-staticbackend/6725/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/ill-build-and-give-a-saas-mvp-to-get-my-1st-paying-customer-at-staticbackend/6725/3</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6725-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/ill-build-and-give-a-saas-mvp-to-get-my-1st-paying-customer-at-staticbackend/6725.rss">I&#39;ll build and give a SaaS MVP to get my 1st paying customer at StaticBackend</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I&#39;ll build and give a SaaS MVP to get my 1st paying customer at StaticBackend</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhino]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Interesting marketing idea - could really tap into the zeitgeist around this forum, Indie Hackers etc.</p>
<p>As I understand it you’re going to pick the idea yourself but pick the winner randomly. For best results you want the winner to both succeed and be vocal - so not sure random would be optimal?</p>
<p>From a quick browse of StaticBackend I couldn’t work out the key part of your message : if I replace ‘vendor specific code’ with your API then haven’t I just replaced one lock in with another?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/ill-build-and-give-a-saas-mvp-to-get-my-1st-paying-customer-at-staticbackend/6725/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/ill-build-and-give-a-saas-mvp-to-get-my-1st-paying-customer-at-staticbackend/6725/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 21:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6725-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/ill-build-and-give-a-saas-mvp-to-get-my-1st-paying-customer-at-staticbackend/6725.rss">I&#39;ll build and give a SaaS MVP to get my 1st paying customer at StaticBackend</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I&#39;ll build and give a SaaS MVP to get my 1st paying customer at StaticBackend</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[dominicstpierre]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi all,</p>
<p>Currently doing the non scalable things to get first paying customers. I decided to build and give a functional SaaS MVP using my backend as a service product <a href="https://staticbackend.com">StaticBackend</a>.</p>
<p>It’s a great opportunity for non technical founder to get their idea in front of real users testing their hypothesis.</p>
<p>I’m doing this to demonstrate how uisng my product helps launch a SaaS product faster.</p>
<p>I’ve <a href="https://twitter.com/dominicstpierre/status/1216673403450601472">tweeted this</a> to get idea suggestions. Feel free to jump in and give your suggestion.</p>
<p>The most liked suggestion and the one I feel confident of building in a short amount of time will be selected. The winner of the SaaS will be selected randomly from another tweet’s retweets.</p>
<p>I’m doing this to get initial traction and eye balls on my  product as well as helphing a non technical founder to get their business up and running for non development investment.</p>
<p>Any comments / thoughts highly appreciated, I’m really to go very far to have this product succeed, passion project I finally found after so many years building products.</p>
<p>Thanks,<br>
Dominic</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/ill-build-and-give-a-saas-mvp-to-get-my-1st-paying-customer-at-staticbackend/6725/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/ill-build-and-give-a-saas-mvp-to-get-my-1st-paying-customer-at-staticbackend/6725/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 12:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6725-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/ill-build-and-give-a-saas-mvp-to-get-my-1st-paying-customer-at-staticbackend/6725.rss">I&#39;ll build and give a SaaS MVP to get my 1st paying customer at StaticBackend</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
