<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900</link>
    <description>Hello All, 

I have been running a fairly successful web design agency for the past four years, a model which works well but often results in inconsistent cashflow. We have dreams of launching web applications and moving part of our income stream towards SaaS products.

**Wondered if anyone has any advice on how to promote SaaS services and where is a good place to start?** 

We have unsuccessful launched a couple of applications in the past and therefore have learnt some big lessons the hard way but keen to hear your thoughts! 

</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 10:31:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Crewlab]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/mrchrisdesouza">@mrchrisdesouza</a> - my pleasure, glad it was helpful.</p>
<p><strong>Don’t Outsource Cold-Calling</strong><br>
Especially in the beginning.</p>
<p>To outsource any job effectively, you need to have clear and well documented instructions. And in order to do that effectively, you need to have done the job yourself.</p>
<p>Not to mention all there is to be <em>learned</em> by doing the cold calls yourself. That’s the majority of the benefit!</p>
<p>Ask anyone who’s a few years in on their own product: your messaging - how you explain and sell your product - will change over time.</p>
<p>For <a href="http://www.simplecrew.com" rel="nofollow noopener">SimpleCrew</a>, our product is pretty much exactly what we had in mind we started with just the idea 2.5 years ago.</p>
<p>But the messaging has changed immensely.</p>
<p>We went from describing SimpleCrew with long winded paragraphs as a “mobile field team management application” (wtf?) to the much, much clearer “mobile app for street teams” today.</p>
<p>(I seriously cringe when I go over old executive summaries and product decks…)</p>
<p>However simple that seems in retrospect, that messaging evolved with time, as a result of literally hundreds of conversations with potential customers, investors, friends, etc…</p>
<p>And yes, as you mentioned - no outsource agent is going to have your interests at heart like you will. In the beginning, <em>you</em> need to be on your own frontlines.</p>
<p>Cold-calling honestly isn’t that hard. Once you get started, it’s easy. This is a <em>must do</em> for founders.</p>
<p><strong>On content marketing</strong><br>
I don’t have any particular book recommendations. I’m sure one of the 37Signals books (Getting Real or Rework) covers the topic from their perspective which is a golden one to follow.</p>
<p>This post of theirs also sums up the whole idea nicely: <a href="https://signalvnoise.com/posts/1620-sell-your-by-products" rel="nofollow noopener">Sell Your By-products</a></p>
<p>Hope this helps. Please keep the questions coming if you have them. These topics will inspire future posts on my blog - <a href="http://www.crewlab.net" rel="nofollow noopener">Crewlab.net</a>.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900/7</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 10:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1900-7</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900.rss">Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[mrchrisdesouza]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thank you for your insight, really well balanced thoughts and advice here!</p>
<p>Your advice of building for under-served markets is a good one. I think my own (unfounded) hesitation with this is understanding new marketing places and finding key contacts within them.</p>
<p>Does anyone have experience with out-sourcing cold-calling? I’v heard this is a really bad idea as they do not represent you very well and people often want to speak with the business owner?</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/crewlab">@Crewlab</a> do you have any book recommendations for Content Marketing ?</p>
<p>Thanks!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900/6</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 09:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1900-6</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900.rss">Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Crewlab]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Chris - there’s a lot of great precedent for this exact move, not the least of which is perhaps the OGs themselves 37Signals - also Amy Hoy, Metalab, and many, many more.</p>
<p>Amy wrote about this masterfully/hilariously in a <a href="http://unicornfree.com/2013/37signals-isnt-mythical-youre-not-paying-attention" rel="nofollow noopener">response</a> to a post some agency made about their own <a href="https://medium.com/@freshtilledsoil/the-myth-of-the-design-studio-turned-product-company-fceb670aa74a" rel="nofollow noopener">failure</a> to successfully transition to products.</p>
<p>Amy’s post is great and there’s a lot you can learn from her points in there. There’s also a lot you can learn from the cringe-worthy fail-post she’s responding to in terms of the wrong mindset and approach to have.</p>
<p>Some added thoughts:</p>
<p><strong>Be patient.</strong><br>
The Long, Slow, SaaS Ramp of Death is a real thing. My friends and I have coined the “1000 day rule”, basically, don’t be surprised if your product doesn’t go $25k/mo recurring in month 1. Shit takes time. 3 years for a SaaS to start covering your (SMALL team’s) market salaries seems to be a common theme</p>
<p><strong>Dogfood with caution</strong><br>
"Build a product you want to use" is fantastic advice. But there’s a catch. If you’re coming from the world of software consulting, it turns out that that’s a tricky market to develop for - it’s extremely well served.</p>
<p>There’s an ocean of project management, bug tracking, time tracking, client-support, etc… products available for the agencies of the world. Don’t be afraid to swim into blue ocean to build apps for more under-served markets filled with non-developers who are hungry for delicious SaaS products.</p>
<p>That’s exactly what we did (we make a mobile photo app for street marketing teams. Link in the profile.)</p>
<p><strong>Pick up the phone.</strong><br>
Sell on the phone. Make cold calls.</p>
<p>It’s ridiculous how few bootstrapped B2B software folks do this. It’s <em>effective</em>, and will teach you more about your customers, their pain points, and how to sell your product than any amount of copywriting and a/b testing will, especially in the beginning.</p>
<p><strong>Share your story</strong><br>
Document your journey and share it with the world in a blog or podcast. It’s a great platform to have, and will help others find and relate to you.</p>
<p>Content marketing can be like cheat codes for bootstrappers. Get it in.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900/5</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 15:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1900-5</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900.rss">Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[mrchrisdesouza]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks both, appreciate the advice. We have an idea already lined up to help with the sign off process which we will start to use internally before making public.</p>
<p>when we’re ready I wondered what else we should be doing to expand the client base of a product beyond our circle of influence? Not afraid of hard work just wondered in which areas have people experienced success before? (SEO, B2B Cold Calls, PR in tech blogs ect…)</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900/4</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 10:15:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1900-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900.rss">Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Virgil]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>You have a huge advantage here. I know at least 3 people that started as an agency than shifted into saas. Like Andy said above, try to solve a problem your clients have. You can give a call or meet with a few of them and ask them about their pains. For sure you’ll find some ideas + you already have a relationship with them.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 09:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1900-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900.rss">Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[andycroll]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Where I’ve seen this happen best (as a freelancer contracting to agencies) is by selling a product that would help your existing clients. Whether that is productised consulting (run 5 AB tests a month and produce a report) or (duh) support contracts or a targeted web application you can sell as part of your design &amp; build services.</p>
<p>That’s how Basecamp started after all. Blog to white papers to software to outside their niche.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 09:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1900-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900.rss">Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[mrchrisdesouza]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello All,</p>
<p>I have been running a fairly successful web design agency for the past four years, a model which works well but often results in inconsistent cashflow. We have dreams of launching web applications and moving part of our income stream towards SaaS products.</p>
<p><strong>Wondered if anyone has any advice on how to promote SaaS services and where is a good place to start?</strong></p>
<p>We have unsuccessful launched a couple of applications in the past and therefore have learnt some big lessons the hard way but keen to hear your thoughts!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 09:35:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1900-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/advice-on-moving-from-a-client-focused-agency-to-saas-business-model/1900.rss">Advice on moving from a client focused agency to SaaS business model</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
