<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bootstrapping-related podcasts (updated for 2019)</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapping-related-podcasts-updated-for-2019/6269</link>
    <description>Here&#39;s our list of podcasts different folks recommend, refreshed for 2019:

[Bootstrapped](http://bootstrapped.fm) - Naturally, the list starts with our own podcast. If you are bootstrapping a software business, or thinking about doing so, this is the podcast for you.

[Startups for the Rest of Us](https://www.startupsfortherestofus.com/) - From the people who run MicroConf. Consistently high quality. They somehow get an episode out every week, without fail.

[Rogue Startups](https://roguestartups.com/) - Listen in on two guys having their weekly call discussing their bootstrapped startup challenges and successes.

[Hurry Slowly](https://hurryslowly.co/) - A podcast about how you can be more productive, creative, and resilient through the simple act of slowing down.

[Tropical MBA](http://www.tropicalmba.com/podcasts/) - Great stuff if you&#39;re interested in location independence/digital nomadism. 

[Build Your SaaS](https://saas.transistor.fm/) - Follow along as they get a SaaS off the ground.

[Bootstrapped Web](http://bootstrappedweb.com/) - Brian and Jordan share the lessons they &quot;learn by doing, and learn from the things that others are doing, to help us all get ahead as we bootstrap our businesses online.&quot;

[Mixergy](https://mixergy.com/) - Consensus seems to be that this is hit or miss for bootstrappers, but great interviewing

[The Gently Mad](https://thegentlymad.com/) - A podcast about meaning, disguised as a podcast about entrepreneurship. It’s a bright-eyed and sweary look at what it takes to make a living on the internet (and still sleep at night).

[Fizzle](https://fizzle.co/show) - A podcast for creative entrepreneurs and honest business builders who want to earn a living doing something they care about.

[Smart Passive Income](https://www.smartpassiveincome.com/category/podcast/) - Weekly interviews, strategy, and advice for building your online business. Don&#39;t be put off by the name - this podcast isn&#39;t really about passive income.

What&#39;s missing that you&#39;d recommend?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 01:39:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Interesting Links</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapping-related-podcasts-updated-for-2019/6269.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Bootstrapping-related podcasts (updated for 2019)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapping-related-podcasts-updated-for-2019/6269/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapping-related-podcasts-updated-for-2019/6269/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 09:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6269-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapping-related-podcasts-updated-for-2019/6269.rss">Bootstrapping-related podcasts (updated for 2019)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Bootstrapping-related podcasts (updated for 2019)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[nevf]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>My regulars include:</p>
<p><a href="https://thisweekinstartups.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">This Week in Startups</a> - Jason Calacanis and a rotating group of guest experts bring you this weekly take on the best, worst, most outrageous and interesting stories from the world of entrepreneurship. <em>You either like him or don’t <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=6" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></em></p>
<p><a href="https://www.recode.net/recode-decode-podcast-kara-swisher" rel="nofollow noopener">Recode Decode</a> - One of tech’s most prominent journalists, Kara Swisher is known for her insightful reporting and straight-shooting style. <em>Well informed, well known with an impressive line up of guests.</em></p>
<p><a href="https://www.recode.net/recode-media-podcast" rel="nofollow noopener">Recode Media</a> with Peter Kafka. <em>Same comment as above</em>  Also see <a href="https://www.recode.net/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.recode.net/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.recode.net/pivot-with-kara-swisher-and-scott-galloway" rel="nofollow noopener">Recode Media - Pivot</a> with Kara Swisher and Scott Galloway. <em>Lively banter about Tech etc.</em></p>
<p><a href="https://hacktheentrepreneur.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">Hack the Entrepreneur</a> - Learn how to start an online business, find a side hustle idea, and skyrocket your success with Hack the Entrepreneur. <em>Down to earth interviews with entrepreneur’s</em></p>
<p><a href="https://getting2alpha.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">Getting2Alpha</a> Podcast: Learn how to innovate better, faster &amp; smarter. <em>A focus on gaming, with some useful content</em></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapping-related-podcasts-updated-for-2019/6269/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapping-related-podcasts-updated-for-2019/6269/3</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 01:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6269-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapping-related-podcasts-updated-for-2019/6269.rss">Bootstrapping-related podcasts (updated for 2019)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Bootstrapping-related podcasts (updated for 2019)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapping-related-podcasts-updated-for-2019/6269/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapping-related-podcasts-updated-for-2019/6269/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 08:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6269-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapping-related-podcasts-updated-for-2019/6269.rss">Bootstrapping-related podcasts (updated for 2019)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Bootstrapping-related podcasts (updated for 2019)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Here’s our list of podcasts different folks recommend, refreshed for 2019:</p>
<p><a href="http://bootstrapped.fm">Bootstrapped</a> - Naturally, the list starts with our own podcast. If you are bootstrapping a software business, or thinking about doing so, this is the podcast for you.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.startupsfortherestofus.com/">Startups for the Rest of Us</a> - From the people who run MicroConf. Consistently high quality. They somehow get an episode out every week, without fail.</p>
<p><a href="https://roguestartups.com/">Rogue Startups</a> - Listen in on two guys having their weekly call discussing their bootstrapped startup challenges and successes.</p>
<p><a href="https://hurryslowly.co/">Hurry Slowly</a> - A podcast about how you can be more productive, creative, and resilient through the simple act of slowing down.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.tropicalmba.com/podcasts/">Tropical MBA</a> - Great stuff if you’re interested in location independence/digital nomadism.</p>
<p><a href="https://saas.transistor.fm/">Build Your SaaS</a> - Follow along as they get a SaaS off the ground.</p>
<p><a href="http://bootstrappedweb.com/">Bootstrapped Web</a> - Brian and Jordan share the lessons they “learn by doing, and learn from the things that others are doing, to help us all get ahead as we bootstrap our businesses online.”</p>
<p><a href="https://mixergy.com/">Mixergy</a> - Consensus seems to be that this is hit or miss for bootstrappers, but great interviewing</p>
<p><a href="https://thegentlymad.com/">The Gently Mad</a> - A podcast about meaning, disguised as a podcast about entrepreneurship. It’s a bright-eyed and sweary look at what it takes to make a living on the internet (and still sleep at night).</p>
<p><a href="https://fizzle.co/show">Fizzle</a> - A podcast for creative entrepreneurs and honest business builders who want to earn a living doing something they care about.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.smartpassiveincome.com/category/podcast/">Smart Passive Income</a> - Weekly interviews, strategy, and advice for building your online business. Don’t be put off by the name - this podcast isn’t really about passive income.</p>
<p>What’s missing that you’d recommend?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapping-related-podcasts-updated-for-2019/6269/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapping-related-podcasts-updated-for-2019/6269/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 08:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6269-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapping-related-podcasts-updated-for-2019/6269.rss">Bootstrapping-related podcasts (updated for 2019)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
