<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Where do Rails operators hang out?</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/where-do-rails-operators-hang-out/2513</link>
    <description>Hey, guys!

Last year I started bootstrapping my own product business and the year went quite well - I released a free ebook for members of my mailing list and started working on my first paid book a few weeks ago.

I am quite excited about the book and I think it will be a great read for a lot of Rails developers who want to manage their own Rails server (if you are interested, here is the book&#39;s landing page: http://www.relativkreativ.at/products/rails_operations_for_bootstrappers - though it&#39;s a little outdated and will be reworked soon because I published it before I started working on the book).

However, my number one goal for this year is growing my mailing list. Even though my list gains new subscribers slowly but regularly, I have always found it hard to track down my core audience online.

A lot of questions related to Rails operations can be found on stackoverflow.com, serverfault.com and in DigitalOcean&#39;s community but I am wondering if anyone knows other places where people hang out sharing their knowledge and asking questions about Rails operations (provisioning servers, deploying applications and generally running in production). Any clues?

Thanks a lot and all the best for the new year!

Michael</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 12:26:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/where-do-rails-operators-hang-out/2513.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Where do Rails operators hang out?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[relativkreativ]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey, guys (sorry <a class="mention" href="/u/steve">@steve</a>, I missed the notification of your reply)!</p>
<p>Thanks a lot for your input. Obviously there is some confusion about the book’s title.</p>
<p>I have not been happy with it too - I just needed a title to build a landing page. The book’s working title is now “Efficient Rails DevOps” which sums it up quite nicely I think.</p>
<p>About two thirds of the book are feature-complete and I will register the domain and start building the real landing page soon.</p>
<p>Thanks for your suggestions regarding the places where Rails operators hang out. The larger part of my mailing list comes from posts on Reddit, HackerNews and <a href="http://bootstrappers.io" rel="nofollow noopener">bootstrappers.io</a>. I just wanted to make sure that I’m not missing something obvious.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/where-do-rails-operators-hang-out/2513/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/where-do-rails-operators-hang-out/2513/4</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 12:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2513-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/where-do-rails-operators-hang-out/2513.rss">Where do Rails operators hang out?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Where do Rails operators hang out?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[DeLongShot]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I would take a step back and think about your core audience.</p>
<p>I was a little confused about this at first because you say…</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I think it will be a great read for a lot of Rails developers who want to manage their own Rails server</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But then the book is called “Rails Operations for Bootstrappers”.  All Rails developers aren’t necessarily bootstrappers, but they might still find this information very useful. I wouldn’t consider myself a bootstrapper quite yet, but I am a dev consultant and would find this information interesting.  And I know other just plain Rails devs who don’t know much about operations but might like to learn.</p>
<p>So, to answer your question, I think you need to find places where there are Rails devs who are looking to learn operations. <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/ruby" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.reddit.com/r/ruby</a> or <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/programming" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.reddit.com/r/programming</a> might be useful and then of course, Hacker News is also very popular.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/where-do-rails-operators-hang-out/2513/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/where-do-rails-operators-hang-out/2513/3</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 04:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2513-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/where-do-rails-operators-hang-out/2513.rss">Where do Rails operators hang out?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Where do Rails operators hang out?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[steve]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>If you widen your audience a little to “[Dev]Ops for Rails shops” there are plenty of places which might have interested people:</p>
<p><a href="http://Meetup.com" rel="nofollow noopener">Meetup.com</a> groups for Rails/Dev Ops<br>
Small companies that advertise Rails development services or help wanted ads for Rails developers</p>
<p>Perhaps you could guest post on Rails sites/appear on podcasts about Rails talking about some aspect of Ops for Rails.</p>
<p>You might want to invest in an easier to say/remember domain name for us dumb Americans; <a href="http://DevOpsForRailsShops.com" rel="nofollow noopener">DevOpsForRailsShops.com</a> or something.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/where-do-rails-operators-hang-out/2513/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/where-do-rails-operators-hang-out/2513/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 11:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2513-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/where-do-rails-operators-hang-out/2513.rss">Where do Rails operators hang out?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Where do Rails operators hang out?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[relativkreativ]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey, guys!</p>
<p>Last year I started bootstrapping my own product business and the year went quite well - I released a free ebook for members of my mailing list and started working on my first paid book a few weeks ago.</p>
<p>I am quite excited about the book and I think it will be a great read for a lot of Rails developers who want to manage their own Rails server (if you are interested, here is the book’s landing page: <a href="http://www.relativkreativ.at/products/rails_operations_for_bootstrappers" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.relativkreativ.at/products/rails_operations_for_bootstrappers</a> - though it’s a little outdated and will be reworked soon because I published it before I started working on the book).</p>
<p>However, my number one goal for this year is growing my mailing list. Even though my list gains new subscribers slowly but regularly, I have always found it hard to track down my core audience online.</p>
<p>A lot of questions related to Rails operations can be found on <a href="http://stackoverflow.com" rel="nofollow noopener">stackoverflow.com</a>, <a href="http://serverfault.com" rel="nofollow noopener">serverfault.com</a> and in DigitalOcean’s community but I am wondering if anyone knows other places where people hang out sharing their knowledge and asking questions about Rails operations (provisioning servers, deploying applications and generally running in production). Any clues?</p>
<p>Thanks a lot and all the best for the new year!</p>
<p>Michael</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/where-do-rails-operators-hang-out/2513/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/where-do-rails-operators-hang-out/2513/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 12:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2513-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/where-do-rails-operators-hang-out/2513.rss">Where do Rails operators hang out?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
