<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Following on Twitter</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115</link>
    <description>I follow 62 people on Twitter. It is all I can do to skim through their Tweets. I see many people follow hundreds or even thousands of people. What is going on? If you are following hundreds of people do you:

a) spend hours every day reading tweets
b) use software to filter whose tweets you see
c) only read a tiny fraction of the tweets you are subscribed to
d) something else 

C&#39;mon. Fess up!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2014 06:55:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Following on Twitter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[travisfischer]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I have legitimately followed close to 900 people and only have 300 followers. I’m an option C user. I just tune in for little bursts of content.</p>
<p>I am trying to clean up my follow list because there is a lot of silly noise with 900 follows. My general approach for following is if I think someone has a possibility of being remotely interesting or relevant I just follow them and tell myself I’ll unfollow if they don’t turn out to be valuable. Most of the time I don’t unfollow unless they are really annoying or useless.</p>
<p>I’ve found that the majority of accounts tweet pretty sparingly so even though I follow 900 there are probably 200 that I see tweet consistently. As such it doesn’t feel like completely unfocused stream of tweets. Following 900 accounts obviously makes it impossible to keep up with all tweets. I like that aspect of having a huge follow list because it prevents me from feeling like I’m falling behind and must read everything. I also really enjoy having a huge cross section of interesting people because it gives me a pretty neat curated experience during current events. I’ll have 100 unique and diverse people who are all in some way relevant to me commenting on something that’s in the news.</p>
<p>I just recently decided to start trying to use lists for groups of people that I want to do a better job of really tracking. For instance my bootstrappers list is one I’m reading pretty much every tweet from <a href="https://twitter.com/TravisFischer/business-bootstrapping" rel="nofollow noopener">https://twitter.com/TravisFischer/business-bootstrapping</a>. The list is a work in progress in terms of who’s on it. I add accounts as I see them come up in my main stream or discover them elsewhere online.</p>
<p>I try to limit the amount of time I invest in Twitter. On the one hand I have built some real valuable relationships and connections. On the other hand I have wasted hours and hours reading about what 900 people are watching on TV and eating for supper.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/14</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2014 06:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1115-14</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss">Following on Twitter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Following on Twitter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ericbarnes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I seem to just skim as well. I currently follow less than 200 and during the day I can keep up pretty easily by just scanning every few hours. I feel like I should follow more but signal to noise ratio will just get out of hand. If it’s something awesome I figure one of the people I follow will retweet it so I will come across it. The weekends I usually just skip if I’m not on the computer.</p>
<p>My workflow is by using TweetBot with three panes open. One for my followers, and the other two for product mentions.  This works well for quickly seeing if someone has a complaint or something and they haven’t added our @ to it.</p>
<p>I did have all my notifications turned off but now I’m on a self proclaimed mission to have more followers than my boss so it’s an important metric. I may have to just buy followers since I am not that interesting and he keeps gaining more than me. <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smiley.png?v=5" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/13</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2014 01:59:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1115-13</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss">Following on Twitter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Following on Twitter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[andrey]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I have a list set up for “specific people”, which contains &lt; 10 people for whom I’d really like to see every tweet since the last time I checked - with so few people, that list doesn’t contain more than a few dozen tweets at most every day.</p>
<p>With TweetDeck, I have that “specific people” list open all the time, as a regular column, so I don’t miss anything important.</p>
<p>The “everyone” column is too much to pay attention to, so I tend to just look through there when I have some minutes to kill here and there.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/12</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 22:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1115-12</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss">Following on Twitter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Following on Twitter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>heh, maybe so. Though even when I had less I didn’t watch that. Then you’re tempted to follow back which all leads down the wrong path. I want to focus on the people I follow so I don’t miss much, though even at 292 I should go in and trim the dead stuff and such.</p>
<p>SocialBro is a decent free tool to go in and clean up old things, see the really big people following you etc. Some of y’all might want to check it out.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/11</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 20:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1115-11</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss">Following on Twitter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Following on Twitter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Easy to say for you Mr. <a class="mention" href="/u/ian">@ian</a> Landsman, with your 2921 followers! Some of us with not nearly as many get just a wee bit excited when someone new follows.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/10</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 20:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1115-10</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss">Following on Twitter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Following on Twitter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Twitter is much more enjoyable if you turn off all follow/unfollow notifications fyi. I have no email notifications, this makes it much less distracting.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/9</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 19:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1115-9</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss">Following on Twitter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Following on Twitter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>e) are a person/businesses desperate for attention.*</p>
<p>*Although I think a few hundred is fine, especially if you’ve been active on Twitter for a long time. It’s when you’re in the 4-digits that I just don’t believe you actually care one iota what any of these people are saying.</p>
<p>There is no way to “follow” 1000 people, even in the lightest sense of the word. As <a class="mention" href="/u/lewis">@Lewis</a> said it’s a technique used to get your own follower base. But it totally cheapens the experience of being on Twitter. I hate getting followed by some random account only to get unfollowed a week later because I didn’t reciprocate.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/8</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 19:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1115-8</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss">Following on Twitter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Following on Twitter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[steve]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I try to skim.</p>
<p>In iOS, there is the “@” tab in Safari which shows you links from your Twitter feed, which can be helpful.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/7</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 18:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1115-7</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss">Following on Twitter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Following on Twitter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="5" data-topic="1115">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/lewis/40/142_1.png" class="avatar"> Lewis:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I think this approach is stupid. It’s not beneficial to anyone.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Yes. Seems sleazy. Even worse are those people who automatically follow thousands of people (in the hope of getting a follow back) and then quietly unfollow them later.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/6</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 17:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1115-6</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss">Following on Twitter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Following on Twitter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Lewis]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>It was a common tactic to build a twitter following by following. Follow an account, if they follow you back keep them. If they do not follow you back, unfollow them. This reciprocity approach to building a following on twitter has resulted in many accounts having similar followers and following. It’s obvious to me that this tactic was used when I see an account that is following 800 accounts and has just over 800 followers.</p>
<p>I think this approach is stupid. It’s not beneficial to anyone.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/5</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 16:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1115-5</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss">Following on Twitter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Following on Twitter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I follow 294 it looks like, though many are businesses or other things that don’t tweet constantly.</p>
<p>I think I read most of it, though not all. I would say it’s less than an hour most days though perhaps an hour in total if you count time to reply and such.</p>
<p>Hard to say if it’s worthwhile or not. There’s definitely been some considering upsides, but it’s certainly hard to quantify. I tend to view it as marketing and ‘part of my job’ in general which also has some impact on the effort I put into it.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/4</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 16:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1115-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss">Following on Twitter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Following on Twitter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[shantnu]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>It’s always C.</p>
<p>What you can do is, create a list for important people whose Tweets you dont want to miss. Other than that, Twitter is a non-stop show of “look at me look at me look at me.”</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 15:33:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1115-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss">Following on Twitter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Following on Twitter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[adrian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>With me it’s choice C – I accept that I won’t see everything. It’s sort of like the radio, where you’ll only hear things when you tune in.</p>
<p>Incidentally, this is why I think it’s unwise to say Twitter is replacing RSS. If I want to be sure I’m getting everything from a person/company, I’ll subscribe to their RSS feed. Twitter is more for loose/real-time stuff.</p>
<p>Of course, there are many different ways to use it. That’s my own two cents.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 14:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1115-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss">Following on Twitter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Following on Twitter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I follow 62 people on Twitter. It is all I can do to skim through their Tweets. I see many people follow hundreds or even thousands of people. What is going on? If you are following hundreds of people do you:</p>
<p>a) spend hours every day reading tweets<br>
b) use software to filter whose tweets you see<br>
c) only read a tiny fraction of the tweets you are subscribed to<br>
d) something else</p>
<p>C’mon. Fess up!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 14:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1115-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/following-on-twitter/1115.rss">Following on Twitter</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
