<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>What mistakes have you made with your brochure site?</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-mistakes-have-you-made-with-your-brochure-site/1217</link>
    <description>I&#39;ve been asked to teach a class at a local startup incubator (with bootstrappy leanings) on any topic that a) I&#39;m qualified to talk about and b) would make sense for their audience.

Since I recently gave a presentation to a business networking group on &quot;3 Common Website Mistakes,&quot; I suggested a similar talk to the inclubator and they liked it. But it&#39;s of course one thing to take a plumbing company&#39;s shitty website and optimize it for lead generation, and another thing entirely to take a SaaS app with no brochure site and tell them what they should build.

So I&#39;d like to ask you: **what in your opinion are some common SaaS brochure site mistakes?** Perhaps you&#39;ve made a mistake or two of your own.

Mistakes I made include:

 - No list-building mechanism
 - Bad domain name (e.g. sniphq.com instead of snipsalonsoftware.com)
 - Ill-conceived value proposition
 - Inadequate pricing information
 - Lack of screenshots, videos, etc.
 - Asking to &quot;get married on the first date&quot;
 - Unclear CTAs
 - General SEO ignorance
 - Simply not having a website at all for the first year
 - Choosing a limiting CMS (in my case, Rails instead of WP)
 - No contact form

Wow...that&#39;s fuckload of mistakes. Curious to hear yours. I also welcome any suggestions you might have on how I could/should structure this class. It&#39;s a one-time, 2-hour class.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 19:12:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-mistakes-have-you-made-with-your-brochure-site/1217.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>What mistakes have you made with your brochure site?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jasonswett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’ve been asked to teach a class at a local startup incubator (with bootstrappy leanings) on any topic that a) I’m qualified to talk about and b) would make sense for their audience.</p>
<p>Since I recently gave a presentation to a business networking group on “3 Common Website Mistakes,” I suggested a similar talk to the inclubator and they liked it. But it’s of course one thing to take a plumbing company’s shitty website and optimize it for lead generation, and another thing entirely to take a SaaS app with no brochure site and tell them what they should build.</p>
<p>So I’d like to ask you: <strong>what in your opinion are some common SaaS brochure site mistakes?</strong> Perhaps you’ve made a mistake or two of your own.</p>
<p>Mistakes I made include:</p>
<ul>
<li>No list-building mechanism</li>
<li>Bad domain name (e.g. <a href="http://sniphq.com" rel="nofollow noopener">sniphq.com</a> instead of <a href="http://snipsalonsoftware.com" rel="nofollow noopener">snipsalonsoftware.com</a>)</li>
<li>Ill-conceived value proposition</li>
<li>Inadequate pricing information</li>
<li>Lack of screenshots, videos, etc.</li>
<li>Asking to “get married on the first date”</li>
<li>Unclear CTAs</li>
<li>General SEO ignorance</li>
<li>Simply not having a website at all for the first year</li>
<li>Choosing a limiting CMS (in my case, Rails instead of WP)</li>
<li>No contact form</li>
</ul>
<p>Wow…that’s fuckload of mistakes. Curious to hear yours. I also welcome any suggestions you might have on how I could/should structure this class. It’s a one-time, 2-hour class.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-mistakes-have-you-made-with-your-brochure-site/1217/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-mistakes-have-you-made-with-your-brochure-site/1217/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 19:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1217-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/what-mistakes-have-you-made-with-your-brochure-site/1217.rss">What mistakes have you made with your brochure site?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
