<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Recommendations for an invoicing app with ACH integration?</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/recommendations-for-an-invoicing-app-with-ach-integration/2723</link>
    <description>Hey Bootstrappers,

I was wondering if anyone had a rec for an an invoicing app that can essentially know if an invoice it has issued has been paid by the client.

I&#39;m running a SaaS business where some clients insist on being invoiced monthly. Doing the accounting to make sure everyone paid and on time, etc, becomes increasingly annoying as I get more of these guys.

Is there an app that can hook into my bank account and see when I&#39;ve received ACH payments (or even check deposits)? I think I may have seen one invoicing app that had an in-house ACH solution where they took a percent cut of the ACH amount, which I found totally unreasonable. There has to be something better!

Cheers,
Vincent</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 13:01:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/recommendations-for-an-invoicing-app-with-ach-integration/2723.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations for an invoicing app with ACH integration?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[cpursley]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Vincent,</p>
<p>Not quite what you are looking for regarding ACH, but <a href="http://invoiced.com" rel="nofollow noopener">invoiced.com</a> is really nice. You can accept PayPal or stripe at the moment. I personally use popmoney to send money to other’s account which is provided by my bank. Works just like PaPal but in my case is only $1 per transaction.</p>
<p>Also, consider charging your SaaS clients an extra invoice fee for your preparation time. This way you will find out if they really want a traditional invoice. If they balk at the fee, they can pay the standard way.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/recommendations-for-an-invoicing-app-with-ach-integration/2723/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/recommendations-for-an-invoicing-app-with-ach-integration/2723/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 13:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2723-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/recommendations-for-an-invoicing-app-with-ach-integration/2723.rss">Recommendations for an invoicing app with ACH integration?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations for an invoicing app with ACH integration?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[vwoo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey Bootstrappers,</p>
<p>I was wondering if anyone had a rec for an an invoicing app that can essentially know if an invoice it has issued has been paid by the client.</p>
<p>I’m running a SaaS business where some clients insist on being invoiced monthly. Doing the accounting to make sure everyone paid and on time, etc, becomes increasingly annoying as I get more of these guys.</p>
<p>Is there an app that can hook into my bank account and see when I’ve received ACH payments (or even check deposits)? I think I may have seen one invoicing app that had an in-house ACH solution where they took a percent cut of the ACH amount, which I found totally unreasonable. There has to be something better!</p>
<p>Cheers,<br>
Vincent</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/recommendations-for-an-invoicing-app-with-ach-integration/2723/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/recommendations-for-an-invoicing-app-with-ach-integration/2723/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 13:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2723-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/recommendations-for-an-invoicing-app-with-ach-integration/2723.rss">Recommendations for an invoicing app with ACH integration?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
