<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Pricing for schools?</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/pricing-for-schools/4203</link>
    <description>So here&#39;s a question.

Recently I&#39;ve gotten a lot of great advice on pricing for individuals and for teams. But one area where I&#39;m still at sea, pricing-wise, is in what to offer to schools (e.g. coding bootcamps) that want to use my material as part of their curriculum.

Any thoughts on how to approach this question? I&#39;m looking for both pricing advice as well as advice on the &quot;package&quot; I should be offering to for-profit educational institutions.

Thanks!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 12:31:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/pricing-for-schools/4203.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Pricing for schools?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[buggy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>There two most commonly used ways to package educational content I saw when I was working for universities were:</p>
<ol>
<li>Per student pricing (teachers are free) with a minimum number of students to qualify.</li>
<li>Site license allowing any student or teacher to access the content during a fixed period (typically a year).</li>
</ol>
<p>I don’t think there is one right answer. Sometimes the content is required by a single course and comes out of that courses budget. Other times a school or university would buy it for everyone.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/pricing-for-schools/4203/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/pricing-for-schools/4203/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 12:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4203-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/pricing-for-schools/4203.rss">Pricing for schools?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Pricing for schools?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[avdi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>So here’s a question.</p>
<p>Recently I’ve gotten a lot of great advice on pricing for individuals and for teams. But one area where I’m still at sea, pricing-wise, is in what to offer to schools (e.g. coding bootcamps) that want to use my material as part of their curriculum.</p>
<p>Any thoughts on how to approach this question? I’m looking for both pricing advice as well as advice on the “package” I should be offering to for-profit educational institutions.</p>
<p>Thanks!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/pricing-for-schools/4203/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/pricing-for-schools/4203/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 18:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4203-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/pricing-for-schools/4203.rss">Pricing for schools?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
