<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Working on a new app that injects a bunch of custom emoji into your Slack/Discord workspace. Would love your thoughts!</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/working-on-a-new-app-that-injects-a-bunch-of-custom-emoji-into-your-slack-discord-workspace-would-love-your-thoughts/7216</link>
    <description>Hey there folks! Working on a new side project/toy for avid users of conversational workspaces like Slack and Discord. If you&#39;re anything like me and the teams on which I participate, emojis are a huge element of our banter and conversations. We&#39;re also fans of the custom emoji features, but finding the right emoji (especially for an in-the-moment reaction) is sometimes tough. 

So we&#39;re building an app that injects a boat load of custom emojis into these workspaces for you. We&#39;re in the research phase at the moment and hoping to gather feedback and ideas from communities who use these apps often. Please check out the idea at **moji.studio** (yep, that&#39;s the URL) and click the Sign Up button to answer a few quick questions (literally about 2 minutes).</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 19:16:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Show Bootstrapped</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/working-on-a-new-app-that-injects-a-bunch-of-custom-emoji-into-your-slack-discord-workspace-would-love-your-thoughts/7216.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Working on a new app that injects a bunch of custom emoji into your Slack/Discord workspace. Would love your thoughts!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[amongmany]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey there folks! Working on a new side project/toy for avid users of conversational workspaces like Slack and Discord. If you’re anything like me and the teams on which I participate, emojis are a huge element of our banter and conversations. We’re also fans of the custom emoji features, but finding the right emoji (especially for an in-the-moment reaction) is sometimes tough.</p>
<p>So we’re building an app that injects a boat load of custom emojis into these workspaces for you. We’re in the research phase at the moment and hoping to gather feedback and ideas from communities who use these apps often. Please check out the idea at <strong>moji.studio</strong> (yep, that’s the URL) and click the Sign Up button to answer a few quick questions (literally about 2 minutes).</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/working-on-a-new-app-that-injects-a-bunch-of-custom-emoji-into-your-slack-discord-workspace-would-love-your-thoughts/7216/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/working-on-a-new-app-that-injects-a-bunch-of-custom-emoji-into-your-slack-discord-workspace-would-love-your-thoughts/7216/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 19:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-7216-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/working-on-a-new-app-that-injects-a-bunch-of-custom-emoji-into-your-slack-discord-workspace-would-love-your-thoughts/7216.rss">Working on a new app that injects a bunch of custom emoji into your Slack/Discord workspace. Would love your thoughts!</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
