<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Howdy. I&#39;m Matt, from Karani &amp; Good Food</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/howdy-im-matt-from-karani-good-food/740</link>
    <description>Hey! I&#39;m Matt Stauffer. I&#39;m a developer and a consultant, and I&#39;ve sort of accidentally become a bootstrap founder.

**The short story:** I work full-time as a consultant/developer, and in my spare time I run **[Karani][1], a CRM for fundraisers**. I wrote the primary codebase and made the initial designs for Karani, but I&#39;ve decided, at the moment, to hire people part time to continue work on it, and I just oversee/direct and write some code here and there on nights and weekends.

-----

**Longer story:** I worked in non-technical positions for a non-profit for years; while I was there I started Staffhacker (now defunct), a Lifehacker-ish blog about tech &amp; productivity for campus ministers. In writing that blog I realized how badly we needed a CRM for fundraisers, so I bootstrapped a little app that eventually became Karani.

I had never heard the phrase bootstrap, or realized that I was a startup founder, until I attended LessConf in March of this year ([I wrote about it a bit][2]). I&#39;ve never read HackerNews or considered myself an entrepreneur--I just saw a need, knew I could program, and have figured (ish) everything else out as I&#39;ve gone--payroll, taking payments, security, etc. So a lot of the stuff y&#39;all talk about here is pretty new for me. :smile:
 
Today, I&#39;m a partner at Good Food Productions, a Chicago-based web consultancy. I run Karani in my nights and weekends; I have a part time developer, part time user advocate, and a part time designer working for Karani. With both Karani and my day job I code primarily in PHP (Laravel these days), MySQL, and various front-end tech, and Rails every once in a while.


  [1]: https://karaniapp.com/
  [2]: http://www.mattstauffer.co/blog/2013/04/14/what-is-an-accidental-bootstrap-founder/</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 18:09:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/howdy-im-matt-from-karani-good-food/740.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Howdy. I&#39;m Matt, from Karani &amp; Good Food</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[mattstauffer]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks Jeremy! I appreciate it much.</p>
<p>And yes–Laravel and its community has singlehandedly brought me back to PHP.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/howdy-im-matt-from-karani-good-food/740/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/howdy-im-matt-from-karani-good-food/740/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 18:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-740-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/howdy-im-matt-from-karani-good-food/740.rss">Howdy. I&#39;m Matt, from Karani &amp; Good Food</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Howdy. I&#39;m Matt, from Karani &amp; Good Food</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jeremy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Welcome! I too recently realized ‘bootstrapper’ was a label. I knew it was a term, but didn’t realize anyone referred to themselves that way, just that a company was bootstrapped. So I recently stumbled on this great little subculture myself. Welcome to the party.</p>
<p>And Laravel FTW.</p>
<p>Jeremy</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/howdy-im-matt-from-karani-good-food/740/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/howdy-im-matt-from-karani-good-food/740/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 14:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-740-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/howdy-im-matt-from-karani-good-food/740.rss">Howdy. I&#39;m Matt, from Karani &amp; Good Food</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Howdy. I&#39;m Matt, from Karani &amp; Good Food</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[mattstauffer]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey! I’m Matt Stauffer. I’m a developer and a consultant, and I’ve sort of accidentally become a bootstrap founder.</p>
<p><strong>The short story:</strong> I work full-time as a consultant/developer, and in my spare time I run <strong><a href="https://karaniapp.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">Karani</a>, a CRM for fundraisers</strong>. I wrote the primary codebase and made the initial designs for Karani, but I’ve decided, at the moment, to hire people part time to continue work on it, and I just oversee/direct and write some code here and there on nights and weekends.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Longer story:</strong> I worked in non-technical positions for a non-profit for years; while I was there I started Staffhacker (now defunct), a Lifehacker-ish blog about tech &amp; productivity for campus ministers. In writing that blog I realized how badly we needed a CRM for fundraisers, so I bootstrapped a little app that eventually became Karani.</p>
<p>I had never heard the phrase bootstrap, or realized that I was a startup founder, until I attended LessConf in March of this year (<a href="http://www.mattstauffer.co/blog/2013/04/14/what-is-an-accidental-bootstrap-founder/" rel="nofollow noopener">I wrote about it a bit</a>). I’ve never read HackerNews or considered myself an entrepreneur–I just saw a need, knew I could program, and have figured (ish) everything else out as I’ve gone–payroll, taking payments, security, etc. So a lot of the stuff y’all talk about here is pretty new for me. <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
<p>Today, I’m a partner at Good Food Productions, a Chicago-based web consultancy. I run Karani in my nights and weekends; I have a part time developer, part time user advocate, and a part time designer working for Karani. With both Karani and my day job I code primarily in PHP (Laravel these days), MySQL, and various front-end tech, and Rails every once in a while.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/howdy-im-matt-from-karani-good-food/740/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/howdy-im-matt-from-karani-good-food/740/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 03:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-740-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/howdy-im-matt-from-karani-good-food/740.rss">Howdy. I&#39;m Matt, from Karani &amp; Good Food</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
