<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hiya, I&#39;m Rocky</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hiya-im-rocky/2728</link>
    <description>Heya fellow bootstrappers,

I&#39;m a functional, logic, and meta programmer who has passions in the lower-end of the spectrum, with particular emphasis on machine learning, natural language processing, expert systems, and other forms of artificial intelligence. I&#39;m also data scientist with a heavy background in both frequentist and bayesian statistics.

I&#39;ve been a quasi-bootstrapper for the past eight or so years. You might wonder what a quasi-boostrapper is, and it is someone who: developed a web-centric data platform about eight years ago (~500k rev, to-date, all passive income), got bored with the idea and working alone, went to work for/with super-computers/tech-giants/non-profits searching for what was missing, didn&#39;t find what exactly what he was looking for, and finally came back to the thought he could make a bigger impact on the world, and be happier doing it, by doing things himself once again.

I am coming back full-circle to the bootstrapping life with [Bayes][1] and some freelancing (3 to 1 split). I am opting for this route over the traditional VC route after starting down that path and realizing that I don&#39;t have the perfect non-tech cofounder, I can likely raising similar funds with via freelancing myself, and I simply like the lifestyle of bootstrapping over VC-land. Networking for networking&#39;s sake, CEO/CTO duties, high burn rates, 120-hour weeks, jeopardizing mission for money, etc -- these are things I don&#39;t care to partake in.

I was pointed to this wonderful community from Hacker News, and I must say it seems to be much different than most bootstrap/startup communities (the biggest complement I can give). So, HELLO WORLD! I love to talk with passionate/talented people, so don&#39;t be strangers :smile: 

  [1]: https://bayes.io</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 19:56:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hiya-im-rocky/2728.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hiya, I&#39;m Rocky</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[rockymadden]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Heya fellow bootstrappers,</p>
<p>I’m a functional, logic, and meta programmer who has passions in the lower-end of the spectrum, with particular emphasis on machine learning, natural language processing, expert systems, and other forms of artificial intelligence. I’m also data scientist with a heavy background in both frequentist and bayesian statistics.</p>
<p>I’ve been a quasi-bootstrapper for the past eight or so years. You might wonder what a quasi-boostrapper is, and it is someone who: developed a web-centric data platform about eight years ago (~500k rev, to-date, all passive income), got bored with the idea and working alone, went to work for/with super-computers/tech-giants/non-profits searching for what was missing, didn’t find what exactly what he was looking for, and finally came back to the thought he could make a bigger impact on the world, and be happier doing it, by doing things himself once again.</p>
<p>I am coming back full-circle to the bootstrapping life with <a href="https://bayes.io" rel="nofollow noopener">Bayes</a> and some freelancing (3 to 1 split). I am opting for this route over the traditional VC route after starting down that path and realizing that I don’t have the perfect non-tech cofounder, I can likely raising similar funds with via freelancing myself, and I simply like the lifestyle of bootstrapping over VC-land. Networking for networking’s sake, CEO/CTO duties, high burn rates, 120-hour weeks, jeopardizing mission for money, etc – these are things I don’t care to partake in.</p>
<p>I was pointed to this wonderful community from Hacker News, and I must say it seems to be much different than most bootstrap/startup communities (the biggest complement I can give). So, HELLO WORLD! I love to talk with passionate/talented people, so don’t be strangers <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hiya-im-rocky/2728/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hiya-im-rocky/2728/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 14:50:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2728-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hiya-im-rocky/2728.rss">Hiya, I&#39;m Rocky</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
