<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Peter Harkins</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-peter-harkins/311</link>
    <description>Hi, I&#39;m Peter Harkins, a web developer in Chicago.

I have a labor of love at [NearbyGamers.com] that helps people who play tabletop games meet up with folks to play tabletop games. Emphasis on the labor; I&#39;ve been updating it from Rails 2.1 to 4. In any case, it&#39;s now a large enough site that I&#39;d like to treat it less like a hobby and more like a business, so I&#39;m starting to add basic information on events, conventions, and retailers to the site and talk to them about what they&#39;d like in a premium listing. When that&#39;s in a stable place I&#39;ll probably move on to some kind of business-oriented saas, though for now I&#39;m still filling up my ideas text file. :)

And with my other link, I&#39;ll mention I&#39;m on Twitter as [@pushcx](http://twitter.com/pushcx).

In any case, I&#39;ve been feeling like my biz signal:noise ratio is poor, so I&#39;m going to be pretty quiet until things get done.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 17:56:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-peter-harkins/311.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Peter Harkins</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[sean]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey Peter! I remember you from the 47Masterminds group we were in a while back. Welcome to the board!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-peter-harkins/311/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-peter-harkins/311/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 17:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-311-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-peter-harkins/311.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Peter Harkins</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Peter Harkins</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pushcx]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi, I’m Peter Harkins, a web developer in Chicago.</p>
<p>I have a labor of love at [<a href="http://NearbyGamers.com" rel="nofollow noopener">NearbyGamers.com</a>] that helps people who play tabletop games meet up with folks to play tabletop games. Emphasis on the labor; I’ve been updating it from Rails 2.1 to 4. In any case, it’s now a large enough site that I’d like to treat it less like a hobby and more like a business, so I’m starting to add basic information on events, conventions, and retailers to the site and talk to them about what they’d like in a premium listing. When that’s in a stable place I’ll probably move on to some kind of business-oriented saas, though for now I’m still filling up my ideas text file. <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>And with my other link, I’ll mention I’m on Twitter as <a href="http://twitter.com/pushcx" rel="nofollow noopener">@pushcx</a>.</p>
<p>In any case, I’ve been feeling like my biz signal:noise ratio is poor, so I’m going to be pretty quiet until things get done.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-peter-harkins/311/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-peter-harkins/311/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 17:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-311-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-peter-harkins/311.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Peter Harkins</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
