<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Moving a business to another state?</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/moving-a-business-to-another-state/4880</link>
    <description>My wife and I&#39;ve got a Washington State LLC (software consultancy) that files taxes as an S-corp. The business bank accounts and mailing address are in WA, but there&#39;s no real physical presence.

Our clients and contractors are spread across the US and internationally, but we have no employees, just us two owners/members. We are thinking about moving to California and wondering what are options are for the business. 

A cursory glance suggests that domestication is the likely best choice, but I&#39;m hoping there might be something simpler where we keep the business in WA, but work out of CA. Or hell, maybe move the company somewhere else entirely.

Anyone gone through this before?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 01:36:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/moving-a-business-to-another-state/4880.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Moving a business to another state?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[yanokwa]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>My wife and I’ve got a Washington State LLC (software consultancy) that files taxes as an S-corp. The business bank accounts and mailing address are in WA, but there’s no real physical presence.</p>
<p>Our clients and contractors are spread across the US and internationally, but we have no employees, just us two owners/members. We are thinking about moving to California and wondering what are options are for the business.</p>
<p>A cursory glance suggests that domestication is the likely best choice, but I’m hoping there might be something simpler where we keep the business in WA, but work out of CA. Or hell, maybe move the company somewhere else entirely.</p>
<p>Anyone gone through this before?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/moving-a-business-to-another-state/4880/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/moving-a-business-to-another-state/4880/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 01:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4880-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/moving-a-business-to-another-state/4880.rss">Moving a business to another state?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
