<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bootstrapped Interviews - Discuss @ Bootstrapped.fm</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/c/bootstrapped-interviews/14</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Bootstrapped Interviews&#39; category People who are important to our community of software bootstrappers tell their stories here. You can:</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 08:39:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/c/bootstrapped-interviews/14.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Bootstrapped Interview: Robert Brandl, ToolTester Network</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Bootstrapped Interviews</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>A few years ago I created an affiliate program to increase the sales of my desktop app. The program had little success.</p>
<p>I’m doing now what I should have done then - interviewing someone who makes their living from affiliate programs.</p>
<p>Meet Robert Brandl. Robert runs a collection of affiliate marketing sites, collectively known as the <a href="https://www.tooltester.net/">ToolTester Network</a>.</p>
<h2>Hi Robert! What’s the ToolTester Network?</h2>
<p>From our office in Barcelona, we run review websites for various SaaS tools. Among other things, we test <a href="https://www.emailtooltester.com/en/email-marketing-services/">email marketing services</a>, <a href="https://www.websitetooltester.com/en/best-website-builder/">website builders</a>, <a href="https://www.chattooltester.com/live-chat-software-reviews/">live chat tools</a> and a few other web services. I started it in late 2009 while I was still working at my old job in an online marketing agency.</p>
<h2>Tell us a brief history of the ToolTester Network. Why did you start it? How did it grow?</h2>
<p>Basically I scratched my own itch. Since I am not a programmer, I found it very difficult to create a website. Back then software like Dreamweaver was state of the art. So I researched the web and found the first hosted website builders like Weebly, Webnode and Squarespace that even I was capable of using. As there was hardly any information on the web about them, I created a simple (free!) website with Webnode and collected all the information I could find. Total bootstrapper budget: $12 for a domain name!</p>
<p>WebsiteToolTester then grew through Google’s organic search. A lot of search demand was met with a very limited content offering. Luckily many of these searches ended up on my website. I guess I was in the right place at the right time.</p>
<p>I had already heard about affiliate marketing but never thought much of it. But reading that some bloggers make 4 or even 5 figures per month with it, I thought I could give it a try. Three weeks later I recorded my first sale, one of many more to follow.</p>
<p>Replacing my old salary took a little more than a year, which, frankly, surprised me quite a bit! Now I manage a team of four employees in our office in Barcelona. Initially hiring was a big pain point as I thought I should follow all these internet marketer’s advice to hire cheap remote staff in the Philippines. However, after a few initial interviews I realised that this isn’t the way to go as not one of the candidates even understood what my website was about.</p>
<p>What worked out well for me is to hire locally as Barcelona is a super international city, where you can find all kinds of skills and languages. Currently we only work with remote staff if we absolutely have to – even though it’s probably against the current trend. I like it when my employees are near me. I find it much more productive to work this way and I am also able to build much stronger relationships with them. My first employee has been with the company for six years already and is still with me today!</p>
<h2>Some people describe the affiliate marketing industry in unflattering terms. Do you think that’s deserved? How do you keep things honest?</h2>
<p>You are absolutely right that there are nasty things happening in the affiliate space. Probably the worst I’ve seen was an affiliate review website (which got its traffic via Google ads) do an A/B test with the rankings of the products they review. Reloading the page would give you an entirely new ranking table. So much about honesty.</p>
<p>On the other hand there’s also a lot of honest affiliates who genuinely want to help their readers and their community succeed. In our case we always have the comments in our reviews activated. That makes us accountable as our readers do let us know when there’s a mistake in the review or when they think something is not accurate.</p>
<p>Also there is this general rule I always give to my reviewers: would you recommend this product to a good friend? If not, it probably shouldn’t have a good rating regardless if they pay a high commission.</p>
<h2>What affiliate program is a good example that us bootstrappers can learn?</h2>
<p>It’s not easy to pick one program out of the many we are part of. <a href="http://Wix.com">Wix.com</a> have an excellent affiliate program with a team dedicated to supporting their affiliates. Their tracking software is excellent and allows you to track sub-IDs, specific landing pages and also do wire transfers instead of Paypal (which usually incurs high fees). But as they are so big it’s probably a bit hard to relate to them for founders of bootstrapped companies.</p>
<h2>What general advice do you have for a software bootstrapper considering an affiliate program?</h2>
<p>The best affiliate programs have a couple of characteristics that I wrote down in <a href="https://www.tooltester.net/blog/how-to-create-a-great-affiliate-program">this blog post</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Technical</strong>: There are technical things that are very important for me like being able to create affiliate links to subpages (so-called deeplinks). Ideally they also let you track sub-IDs so we can separate different languages for example. We are partners with some companies where we need seven different affiliate accounts because otherwise, we wouldn’t know from what language the sale comes from.</p>
<p><strong>Free Demo Account</strong>: What I find bewildering is how difficult many companies make it to obtain a free account for testing. Since we are a review website we really need a working demo account and I don’t think it’s fair to expect us to pay for it.</p>
<p><strong>Partner Management</strong>: One of the biggest factors causing an affiliate program to work or not is whether the company has assigned a person with responsibility for it. Too often the affiliate program is just run as an additional task by a marketing person who already has a million other things on their plate.</p>
<p>One thing that is completely overrated, at least for me, are banner visuals. I would not put them on my site and also don’t know any successful affiliate site using such banners.</p>
<p>We have built up some really good affiliate partnerships where we even publish guest posts on other websites where we mention our partners. I think that’s pretty much as good as it gets for the company with the affiliate program.</p>
<h2>Some affiliate programs offer benefits instead of cash. For example, DropBox offers more storage space, and MailChimp offers account credits. What are your views on this approach?</h2>
<p>Speaking as an affiliate this model is really not attractive. As you are saying, Mailchimp only pays out “monkey credits”. We’ve now got more monkey credits than we can ever use up in our lifetimes. But fortunately there are other newsletter services that pay real money.</p>
<h2>Where can people reach you if they want more advice?</h2>
<p>The easiest way would be <a href="https://twitter.com/RobertBrandl">@RobertBrandl on Twitter</a>. Judging by the amount of unsolicited emails I receive, it’s probably also not too difficult to find my email address somewhere on the web. <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapped-interview-robert-brandl-tooltester-network/6339">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapped-interview-robert-brandl-tooltester-network/6339</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 08:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-topic-6339</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapped-interview-robert-brandl-tooltester-network/6339.rss">Bootstrapped Interview: Robert Brandl, ToolTester Network</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Bootstrapped Interview: Andy Brice, PerfectTablePlan and Hyper Plan</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Bootstrapped Interviews</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Andy has been running his one-person bootstrapped software company for more than ten years. He has two products:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<a href="https://www.perfecttableplan.com/">PerfectTablePlan</a> which creates the best table seating plan in the least time, and</li>
<li>
<a href="https://www.hyperplan.com/">Hyper Plan</a> which combines the simplicity of sticking colored notes to the wall with the flexibility of software.</li>
</ul>
<p>Andy tells us why he bootstrapped, how he balances two products, how he stays motivated, and the changes he has seen over the years in our industry.</p>
<h3>Peldi Guilizzoni from Balsamiq says he was inspired by you to start his business. Who inspired you and gave you the desire and motivation to bootstrap a software company?</h3>
<p>For 20 years I worked for other people writing software that they paid me to write. Most of it never got used, which was very frustrating. So when the dotcom company I was working for laid me off I decided to strike out on my own. Having seen in the dotcom company how stressful it was dealing with investors, I never wanted to take investment.</p>
<p>Two of my friends had been running a small software business for a while. So that gave me the confidence that it was do-able.</p>
<p>I was also inspired by the dotcom boom and bust. A lot of people had started companies who clearly had no idea what they were doing. If they could do it, why couldn’t I?</p>
<p>Lots of other people have helped and inspired me along the way. Too many to mention. But Joel Spolsky’s Business of Software Forum was important in the early days.</p>
<p>It is interesting to see how the people who were on the Business of Software Forum at same time as me have gone off into different directions. Peldi has been very successful at growing his company. He<br>
should be very proud of what he has achieved. But employing lots of people sounds stressful and I have consciously decided not to follow that path.</p>
<h3>How did your life change as a consequence of creating PerfectTablePlan as a bootstrapped business?</h3>
<p>After a couple of lean years, I am now significantly better off financially and I have a lot more flexibility and freedom in my day-to-day life. My commute is about ten meters and I never have to set an alarm clock for work. So it is mostly very positive. But of course there are always negatives. It can be isolating to work on your own. So I try to keep in touch with other bootstrappers and I do some volunteering to get out of the office.</p>
<h3>Developing, marketing, and supporting one product is already a challenge for a one-person company. Why did you add a second product to your workload?</h3>
<p>Trying to keep two products moving forward on your own is certainly a challenge. But I felt I had all my eggs in one basket with PerfectTablePlan and no product lasts forever. So I wanted to diversify<br>
a bit. There was also the danger of getting stale after working on PerfectTablePlan continuously since 2005. And the idea for Hyper Plan had been burning a hole in my brain for quite a while. Plus I was in the fortunate position of being able to use the income for PerfectTablePlan to finance the development of Hyper Plan.</p>
<h3>How do you balance the day-to-day operations of your two products?</h3>
<p>Using Hyper Plan, of course!</p>
<p>I naturally alternate between working on PerfectTablePlan and Hyper Plan. And I try to keep a balance between the reactive stuff (bug fixing, support) and the longer term stuff (major releases, marketing). I never promise release dates to customers and that takes the pressure off a lot.</p>
<h3>You started your bootstrapped company in 2005. It is now 2019. Tell us how you deal with the struggle to stay motivated day after day, year after year.</h3>
<p>I have tried to keep things varied. As well as creating, supporting and marketing products I have also done some consulting (mostly helping programmers launching products with their marketing) and run some face-to-face training courses for others wanting to start a software business. Having paying customers also helps a lot with motivation.</p>
<p>But staying motivated definitely can be a struggle at times. I think that part of it is accepting that you will go through periods when you have lost your mojo. Don’t beat yourself up about it.</p>
<p>Also I think it is important to exercise. I try to get out of the office to run, cycle, swim or do some martial arts most days.</p>
<h3>What changes have you seen in the bootstrapped software industry over the years with regards to sales and marketing strategies?</h3>
<p>Obviously the big changes in the market are the move from Windows and Mac software to web-based products with subscriptions and mobile software. The mobile market looks horrible. But maybe I will do a web-based product one day. Some products still make more sense on the desktop.</p>
<p>The marketing channels are changing all the time. For example, download sites like <code>Tucows.com</code> were big in 2005. And I used to advertise in glossy wedding magazines - remember magazines? And I could get targeted clicks for £0.05 each on Google Adwords!</p>
<p>But human nature doesn’t change very much, so the basics of marketing and sales remain the same.</p>
<h3>Compared to when you started, what advantages do first-time bootstrappers have in 2019?</h3>
<p>It is easier to write and distribute software now. But that is a double-edged sword as it means a lot more competition. So I think that marketing skills are increasingly important.</p>
<h3>What words of advice do you have to someone dreaming today of creating and launching their first bootstrapped product?</h3>
<p>I wrote a whole 2 day course on this. So it is hard to condense it down a few sentences!</p>
<p>Bootstrapping a software company is hard. Don’t believe anyone who tells you different - they are probably trying to sell you something. If you don’t have plenty of energy, drive and determination - it’s not for you.</p>
<p>It is useful to learn from forums, books and courses before taking the plunge. But the real learning only starts when you create something and try to get people to pay for it.</p>
<p>Be prepared to learn marketing, sales and business skills. If you want to just program, you are probably better off working for someone else.</p>
<p>Release something as soon as you think it might be useful to someone and iterate like crazy based on the feedback. Be flexible - often the opportunity turns out to be quite different to what you expected.</p>
<p>Strangers giving you money is the only true validation.</p>
<p>When you are running a business there is a near infinite list of things to do and you are never quite sure which one to do next. Get used to it.</p>
<p>Don’t be put off by not knowing everything before you start. No-one starting their first software company has any real idea what they are doing (especially if they think they do).</p>
<ul>
<li>
<a class="mention" href="/u/andy">@Andy</a>, <a href="https://www.perfecttableplan.com/">PerfectTablePlan</a> and <a href="https://www.hyperplan.com/">Hyper Plan</a>
</li>
</ul>
            <p><small>9 posts - 6 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapped-interview-andy-brice-perfecttableplan-and-hyper-plan/6314">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapped-interview-andy-brice-perfecttableplan-and-hyper-plan/6314</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 12:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-topic-6314</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapped-interview-andy-brice-perfecttableplan-and-hyper-plan/6314.rss">Bootstrapped Interview: Andy Brice, PerfectTablePlan and Hyper Plan</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Bootstrapped Interview: Mark Littlewood, Business of Software</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Bootstrapped Interviews</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Our first Bootstrapped interview features Mark Littlewood. Mark runs the Business of Software (BoS) conference, held each year in both <a href="https://businessofsoftware.eu/">Europe</a> and the <a href="https://businessofsoftware.org/">USA</a>.</p>
<h2>Hi Mark! What’s the Business of Software conference? Who it is for?</h2>
<p>The Business of Software Conference is a conference and community for people who want to build software/SaaS products customers love and software/SaaS companies people love working for.</p>
<p>We curate a programme of talks that help people do three things:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<strong>Product</strong>. Think about how to build things people want,  will use and pay for. Not all great software products are great businesses. Not all profitable businesses have great software or do things that impact the world positively. How can you build things people will pay for and help you build a sustainable business?</li>
<li>
<strong>People</strong>. Think about how to create and grow a company that attracts the right type of talented people. At the heart of every great business, people make it happen. You need to find, attract and develop great people who need leadership, direction, purpose, vision and bring everything together so the sum of the parts is greater than the individuals in your team.</li>
<li>
<strong>Customers</strong>. How can you ensure that your business will be successful in the long term by ensuring that the software solution you build will continue to grow and attract more profitable customers? How do you find more customers (marketing) and get them to part with their money (sales)? Neither sales nor marketing are dirty words, though a lot of tech entrepreneurs fall into the trap of thinking they are, because of their experiences with the industry norms. There are much better ways.</li>
</ol>
<p>We steer clear of ‘magic’ solutions – those motivational speakers on the circuit offering the guaranteed SaaS marketing playbook type solutions. We know every business is different. Every business exists in a unique set of circumstances and context is everything. We never offer a ‘one-size fits all’ answer. Quite the reverse.</p>
<p>I think that most questions are relatively easy to answer once you know what the right question is for you. If BoS can help an entrepreneur understand what the right question is, we have succeeded!</p>
<h2>The Business of Software conference has been running since 2007. You weren’t directly running it in the first couple of years. How did you come to run the Business of Software conference?</h2>
<p>I was friends with Neil Davidson from college and have run events most of my professional life. Neil co-founded RedGate Software and got to the point when the company was 30 or so people. He thought he was out of his depth (he wasn’t), and needed to learn how to build a business. He looked at various events about building software companies and felt they were either about code, being a startup or how to raise venture funding/IPO.</p>
<p>There wasn’t anything about the craft of building a company. He set up BoS to scratch that itch. He also didn’t want to run an event business, as there is <strong>far</strong> too much hassle and stress.</p>
<p>Neil approached me as I ran events and shared a similar outlook on life and what was important. I got involved in 2010. He is still involved as a shareholder and we run BoS true to the original spirit of the idea, having resisted many approaches to grow, expand, scale, and take over the world.</p>
<p>We’re always puzzled when events market themselves as the fastest growing, biggest event, etc. McDonald’s is a big restaurant, but that doesn’t make it the place you dream of eating at.</p>
<h2>Running two editions of the conference on two continents is surely stressful. What motivates you to keep running the Business of Software conference?</h2>
<p>It is much easier to run the second event, Business of Software Europe, as it is on my home continent!</p>
<p>I do it because much of the time, despite the daily grind and the constant worry of, ‘Have we got the right speakers, have we got the right attendees, how can we manage the expectations of sponsors who so often expect to sponsor and speak?’, we are making a difference.</p>
<p>Last October, as I walked around a pretty big SaaS conference, someone came over to me and said,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Are you Mark Littlewood?”</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Duh, that is what my badge said.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>“You saved my life.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Huh?!</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>“I’d been running my company for 6 years, all in. Savings used up. Relationship at breaking point. I was despondent that what we were doing wasn’t working. We weren’t getting there. I was exhausted. Whenever I looked around for help or advice, all I saw was tales about crushing it. Instant success. Brilliant people with growth mindsets killing it. My life was wrapped up in my business, and I’d been telling my wife it was all going to be worth it. It wasn’t. I’d failed and the only way out for me was my life insurance. No use to me but… Then I watched Gail Goodman’s talk, <a href="https://businessofsoftware.org/2013/02/gail-goodman-constant-contact-how-to-negotiate-the-long-slow-saas-ramp-of-death/">The Long, Slow, SaaS Ramp of Death</a>. For the first time in a very long time, I got some perspective. This shit is hard. Don’t be hard on yourself”.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Happy ending. Five years later that person has a relationship with his wife and kids, some sort of work-life balance and a company with almost 200 people and no outside funding. He is alive and thriving. He recorded a video on my phone and asked that I share it. I don’t think I ever will as while it might be good marketing, it was a very special moment. That’s enough.</p>
<p>There are plenty more times when we’ve been told we made a difference, we have helped, and we have been instrumental in making a pivotal difference in the growth of a business. That sort of thing means I could never walk away.</p>
<h2>The <a href="https://businessofsoftware.org/2016/07/all-talks-from-business-of-software-conferences-in-one-place-saas-software-talks/">videos of all talks from past conferences</a> are a great resource for Bootstrappers. Some, such as Gail Goodman’s talk you mentioned have become widely-shared classics.  What are a couple of your all-time favourite talks? Why are they favourites of yours?</h2>
<p>All the talks are my favourite talks! Never a dud. Well, there are two I have curated that I am embarrassed to have had talk. They won’t be coming back. They disrespected me but most important, the audience.</p>
<p>A favourite is, Greg Baugues, now at Twilio, on <a href="https://businessofsoftware.org/2013/11/developers-entrepreneurs-depression-a-wonderful-talk-at-business-of-software-conference/">Developers, Depression and Tech</a>. We talked about feelings before it was fashionable.</p>
<p>Greg applied to do a BoS Business Development talk. He didn’t get to talk but I really liked him and we stayed in touch. A couple of years later he applied to do a Lighting Talk about depression. We decided to make it a full talk.</p>
<p>It is the only talk in BoS history that had a standing ovation. It was incredibly powerful and hysterically funny. It got people talking and saved lives - literally. I still get emails.</p>
<p>Greg had a massive impact on me personally, I discovered I had ADHD as a result and that probably saved my marriage but that’s another story.</p>
<h2>Us Bootstrappers have limited funds and time. What’s the value to Bootstrappers of attending conferences? How should we choose which conferences to go to?</h2>
<p>Conferences do many things and you have to pick the ones that are right for you and what you want to achieve. Some help you promote your business, meet new potential customers, raise your profile, and help you hang out with people that pursue the same groove as you.</p>
<p>We serve a niche. Our attendees want to be the best they can at what they do, spend time with like minded folk, and come to listen. They want to spend time with other smart people and spend time working on, not in, their business.</p>
<p>Whatever you do, you should be clear about why you want to come and what you want to achieve.</p>
<h2>Now a chance to pitch Business of Software directly. Convince us that Business of Software is a good choice for Bootstrappers!</h2>
<p>We will give you ideas and the connections to help you build a profitable, sustainable, business, or your money back.</p>
<p>– <a class="mention" href="/u/marklittlewood">@MarkLittlewood</a>, Business of Software</p>
<hr>
<h2>Want to know more about BoS? The next events are</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<a href="https://businessofsoftware.eu/">Business of Software Europe</a>: 11th-12th April 2019 – Cambridge, UK</li>
<li>
<a href="https://businessofsoftware.org/">Business of Software USA</a>: 16th-18th September 2019 – Boston MA</li>
</ul>
<p>Can’t make it to the events? You can watch <a href="https://businessofsoftware.org/2016/07/all-talks-from-business-of-software-conferences-in-one-place-saas-software-talks/">videos from past events</a>.</p>
<p>For Bootstrappers wanting to go BoS Europe, Mark is kindly <a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/business-of-software-conference-europe-2019-tickets-50593455387?discount=BootStrapped">offering us tickets with a 20% discount</a>.</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapped-interview-mark-littlewood-business-of-software/6280">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapped-interview-mark-littlewood-business-of-software/6280</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 14:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-topic-6280</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapped-interview-mark-littlewood-business-of-software/6280.rss">Bootstrapped Interview: Mark Littlewood, Business of Software</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>About the Bootstrapped Interviews category</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Bootstrapped Interviews</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>People who are important to our community of software bootstrappers tell their stories here. You can:</p>
<ul>
<li>ask follow-up questions. We can’t guarantee the interview subject will answer your questions though!</li>
<li>discuss the interview.</li>
</ul>
<p>Remember to be respectful towards the people being interviewed!</p>
<p>We’re aiming to add a new interview once every month.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/about-the-bootstrapped-interviews-category/6249">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/about-the-bootstrapped-interviews-category/6249</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 17:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>Yes</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-topic-6249</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/about-the-bootstrapped-interviews-category/6249.rss">About the Bootstrapped Interviews category</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
