<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bootstrapped magazines &amp; media companies in the Digital Era</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapped-magazines-media-companies-in-the-digital-era/4440</link>
    <description>For inspiration, I&#39;m looking for magazines and media companies from the digital era that are bootstrapped. Probably rare success stories about a lonely person starting a media empire from the basement.

The closest I&#39;ve come is Gawker Media by Nich Denton (who eventually dug his own grave, but this is something I&#39;m not interested in discussing).

Maybe from the history Condé Montrose Nast who built an empire -- but he was a good investor who knew the market above everything.

All the success stories I&#39;ve read are basically &quot;blogs of how to make money.&quot; Okay, some mommy blogs too, I guess. But out these two categories, can anyone give me some inspiration?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 16:12:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapped-magazines-media-companies-in-the-digital-era/4440.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Bootstrapped magazines &amp; media companies in the Digital Era</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[liams]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>For inspiration, I’m looking for magazines and media companies from the digital era that are bootstrapped. Probably rare success stories about a lonely person starting a media empire from the basement.</p>
<p>The closest I’ve come is Gawker Media by Nich Denton (who eventually dug his own grave, but this is something I’m not interested in discussing).</p>
<p>Maybe from the history Condé Montrose Nast who built an empire – but he was a good investor who knew the market above everything.</p>
<p>All the success stories I’ve read are basically “blogs of how to make money.” Okay, some mommy blogs too, I guess. But out these two categories, can anyone give me some inspiration?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapped-magazines-media-companies-in-the-digital-era/4440/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapped-magazines-media-companies-in-the-digital-era/4440/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 16:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4440-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bootstrapped-magazines-media-companies-in-the-digital-era/4440.rss">Bootstrapped magazines &amp; media companies in the Digital Era</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
