<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>ThingsIWantMade.com</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/thingsiwantmade-com/353</link>
    <description>I&#39;m not sure how &quot;useful&quot; this is, but it&#39;s up our alley, and it is entertaining.

[ThingsIWantMade.com][1] is a site that allows people to submit ideas for products and software they would like have made (by someone else, presumably), and each submission gets voted on.

It&#39;s an interesting site to peruse if you&#39;re brainstorming some ideas for consumer-based software, and while many of the submissions fall into the &quot;you&#39;ll need a lamp with a magical genie in it&quot; category, a few are interesting.

Just don&#39;t expect to get many solid ideas for B2B products out of this site.


  [1]: http://ThingsIWantMade.com</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 17:30:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Interesting Links</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/thingsiwantmade-com/353.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>ThingsIWantMade.com</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[andrey]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m not sure how “useful” this is, but it’s up our alley, and it is entertaining.</p>
<p><a href="http://ThingsIWantMade.com">ThingsIWantMade.com</a> is a site that allows people to submit ideas for products and software they would like have made (by someone else, presumably), and each submission gets voted on.</p>
<p>It’s an interesting site to peruse if you’re brainstorming some ideas for consumer-based software, and while many of the submissions fall into the “you’ll need a lamp with a magical genie in it” category, a few are interesting.</p>
<p>Just don’t expect to get many solid ideas for B2B products out of this site.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/thingsiwantmade-com/353/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/thingsiwantmade-com/353/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 17:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-353-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/thingsiwantmade-com/353.rss">ThingsIWantMade.com</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
