<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>The less time you have for your team, the more you need Teamscore</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-less-time-you-have-for-your-team-the-more-you-need-teamscore/4397</link>
    <description>Hi,

tldr: [Teamscore](https://teamscore.io) - Team peer review tool for managers who have very little time for their time

Wow, It&#39;s been quite a while since I posted here anything! I definitely fall in to the category of a lurker.

Few months ago I just started trying out Rails 5 and one thing led to another. Somehow along the way, some brain malfunction happened and I thought it would be better to write a small app with Sinatra. Realising pretty soon that it was a bad Idea, I still kept going. I kept finding few extra hours here and there to spend with Teamscore, slowly building my yet-another-sideproject. Unlike most of my sideprojects, I actually managed to get this into a MVP state, which could actually provide some value for it&#39;s users.

What I built is [Teamscore](https://teamscore.io) - An app that helps managers and team leads to figure out how their team is actually doing by creating a peer review survey for the team. The manager ends up with a report that she can use to start making things better. I work for a big financial institute and I see a lot of busy managers who have very little time for their team, so the idea for Teamscore originates from those experiences.

I just did the last deploy for today, adding Google Analytics. Now, as I&#39;m writing this, it&#39;s 1am here and I&#39;m definitely ready to get some sleep.  :slight_smile: 

Anyway, if you&#39;re interested I would love to hear your comments. Especially all the comments on the landing page copy since I&#39;m not a native English speaker.

Thanks!
@tuomasj</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 20:34:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Show Bootstrapped</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-less-time-you-have-for-your-team-the-more-you-need-teamscore/4397.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>The less time you have for your team, the more you need Teamscore</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[shantnu]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Ummmmm, I’m not sure.</p>
<p>In a toxic environment, this will just provide more fuel for the fire. I can just imagine some teams I worked with, where everyone would be sharpening their knives. <em>I’ll show them, now</em>.</p>
<p>And does a manager really need a tool to tell him which employees are not up to the task? If they really are that incompetent, why would they pay for your service?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-less-time-you-have-for-your-team-the-more-you-need-teamscore/4397/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-less-time-you-have-for-your-team-the-more-you-need-teamscore/4397/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 20:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4397-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-less-time-you-have-for-your-team-the-more-you-need-teamscore/4397.rss">The less time you have for your team, the more you need Teamscore</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The less time you have for your team, the more you need Teamscore</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[tuomasj]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi,</p>
<p>tldr: <a href="https://teamscore.io" rel="nofollow noopener">Teamscore</a> - Team peer review tool for managers who have very little time for their time</p>
<p>Wow, It’s been quite a while since I posted here anything! I definitely fall in to the category of a lurker.</p>
<p>Few months ago I just started trying out Rails 5 and one thing led to another. Somehow along the way, some brain malfunction happened and I thought it would be better to write a small app with Sinatra. Realising pretty soon that it was a bad Idea, I still kept going. I kept finding few extra hours here and there to spend with Teamscore, slowly building my yet-another-sideproject. Unlike most of my sideprojects, I actually managed to get this into a MVP state, which could actually provide some value for it’s users.</p>
<p>What I built is <a href="https://teamscore.io" rel="nofollow noopener">Teamscore</a> - An app that helps managers and team leads to figure out how their team is actually doing by creating a peer review survey for the team. The manager ends up with a report that she can use to start making things better. I work for a big financial institute and I see a lot of busy managers who have very little time for their team, so the idea for Teamscore originates from those experiences.</p>
<p>I just did the last deploy for today, adding Google Analytics. Now, as I’m writing this, it’s 1am here and I’m definitely ready to get some sleep.  <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>Anyway, if you’re interested I would love to hear your comments. Especially all the comments on the landing page copy since I’m not a native English speaker.</p>
<p>Thanks!<br>
<a class="mention" href="/u/tuomasj">@tuomasj</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-less-time-you-have-for-your-team-the-more-you-need-teamscore/4397/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-less-time-you-have-for-your-team-the-more-you-need-teamscore/4397/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 22:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4397-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-less-time-you-have-for-your-team-the-more-you-need-teamscore/4397.rss">The less time you have for your team, the more you need Teamscore</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
