<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bug bounties anyone?</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bug-bounties-anyone/4386</link>
    <description>Do you have a bug bounty program for your SaaS? What are your typical rewards and practices?

I&#39;ve been contacted by a security researcher form Asia, who found a number of vulnerabilities in [my SaaS](https://www.jitbit.com/hosted-helpdesk/), pretty ugly ones (a hacker can delete - but not read - other users data) so I fixed those and I&#39;m willing to pay him a reward. Not sure what the number should be. He asked for $3k but that&#39;s too much for our small bootstrapped company, I&#39;m trying to negotiate him down... So I&#39;m trying to understand the typical reward scale. I understand companies like Facebook/Instagram/etc pay at a scale of &quot;thousands&quot;, but this number looks too big for smaller self-funded companies...

So, any thoughts/experience on this would be appreciated. Thanks!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 01:29:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bug-bounties-anyone/4386.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Bug bounties anyone?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[steve]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>IIRC, this podcast discussed bug bounties as a very cost effective way to find problems with a site:  <a href="http://shoptalkshow.com/episodes/250-web-security-april-king-alex-sexton/" rel="nofollow noopener">http://shoptalkshow.com/episodes/250-web-security-april-king-alex-sexton/</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bug-bounties-anyone/4386/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bug-bounties-anyone/4386/3</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 01:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4386-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bug-bounties-anyone/4386.rss">Bug bounties anyone?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Bug bounties anyone?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[shantnu]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>No experience with this, but there was a post a looooooonnnggg time ago, about how someone’s company was placed on one of  bounty lists (without his permission), and he started getting hundreds of issues a day, mostly small css problems that were not a security threat.</p>
<p>He was angry and asked to be removed, but by then other lists had his company’s email, which meant more spam.</p>
<p>So I would be careful about this. There are specialised companies that test security of your software. Is there a reason you can’t hire them, rather than depending on random strangers?</p>
<p>Edit: Here is the link I was talking about <a href="http://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/security-strategy/2298/7">Security strategy</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bug-bounties-anyone/4386/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bug-bounties-anyone/4386/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 10:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4386-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bug-bounties-anyone/4386.rss">Bug bounties anyone?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Bug bounties anyone?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jitbit]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Do you have a bug bounty program for your SaaS? What are your typical rewards and practices?</p>
<p>I’ve been contacted by a security researcher form Asia, who found a number of vulnerabilities in <a href="https://www.jitbit.com/hosted-helpdesk/" rel="nofollow noopener">my SaaS</a>, pretty ugly ones (a hacker can delete - but not read - other users data) so I fixed those and I’m willing to pay him a reward. Not sure what the number should be. He asked for $3k but that’s too much for our small bootstrapped company, I’m trying to negotiate him down… So I’m trying to understand the typical reward scale. I understand companies like Facebook/Instagram/etc pay at a scale of “thousands”, but this number looks too big for smaller self-funded companies…</p>
<p>So, any thoughts/experience on this would be appreciated. Thanks!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bug-bounties-anyone/4386/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bug-bounties-anyone/4386/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 09:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4386-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/bug-bounties-anyone/4386.rss">Bug bounties anyone?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
