<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Business Insurance</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159</link>
    <description>Bootstrappers - do you guys take out business insurance?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 21:20:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Wanted to mention that <a href="http://www.hiscox.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.hiscox.com/</a> is pretty awesome.  I think they’re more of a direct brokerage or something - so I think you’re saving some money on the cut that the agent would normally take.  Their prices seem to be a lot cheaper than some other options.</p>
<p>They offer retroactive coverage which was something that some of the other policies I looked at didn’t cover.</p>
<p>Also they don’t require a general liability policy in order to get an E&amp;O policy.  Other agents that I had talked to said that this was a requirement, which seemed odd.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/27</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 21:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-27</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[peter_backx]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m in the same boat as Andy way up in this thread. It’s about 600 euros each year (for my limited liability business with only me working in it)</p>
<p>The insurance is called “beroepsaansprakelijkheid” in Dutch. Literally translated that’s “professional liability”. I’m not sure if that’s the name used in English, but it could be <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
<p>It’s a very broad policy. It should protect me against any of my mistakes that I make in a professional context and that I did not make intentionally. There are some limits to that. I don’t have the exact terms here with me, but I believe it covers about 1.5 million in material damage and a lot less (500k?) immaterial damage. And it includes legal help if you need it.</p>
<p>There are a few additional policies you can take to increase that last number in special cases (like accidentally breaking intellectual property laws or introducing viruses on your client computers)</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/26</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 08:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-26</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks Peter.  I don’t think I was asked questions <span class="hashtag">#2</span> or <span class="hashtag">#3</span> in the form that I filled out to get a quite.  Interesting.  Makes sense that those would be important indicators.</p>
<p>I think part of what makes business insurance a lot more mysterious than other forms of insurance that we deal with is that most of us just have a very small sample size in terms of having first hand or second hand contacts that have actually dealt with claims.</p>
<p>When you say I’m pretty sure I’m covered in the important cases, what are those cases?</p>
<p>Can you share what kind of cost your insurance policy is?  (I’ll DM you to see if you might prefer to share any of this privately if at all).</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/25</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 22:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-25</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[peter_backx]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="22" data-topic="2159">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/kalenjordan/40/2338_1.png" class="avatar"> kalenjordan:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>What are the top 3 to 5 factors about my business that are driving cost of insurance?<br>
What are the top 3 to 5 types of losses that companies like mine file claims for?<br>
What is the percentage of companies like mine that file for a loss over the past 10 years?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Insuring software companies and especially those active in the online world is a pretty new field. I think that’s why many people don’t really know the limits of their insurance contracts. I’m in the same boat. I’m pretty sure I’m covered in the important cases, but I won’t know until you actually need it, which I hopefully never will.</p>
<p>The most important thing for me is that I’d get legal help if I need it. I have a feeling that may be the most expensive part if anything ever happens. But again, unproven.</p>
<p>The questions I had to answer when I applied for insurance are partially the answer to your questions above:</p>
<ul>
<li>Do you store personal data for clients? How much and where? Do you have a backup strategy for that?</li>
<li>Do you have terms&amp;conditions and have they been verified by a lawyer?</li>
<li>Are there clauses in your contracts that limit your liability? Have they been verified by a lawyer?</li>
</ul>
<p>My company and me are in Belgium and the rate for this kind of business insurance was so low it was a no-brainer and I just took it.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/24</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 14:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-24</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[steve]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>[quote=“kalenjordan, post:22, topic:2159”]<br>
Obviously, insurance by nature is kind of complicated.  No one can give me an exact answer of exactly how covered I am for every potential scenario that could unfold.<br>
[/quote]Yep.  I worked at a medical malpractice insurance company for a couple years.  Insurance, like the law, can be infuriating to those with logical minds (like me, and I assume you) who want straightforward rules they can follow to be perfectly protected.  Sadly neither system works that way.</p>
<p>Do you already have an existing business relationship with a lawyer, and have user, support, etc. agreements created with a lawyer?  You may be able to head off a lot of trouble that way.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/23</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 01:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-23</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Alrighty, little bit of an update.</p>
<p>Thankfully, sales have increased and it’s time to work through this issue more carefully.</p>
<p>I’ve talked to a number of people about this and generally I’ve found that most people don’t really have any concept of what they’re covered for or not covered for.  They have a general sense of peace of mind because they’re <em>paying something</em>.</p>
<p>But they also know that they don’t really know what they’re covered for and suspect that if something went down, there’s a good chance the insurance company would try to get out of covering it.</p>
<p>So, little bit of a weird sense of security - but I’ve heard the same thing over and over.</p>
<p>I’ve seen strong endorsements of FounderShield from both Rob Walling and Josh Pigford.  Talked to them - the founder is super nice and quite responsive by email and phone.  But they haven’t really given me much in the way of detail beyond spitting out a standardized insurance quote.</p>
<p>Also emailed Patrick to get that insurance broker referral but didn’t hear back yet.  I know Patrick is a busy man though and don’t expect him to respond to my every email.   I’ll ping him again now <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
<p>I’m still trying to wrap my head around what coverages I should go for and how much coverage I need.  Here are a few specific questions that I’d love to get answered.  I have a feeling no one will have this information, including the foundershield founder - but we’ll see:</p>
<ul>
<li>What are the top 3 to 5 factors about my business that are driving cost of insurance?</li>
<li>What are the top 3 to 5 types of losses that companies like mine file claims for?</li>
<li>What is the percentage of companies like mine that file for a loss over the past 10 years?</li>
</ul>
<p>–</p>
<p>This whole process of buying insurance is so weird.  To use an analogy that all of us would understand, it’s kind of like a non-technical business guy who needs a website.</p>
<p>He asks around, everyone tells him to use Wordpress, and get a $1k site. That’s the prevailing wisdom.  Kinda like getting a $1m coverage is the prevailing wisdom for whether to get business insurance.</p>
<p>He says - will anything go wrong?  They say “oh yeah, if something goes wrong there’s a good chance that you’ll get screwed, but hey, what are you gonna do.  It’s better than nothing”.</p>
<p>But the information that he actually needs is:</p>
<ul>
<li>Your highest risk security wise are plugins that are not updated.  You should probably be on managed wordpress hosting that manages plugin updates and only accepts well regarded plugins</li>
<li>Your highest risk in terms of the development is hiring someone who doesn’t have expetise in the type of thing you want to build.  So you want to hire a company that has a lot of experience building wordpress solutions, and you probably want to pay them in the range of $5k to $25k.</li>
</ul>
<p>But no one tells him any of this.  When he asks what the biggest risk factors are, they have no clue.  They just tell him to spend the $1k and pray nothing goes wrong.</p>
<p>–</p>
<p>Obviously, insurance by nature is kind of complicated.  No one can give me an exact answer of exactly how covered I am for every potential scenario that could unfold.  But it just seems to me that people don’t even have a broad strokes understanding of what is covered with business insurance.</p>
<p>And it probably has a lot to do with the fact that most of us just don’t know people in our networks that have actually dealt with business insurance claims.</p>
<p>When you think about car insurance - we know that there can always be hairy scenarios in which we might get screwed.  But by and large you know what you’re getting into.  You kind of know the chances that you’re going to need to file a claim - you know several people (probably yourself included) that have done so in the past.</p>
<p>So you can make a relatively informed decision over whether you need comprehensive coverage or not.</p>
<p>But when it comes to business insurance, none of us really know anyone that’s ever had to use it.  So we go ahead and pay for something based on an algorithm that also knows very little about our type of business (i.e. in the event of a Stripe breach, will we be responsible for the tokenized cards or will they be?  <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/Insurance/comments/2wc3am/if_i_get_business_insurance_can_i_keep_my_company/cpggudi" rel="nofollow noopener">Might not be what you think</a>).</p>
<p>–</p>
<p>Also, here are a few resources I’ve found:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/Insurance/" rel="nofollow noopener">Insurance Sub Reddit</a> - pretty interesting.  Mix of insider baseball between insurance agents and insurance consumers asking them for questions / feedback.</li>
<li>
<a href="http://foundershield.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">FounderShield</a> - insurance focused for SaaS founders (in theory at least).</li>
</ul>
<p>–</p>
<p>Feedback welcome, so long as it’s specific.  If you’re going to say something to the effect of “paying $X to protect your business is worthwhile” without any specifics, that won’t be super helpful.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/22</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-22</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/madshadow">@madshadow</a> hey I know you wanted me to keep you posted on my decision <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:">  After talking with a couple of other business people that I trust, I decided to basicaly do what <a class="mention" href="/u/patio11">@patio11</a> said in his initial post, which is to hold off until I hit somewhere around $100k or thereabouts.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/21</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 14:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-21</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[steve]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>WRT incorporation, it’s hard to read the descriptions of ‘piercing the corporate veil’ and think I’d be able to appear sufficiently separate from my corporation for my personal assets to not be up for grabs.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/personal-liability-piercing-corporate-veil-33006.html" rel="nofollow noopener">article 1</a><br>
<a href="http://legal-dictionary.thefreedictionary.com/Piercing+the+Corporate+Veil" rel="nofollow noopener">article 2</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/20</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 15:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-20</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[coreysnipes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/kalenjordan">@kalenjordan</a> - when I was doing more web development &amp; consulting work (including a business partner + 2 employees) we kept an E&amp;O policy from <a href="http://www.techinsurance.com" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.techinsurance.com</a> .  That cost us about $850/yr, and we had to send them a 5-page form every year, to describe the size of the company &amp; types of work we were doing.  Quite worth it, I thought.  I also carry a general business policy (covers general loss and theft stuff) for about $400/yr.</p>
<p>I’d also get going on an LLC right away.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/19</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 13:52:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-19</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Certainly the business entity is most important. After that the insurance. I mean, I suppose you could look at it that way, but I don’t. I’d rather have some form of first line of defense. I’m under no illusions that the insurance company won’t try and find some way out or protecting me if they can <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> but still for a few thousand dollars it’s some additional protection at a modest cost.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/18</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 13:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-18</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[madshadow]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/kalenjordan">@kalenjordan</a> No, you should definitely be skeptical of any salesman, particularly an insurance salesman.  I think it is a difficult thing because, as you point out, there isn’t a lot of information readily available.   Personally, I haven’t gone through the process of obtaining this kind of insurance.  I suppose you might start by trying to find a good insurance agent with this kind of expertise through word of mouth.  Whatever information you can get from him or her, together with a good dose of skepticism, may be the best start.</p>
<p>Please keep us posted as you go through the process.  I’d be curious to hear what you find.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/17</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 20:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-17</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I get the risk.  Really, I do.  It’s the reason I’m spending time looking into this.</p>
<p>Regarding the premium / coverage limit, you’re basically suggesting that I do what the sales person tells me to do and take their word for it?</p>
<p>Not too comfortable with that idea.  It would be nice to have some kind of data on at least how accurately a given agent has estimated coverage limits historically based upon actual claims for their previous clients.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/16</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 15:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-16</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[madshadow]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/kalenjordan">@kalenjordan</a>  I think the key is that there is no maximum you could be sued for.  You are alluding to estimating some estimate of exposure based on revenue and industry…that’s what underlies the calculation of the insurance premium.  There may be companies that specialize in providing actuarial data on various risk factors applicable to your business; generally, though, the coverage amount suggested by an insurance broker and the associate premium are probably the best measures you are going to get.</p>
<p>Also, as several people have pointed out, someone is unlikely to sue you if you don’t have any assets.  However, I would say there are two points to keep in mind.  1) You’ve spent more hours, blood and sweat on your business than you can describe- if it all goes poof when you could have paid a couple thousand dollars a year to prevent that, you might have regret.  2)  Even if you have no assets personally and so aren’t worried about formalizing a business structure, there is still some pretty heavy potential fallout.  I’ve seen many situations where individuals get sued based on business dealings and end up declaring bankruptcy.  While you may have no assets to lose, having filed for bankruptcy is a tough scarlet letter to erase and can impact your future prospects for credit, jobs, professional certifications, etc.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/15</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 05:43:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-15</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/madshadow">@madshadow</a>, thanks man good stuff.</p>
<p>Is there some way of estimating the maximum amount that you could be sued for, based upon the type of business you’re in and the type of customers you have?</p>
<p>For example, in my case, it’s an ecommerce plugin - few thousand MRR currently.  Let’s say for example a customer was in the $10M yearly revenue ballpark.</p>
<p>–</p>
<p>Part of the reason I’m less concerned about incorporation is that I don’t have much in the way of personal assets to worry about (hopefully not for long!).</p>
<p>–</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="12" data-topic="2159">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/ian/40/3579_1.png" class="avatar"> ian:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Even if you do, you won’t have $1,000,000 worth of assets for a very long time. There’s no point in someone suing you for $10,000,000 when you only have $200,000</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/ian">@ian</a> this basically boils down to - people will only sue you if there’s enough to go after.</p>
<p>So by that logic, if you have less than $50k in assets, wouldn’t you be better off <em>without</em> additional insurance?  Because without the insurance, there’s nothing for them to go after in the first place.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/14</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 02:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-14</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[madshadow]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi all,</p>
<p>Indeed, I think the issues of insurance and business entities are related.  I’m a bootstrapper by nights and weekends, but during the weekdays I’m an estate planning attorney- part of my world of law is structuring ownership through the right types of entities.  I thought I would add some thoughts from a US perspective that may or may not be helpful, with the understanding that <strong>This does not constitute actionable legal advice.  I’m not addressing anyone’s specific circumstances.  I am not your lawyer.  I am not giving anyone individualized legal advice.  No activity on this forum creates an attorney-client relationship.  You should seek appropriate legal counsel</strong>  Ok…now that this is out of the way.</p>
<p>It is important to note that, although insurance companies use revenue measures in calculating the cost of premiums, liability doesn’t depend on your revenue.  Yes, the more you sell, the more exposure you are likely to have. But even if you only sell the first couple licenses, exposure to liability has already started.</p>
<p>If you set up shop without forming any formal business entity, you’ve opened up your entire personal wealth to liability.  Let’s say you create a SaaS, which Ian will hate, that gives a business some sort of metrics about their mailing lists and costs $5/month.  In month two (after which they’ve paid you $10 in revenue), the business makes some sort of large decision based on the information your product provided and your product turns out to be flawed.  This business just lost $500,000 because of the decision it made based on your product and it decides to sue you for that full amount.</p>
<p>Let’s start by clarifying - someone can always sue you…it doesn’t mean they are going to win.  Just a lawsuit alone, though, (even if you win) can put you out of business.  So this customer sues you and is able to prove a case.</p>
<p>Because you are a sole proprieter (the default when you have no formal entity), you are personally liable for any debt of the company, including a judgement based on a case like described above.  Now, the judgement is enforced and you lose your bank accounts, your house, your car, and perhaps a lot more.</p>
<p>If instead you form certain types of business entities, you may be able to limit the liability to the assets of your company.  Traditional business structures such as corporations and LLCs, if properly formed, maintained, and managed, can limit the liability stemming from a business debt to your investment in the business.  Sure, it would still suck, but now you are just losing your business bank account, the office chairs and pool table, and maybe your domain names (gasp!).  But you still have your personal money, house, etc.</p>
<p>The costs of setting up and maintaining a formal business entity include the costs of formation, annual filing and possible franchise tax fees, having to maintain separate books and records from your personal assets and a few other things.  This can be a pain.  Most people think it really doesn’t matter what you do if you own all of the equity of the business, but even commingling business and personal accounts, having the business pay for personal expenses, not maintaining accurate records, etc., could allow someone suing you to “pierce the corporate veil” and argue that you shouldn’t be afforded the liability protection of a limited liability entity.  However, it is a small price to pay for the protection afforded by a proper structure.</p>
<p>Now, which type of entity to choose is based on a number of factors and it is too big a topic for this thread.  Typically, businesses in this space will use either a corporation or a limited liability company.  What is clear, though, is that 1) you should not skimp out on the process and 2) you should seek the advice of an appropriate attorney.  Neither <a href="http://incorporate.com" rel="nofollow noopener">incorporate.com</a> nor even an accountant is qualified to walk you through the legal consequences of the choice of entity.</p>
<p>In the end, when we talk about insurance, the couple thousand dollars of setup cost and the money it takes to run the business each year is really worthwhile when you consider the protection it can afford you.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/13</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 20:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-13</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>$1,000,000 is plenty of coverage. You probably don’t make something that could cost someone provable liability to that level. Even if you do, you won’t have $1,000,000 worth of assets for a very long time. There’s no point in someone suing you for $10,000,000 when you only have $200,000. The coverage also covers lawyer fees which might be worth as much as the coverage itself.</p>
<p>Related, it’d be awfully rough to have something go wrong and get sued (or other issues) before you setup a business because then it’s you and your house and your dog they’re going to be going to first instead of the company. I don’t see the minor cost savings as outweighing the risks.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/12</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 17:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-12</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[dennis]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>We also have E&amp;O insurance from day one. We found that going with a broker who specializes in IT companies can provide much better coverage for lower fees (if you are based in Germany and looking for E&amp;O insurance, I’m happy to recommend our broker).</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="9" data-topic="2159">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/patio11/40/1205_1.png" class="avatar"> patio11:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>and the dominating factors for the quote are a) revenue, b) number of employees, c) exactly what type of “tech business” I’m in.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Besides revenue, the covered amount is also a big factor in our insurance policy. If you deal with a lot of enterprise customers who have insurance requirements as part of their standard PO terms, I’ve seen a minimum coverage of $1.000.000 for property damages quite a few times, so this could be a good starting point.</p>
<p>Also, if you are not based in the US or Canada but have a lot of customers there, insurance for revenue with US/Canadian customers can also be significantly more expensive. For us E&amp;O costs 3 times as much per revenue for US/Canadian customers (I believe it has something to do with how liability lawsuits are much more expensive and likely to succeed there).</p>
<p>The tricky part is determining what part of your revenue is actually for services provided in the US/Canada. If you are selling software online or offer SaaS, then not all of your revenue with US/Canadian customers might be subject to the higher rates.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/11</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 07:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-11</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks Patrick - good stuff.</p>
<p>Incorporation - we might as well go ahead and cover this since it falls under basically the same premise as the insurance question which is how to most reasonably protect yourself legally / financially.</p>
<p>Thing is - in addition to the few hundred to incorporate, you also have to pay additional taxes every year.  I remember there being some kind of $800 additional fee or minimum or something that I had to pay when I had incorporated a few years back for a separate business.</p>
<p>Then you also have to pay your accountant several hundred more dollars per year to file those taxes.</p>
<p>And then you also have a bunch of stuff to do for corporate compliance such as meeting minutes and stuff.  And from my understanding, if you make any kind of mistake with all of the compliance, or if for example you comingle expenses even once, the corporate veil could be “pierced” as they say and you lose all the protection that you worked so hard to get yourself.</p>
<p>Obviously I’m not a lawyer and don’t really know much about all of this.</p>
<p>What bothers me is the uncertainty of knowing whether or not these measures (incorporation, insurance, etc.) are going to help if the worst case scenario were ever to play out.</p>
<p>In regard to liability, it’s good to know that it’s based off of revenue - in that case it probably won’t be much at all for me!  And it’s also great to have a solid referral - that’s one of the main things I was looking for, b/c I’m sure that as you said 99.9% of the agents out there don’t know anything about software.</p>
<p>Those three major triggers are helpful rules of thumb, and I think I don’t fall  under any of them currently.</p>
<p>But let’s say that I was over $100k in revenue.  Here’s what I wonder.  So let’s say you take out a $1m policy, and you’re in a B2B niche of some sort.  Assuming that anyone would ever sue you for $1m in damages, it’s not hard to see how they could sue you for $2m.  Figures add up quickly when it comes to businesses.</p>
<p>So then aren’t you right back where you started?  Because the policy is only going to cover up to $1m and after that you’re going to end up having to foot the bill yourself somehow?</p>
<p>So I guess I see this as another instance where it feels very uncertain as to whether that $1m policy is really going to protect you completely.</p>
<p>And what about different <em>kinds</em> of insurance - like e&amp;o vs. cyber liability vs. whatever.  Who knows whether a given scenario would be covered or not.</p>
<p>I’m sure you’d probably just say - go talk to an agency already, that’s what they’re here for.  But the problem is that I’d have a hard time trusting whatever an agent told me.  They’re incentivized to basically scare you into buying insurance.</p>
<p>And if you ever were sued, you know that you’re going to be handed over to someone else and your agent is not going to be there to help you out.  They’re just a sales person with a bit of knowledge in the field.</p>
<p>(That said, I’m really excited about that referral from Patrick b/c I’m sure that’s the best shot I’d have at getting as good of an agent as is possible).</p>
<p>Like I could very much imagine it being the case that if you were actually sued, you would realize that there are about 100 things that you would do completely differently next time around, and really the only way to ever know that is to just go through it.</p>
<p>For example, when I bought my first house - I tried to do a decent amount of research and had an agent to help advise with the decision.  But at the end of the day, there are about 100 things that I would do completely differently if I were to buy a place again.  Things that you just don’t really learn until you experience them for yourself and that an agent isn’t necessarily ever going to explain to you up front.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/10</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 02:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-10</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[patio11]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’d incorporate earlier than $300k revenue, probably, but that isn’t here nor there.  LLCs cost a few hundred bucks and an hour of work to get set up – easily worthwhile if you have any assets outside of the business.  (Both of mine are Nevada LLCs on advice of accountant, FWIW.)</p>
<p>Back to the topic: I have an E&amp;O policy for both my businesses (one policy covers both LLCs).  It runs about $2k a year, and the dominating factors for the quote are a) revenue, b) number of employees, c) exactly what type of “tech business” I’m in.</p>
<p>If you have difficulty getting a policy, email me, I’ll introduce you to my broker.  She’s fantastic and speaks software, which is handy, because the insurance companies (even the ones with dedicated “tech business insurance” product lines) are <em>totally clueless</em>.  She had to explain to underwriters the difference between on-premises and off-premises SaaS, for example.</p>
<p>You probably don’t need a policy if you’re just getting started in a non-critical B2C app.  For example, Bingo Card Creator has nearly zero risk of getting sued.  If it were my only business, I would have held off indefinitely.</p>
<p>For B2B, there are three major triggers:</p>
<ul>
<li>Many purchasing departments at larger clients (enterprise or even, say, a startup with a B round) will require you to have a policy as a checkbox item for any purchase important enough to require a contract review.  (i.e. $50 a month, no, $10k engagement, yes.)</li>
<li>If your software going down can potentially cause a total or substantial business outage for a client (e.g. Github, any analytics software which blocks page rendering if the JS isn’t working, etc), get it.</li>
<li>Just for basic peace of mind reasons, after you’re doing $100k+ in revenue, your business is worth not losing if somebody decides to sue you.</li>
</ul>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/9</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 01:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-9</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Interesting. Good to know!</p>
<p>No I’m following the Dave Ramsey school of thought (or at least the version of it that my buddy explained to me) which is to not incorporate until I’m up around $300k of yearly revenue.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/8</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 01:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-8</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>We’ve had errors and omissions insurance from very near the beginning, but we tend to be pretty conservative with these kinds of decisions. It’s based in large part on revenue. It won’t cost you anything to get a quote. I’d have it at anything more than a pittance of revenue. Also, of course I assume you’re properly setup as a corporation so if you get sued it’s not so easy (but not impossible) to get your personal assets, etc.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/7</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-7</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks Ian!  Sounds brutal but I’m sure for a business of your size it’s a no brainer.</p>
<p>What’s your take on when would be the right time (revenue level) for a bootstrapper to pick up some insurance like that?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/6</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-6</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>We have errors and omissions insurance. Costs about $4,000/year <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/frowning.png?v=5" title=":frowning:" class="emoji" alt=":frowning:"></p>
<p>I mostly worry about getting sued into oblivion!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/5</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 17:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-5</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m more worried about a tree coming through the roof of my office. ;0)</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/4</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 15:24:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Business Insurance</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks Andy.</p>
<p>I’m still pretty small but getting to the point where I’ll hopefully be running my saas app full time within a fee months so I’m thinking about these types of things.</p>
<p>I’ve been doing a bit of online research and I found this answer to seem to make a lot of sense:<br>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://clarity.fm/favicon-32x32.png" class="site-icon" width="" height="">
      <a href="https://clarity.fm/questions/322/i-m-thinking-of-starting-a-web-based-software-as-a-service-company-what/574" target="_blank">clarity.fm</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/361;"><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/app-assets.startups.com/share-default-min.jpg" class="thumbnail" width="690" height="361"></div>

<h3><a href="https://clarity.fm/questions/322/i-m-thinking-of-starting-a-web-based-software-as-a-service-company-what/574" target="_blank">I'm thinking of starting a web-based software-as-a-service company.  What...</a></h3>

<p>For example...is liability insurance needed?  There's currently no office, so it's not like someone can slip and fall on the sidewalk (a commonly cited example for why to get coverage).  Also, are there other types of coverage that are particularly...</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
</p>
<p>Basically if you’re not big enough to sue then don’t worry about it until you are.</p>
<p>Does that sound reasonable for a saas app just starting out?</p>
<p>I’m more thinking about cyber liability or e&amp;o type coverage in my case - not too much equipment to worry about.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159/3</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 13:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2159-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/business-insurance/2159.rss">Business Insurance</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
