<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>I want to be a guest on your podcast…</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-want-to-be-a-guest-on-your-podcast/7186</link>
    <description>...or on your friend&#39;s podcast, or on the podcast you really enjoy listening to. Particularly if the theme is **bootstrapping** or **startups** or **product management**.

I&#39;ve been hosting the new iteration of [the Bootstrapped podcast](https://bootstrapped.fm/) for a year. I now want to experience being on the other side.

Interested? Please DM me on this forum or contact me via Twitter: https://twitter.com/steveofmcleod.

## Why you should have me on your podcast

* I&#39;ll promote your interview with me - and hence your podcast - where I can - Twitter, my own podcast, my email newsletter, and on this forum.

* I&#39;m happy to be a guest even if your podcast is new and has a small audience.

* I&#39;ve got a year&#39;s worth of experience [being a podcast host](https://bootstrapped.fm/). Now I would like to experience being on the other side too.

* I&#39;ve got all the gear and I&#39;m ready to record some quality audio.

* Over the last 12 years I&#39;ve bootstrapped two products to profitability - and failed at some others.

* In the last 12 months I&#39;ve sold one bootstrapped business and bought another.

* I&#39;m currently trying to do a &quot;Gordon Ramsay&quot; on [a bootstrapped B2B SaaS I acquired](https://saberfeedback.com/). That is, fix the problems and make it sustainably profitable. (I swear a lot less than Gordon Ramsay, though.)

* I&#39;m probably the only guest you&#39;ll ever have with a Trans-Tasman accent. What&#39;s a Trans-Tasman accent? Good question! Let&#39;s discuss it on your show.

## Don&#39;t have a podcast but want to help?

Contact the hosts on your favourite podcast and suggest they invite me on! You can send them a link to the page you are reading right now.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 06:22:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-want-to-be-a-guest-on-your-podcast/7186.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>I want to be a guest on your podcast…</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>…or on your friend’s podcast, or on the podcast you really enjoy listening to. Particularly if the theme is <strong>bootstrapping</strong> or <strong>startups</strong> or <strong>product management</strong>.</p>
<p>I’ve been hosting the new iteration of <a href="https://bootstrapped.fm/">the Bootstrapped podcast</a> for a year. I now want to experience being on the other side.</p>
<p>Interested? Please DM me on this forum or contact me via Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/steveofmcleod">https://twitter.com/steveofmcleod</a>.</p>
<h2>Why you should have me on your podcast</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>I’ll promote your interview with me - and hence your podcast - where I can - Twitter, my own podcast, my email newsletter, and on this forum.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I’m happy to be a guest even if your podcast is new and has a small audience.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I’ve got a year’s worth of experience <a href="https://bootstrapped.fm/">being a podcast host</a>. Now I would like to experience being on the other side too.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I’ve got all the gear and I’m ready to record some quality audio.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Over the last 12 years I’ve bootstrapped two products to profitability - and failed at some others.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In the last 12 months I’ve sold one bootstrapped business and bought another.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I’m currently trying to do a “Gordon Ramsay” on <a href="https://saberfeedback.com/">a bootstrapped B2B SaaS I acquired</a>. That is, fix the problems and make it sustainably profitable. (I swear a lot less than Gordon Ramsay, though.)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I’m probably the only guest you’ll ever have with a Trans-Tasman accent. What’s a Trans-Tasman accent? Good question! Let’s discuss it on your show.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2>Don’t have a podcast but want to help?</h2>
<p>Contact the hosts on your favourite podcast and suggest they invite me on! You can send them a link to the page you are reading right now.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-want-to-be-a-guest-on-your-podcast/7186/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-want-to-be-a-guest-on-your-podcast/7186/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 06:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-7186-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/i-want-to-be-a-guest-on-your-podcast/7186.rss">I want to be a guest on your podcast…</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
