<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620</link>
    <description>Hello,
I&#39;m happy I found this community of like minded people. I hope to learn from you and help if I can.

I&#39;m at the beginning of my path to become bootstrapped. Probably as many of you I&#39;m a software developer. I have a regular job at Atlassian - I&#39;m developing the best project management tool - JIRA. 

But I&#39;ve always dreamt about creating my own company. Being independent and so on ;-) We all share the same vision. So I&#39;ve been trying for a few years, I have a few failed attempts behind me (personal money management site, iOS games for children).

I had a crash landing last year when I was so stressed out and tired that my health suffered badly. Funny thing it was when I felt the strongest of all time (I was trying to run a business, working, going to the gym and biking all the time). Being sick was a terrible experience back then (couldn&#39;t walk), I thought I couldn&#39;t make it and I&#39;m done with this entrepreneurship thing (and normal life).

But guess what, I&#39;ve recovered, took some rest and learned a lot about healthy food and health in general. Now 1,5 year after I feel smarter, stronger and still interested in doing my products. So being sick was actually great from the time perspective - it changed my life for better.

Currently I&#39;m involved in:
Queued - Mac menu bar helper for Buffer a social media hub (I wish I had more time to polish it and finally push it to Mac App Store)

[BetaRun.it][2] - I needed a site where I could publish Queued updates (it&#39;s a self updating Mac app) so I built it, but now I&#39;m thinking about making it a set of tools helping people run beta versions of their Mac software

[TeamStatus.TV][3] - this is something I&#39;m betting on - I noticed that at our small office (30 people) we have like 5 big smart TVs displaying different stuff from our build system, project management, etc. - all kinds of widgets to help us see what&#39;s going on in the projects, at other Atlassian offices it&#39;s the same - people are in love with this idea, Atlassian even released a proof of concept for everyone to try AtlasBoard - my idea is to take it and make a product out of it :smile:

I authored also a few JIRA plugings which bring me a few hundreds bucks from time to time.

Basically my strength is coding, my weakness is marketing (I&#39;m not an outgoing person). For some time I was thinking about finding a co-founder but it didn&#39;t work out. So I&#39;m still on my own learning how to change my weaknesses into strengths :smile:

Nice to meet you all!
 
  [1]: http://pawelniewiadomski.com/queued
  [2]: http://betarun.it
  [3]: http://teamstatus.tv
  [4]: http://atlasboard.bitbucket.org
  [5]: https://marketplace.atlassian.com/vendors/1043464</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 17:38:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pawelniewie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Welcome Jesse, it’s encouraging isn’t? <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620/7</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 17:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-620-7</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jessedterry]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="620">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/pawelniewie/40/1291_1.png" class="avatar"> pawelniewie:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Basically my strength is coding, my weakness is marketing (I’m not an outgoing person).</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<aside class="quote" data-post="2" data-topic="620">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/andrey/40/1196_1.png" class="avatar"> andrey:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>So, you’re basically like everyone else on here. Welcome to the forums!</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>That actually makes me feel a little better myself… welcome Pawel  <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620/6</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 14:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-620-6</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pawelniewie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Great advice Najaf!</p>
<p>I’m thinking about the same - to target Atlassian customers first, especially since there’s Marketplace where customers look for plugins.</p>
<p>I started with some landing page and was trying to gauge interest with adwords, but I’m thinking in this case it’s waste of time. Although I said that a few times before <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
<p>I haven’t thought about contacting existing customers and that’s really a great advice!</p>
<p>I did some market research there are competitors but solutions I found needed either a lot of customization (to work with Atlassian tools) or were focused on other ecosystems (one working solely with 37signal’s products). So I believe I can start with Atlassian as a differentiator (and companies using Atlassian products are really keen on the idea of paying for an “integrated” solution) but then I’ll grow and cover different tools.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620/5</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 08:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-620-5</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[najafali]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Pawel!</p>
<p>This:</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="620">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/pawelniewie/40/1291_1.png" class="avatar"> pawelniewie:</div>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="http://TeamStatus.TV" rel="nofollow noopener">TeamStatus.TV</a> - this is something I’m betting on - I noticed that at our small office (30 people) we have like 5 big smart TVs displaying different stuff from our build system, project management, etc. - all kinds of widgets to help us see what’s going on in the projects, at other Atlassian offices it’s the same - people are in love with this idea, Atlassian even released a proof of concept for everyone to try AtlasBoard - my idea is to take it and make a product out of it</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>and then this:</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="620">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/pawelniewie/40/1291_1.png" class="avatar"> pawelniewie:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I authored also a few JIRA plugings which bring me a few hundreds bucks from time to time.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>lead me to wonder why you don’t start <a href="http://TeamStatus.tv" rel="nofollow noopener">TeamStatus.tv</a> as a JIRA plugin? IIRC this is one way that Balsamiq Mockups started, and so would be a really easy way to get adoption fast, especially thanks to your close affiliation with Atlassian.</p>
<p>I can concur that at a big contract this year we had a similar pair of status boards in place, monitoring build status, traffic and counts of 404/500. Having a ‘mission control’ dashboard of all these displays is becoming a common theme in in-house dev/ops teams I’ve worked on over the past few years, so you’re definitely on to something!</p>
<p>In terms of marketing, have you considered using your contacts to get interviews with in-house developers to see what sort of things they want out of a system like this? It would be good also to survey the market for this in terms of competitors (I think there are a few out there, but the exact names escape me) to see how you can differentiate yourself.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620/4</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 07:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-620-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pawelniewie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Haha, so I’m in the right place. Thanks Andrey!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620/3</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 04:24:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-620-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[andrey]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="620">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/pawelniewie/40/1291_1.png" class="avatar"> pawelniewie:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Basically my strength is coding, my weakness is marketing (I’m not an outgoing person)</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>So, you’re basically like everyone else on here. Welcome to the forums! <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 19:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-620-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pawelniewie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello,<br>
I’m happy I found this community of like minded people. I hope to learn from you and help if I can.</p>
<p>I’m at the beginning of my path to become bootstrapped. Probably as many of you I’m a software developer. I have a regular job at Atlassian - I’m developing the best project management tool - JIRA.</p>
<p>But I’ve always dreamt about creating my own company. Being independent and so on <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> We all share the same vision. So I’ve been trying for a few years, I have a few failed attempts behind me (personal money management site, iOS games for children).</p>
<p>I had a crash landing last year when I was so stressed out and tired that my health suffered badly. Funny thing it was when I felt the strongest of all time (I was trying to run a business, working, going to the gym and biking all the time). Being sick was a terrible experience back then (couldn’t walk), I thought I couldn’t make it and I’m done with this entrepreneurship thing (and normal life).</p>
<p>But guess what, I’ve recovered, took some rest and learned a lot about healthy food and health in general. Now 1,5 year after I feel smarter, stronger and still interested in doing my products. So being sick was actually great from the time perspective - it changed my life for better.</p>
<p>Currently I’m involved in:<br>
Queued - Mac menu bar helper for Buffer a social media hub (I wish I had more time to polish it and finally push it to Mac App Store)</p>
<p><a href="http://betarun.it" rel="nofollow noopener">BetaRun.it</a> - I needed a site where I could publish Queued updates (it’s a self updating Mac app) so I built it, but now I’m thinking about making it a set of tools helping people run beta versions of their Mac software</p>
<p><a href="http://teamstatus.tv" rel="nofollow noopener">TeamStatus.TV</a> - this is something I’m betting on - I noticed that at our small office (30 people) we have like 5 big smart TVs displaying different stuff from our build system, project management, etc. - all kinds of widgets to help us see what’s going on in the projects, at other Atlassian offices it’s the same - people are in love with this idea, Atlassian even released a proof of concept for everyone to try AtlasBoard - my idea is to take it and make a product out of it <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
<p>I authored also a few JIRA plugings which bring me a few hundreds bucks from time to time.</p>
<p>Basically my strength is coding, my weakness is marketing (I’m not an outgoing person). For some time I was thinking about finding a co-founder but it didn’t work out. So I’m still on my own learning how to change my weaknesses into strengths <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
<p>Nice to meet you all!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 19:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-620-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-pawel-from-teamstatus-tv/620.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Pawel from TeamStatus.TV</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
