<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Aviv, currently working on deflect.io</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-aviv-currently-working-on-deflect-io/757</link>
    <description>Hey everyone!
A few months ago I left my job and started working with a friend. We do part time freelancing and use the rest of the time to work on our own stuff. After an idea or two that didn&#39;t go too far we&#39;re currently working on [deflect.io][1], a tool for helping web and mobile developers.

It started from a tool we wrote for ourselves and figured it might be helpful to other developers as well. We put a landing page up a few days ago to start collecting emails and are working to get our first version out the door an into customers hands soon.

Both my partner and I are new to this whole thing (we&#39;re developers with no experience in marketing, sales and bootstrapping), and I&#39;m happy to find a group of people going through the same kind of experiences :)

Cheers!


  [1]: http://www.deflect.io</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 09:05:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-aviv-currently-working-on-deflect-io/757.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Aviv, currently working on deflect.io</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[avivby]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey everyone!<br>
A few months ago I left my job and started working with a friend. We do part time freelancing and use the rest of the time to work on our own stuff. After an idea or two that didn’t go too far we’re currently working on <a href="http://www.deflect.io" rel="nofollow noopener">deflect.io</a>, a tool for helping web and mobile developers.</p>
<p>It started from a tool we wrote for ourselves and figured it might be helpful to other developers as well. We put a landing page up a few days ago to start collecting emails and are working to get our first version out the door an into customers hands soon.</p>
<p>Both my partner and I are new to this whole thing (we’re developers with no experience in marketing, sales and bootstrapping), and I’m happy to find a group of people going through the same kind of experiences <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-aviv-currently-working-on-deflect-io/757/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-aviv-currently-working-on-deflect-io/757/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 09:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-757-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-aviv-currently-working-on-deflect-io/757.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Aviv, currently working on deflect.io</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
