<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Making a fresh and wonderful product out of something old and stale</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/making-a-fresh-and-wonderful-product-out-of-something-old-and-stale/48</link>
    <description>Just wanted to point out a few things that caught my eye lately as examples of products that have been around for ages, traditionally presented in a old and stale way, that have been resurrected into new, modern interpretations, and those presentations, in themselves, have differentiated the products, and made them into something special.

One is [thepaperwall.com][1]. Wallpaper repositories have been around for as long as HTML had the &lt;img&gt; tag. They&#39;re next to shareware repos and website template junk sites as the used-car lots of the internet. But the folks at [BrightBox][2] have turned that old, stale concept into something fresh and beautiful. I spent tons of time on thepaperwall.com -- they just made browsing those wallpapers into a wonderful experience. I think the site serves as a portfolio piece for the company; they&#39;re a web dev consultancy from what I understand.

The other one is [forecast.io][3]. I don&#39;t know if these guys are VC-backed or bootstrapped, but it&#39;s just wonderful what they did with just a simple concept like weather forecasting. The site is clean, well-built, functional, plus they put in an developer API, and it looks like some other interesting bits. Even their sponsorship &quot;policies&quot; are thought-through, not allowing anything but a single hand-picked sponsor each week. I think @ianlandsman was a sponsor for a while on there. He can probably add more info. But it just seems like a great example of a fresh take on an otherwise stale concept that&#39;s been done a million times by a million people, but none as well as these guys.

I&#39;m not affiliated with either of these companies or products; just been visiting these sites frequently, lately, and I thought it would be nice to show them as examples of how presentation can make a great product out of something stale or seemingly too simple.


  [1]: http://thepaperwall.com
  [2]: http://thebrightbox.com/
  [3]: http://forecast.io</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 13:21:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/making-a-fresh-and-wonderful-product-out-of-something-old-and-stale/48.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Making a fresh and wonderful product out of something old and stale</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jamespanderson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="http://forecast.io" rel="nofollow noopener">forecast.io</a> is also one of my favorite sites.  It’s by the Dark Sky people, which was a <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/jackadam/dark-sky-hyperlocal-weather-prediction-and-visuali" rel="nofollow noopener">kickstarted project</a> (I guess that’s somewhere between VC and bootstrapped?)</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/making-a-fresh-and-wonderful-product-out-of-something-old-and-stale/48/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/making-a-fresh-and-wonderful-product-out-of-something-old-and-stale/48/3</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 13:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-48-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/making-a-fresh-and-wonderful-product-out-of-something-old-and-stale/48.rss">Making a fresh and wonderful product out of something old and stale</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Making a fresh and wonderful product out of something old and stale</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I also think the software we’re using for this forum is the same thing. Nearly all forum software is junk, but Discourse (<a href="http://www.discourse.org/">http://www.discourse.org/</a>) has made it usable again, even if it is Rails based <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/making-a-fresh-and-wonderful-product-out-of-something-old-and-stale/48/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/making-a-fresh-and-wonderful-product-out-of-something-old-and-stale/48/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 02:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-48-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/making-a-fresh-and-wonderful-product-out-of-something-old-and-stale/48.rss">Making a fresh and wonderful product out of something old and stale</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Making a fresh and wonderful product out of something old and stale</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[andrey]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Just wanted to point out a few things that caught my eye lately as examples of products that have been around for ages, traditionally presented in a old and stale way, that have been resurrected into new, modern interpretations, and those presentations, in themselves, have differentiated the products, and made them into something special.</p>
<p>One is <a href="http://thepaperwall.com">thepaperwall.com</a>. Wallpaper repositories have been around for as long as HTML had the <img> tag. They’re next to shareware repos and website template junk sites as the used-car lots of the internet. But the folks at <a href="http://thebrightbox.com/">BrightBox</a> have turned that old, stale concept into something fresh and beautiful. I spent tons of time on <a href="http://thepaperwall.com">thepaperwall.com</a> – they just made browsing those wallpapers into a wonderful experience. I think the site serves as a portfolio piece for the company; they’re a web dev consultancy from what I understand.</p>
<p>The other one is <a href="http://forecast.io">forecast.io</a>. I don’t know if these guys are VC-backed or bootstrapped, but it’s just wonderful what they did with just a simple concept like weather forecasting. The site is clean, well-built, functional, plus they put in an developer API, and it looks like some other interesting bits. Even their sponsorship “policies” are thought-through, not allowing anything but a single hand-picked sponsor each week. I think <span class="mention">@ianlandsman</span> was a sponsor for a while on there. He can probably add more info. But it just seems like a great example of a fresh take on an otherwise stale concept that’s been done a million times by a million people, but none as well as these guys.</p>
<p>I’m not affiliated with either of these companies or products; just been visiting these sites frequently, lately, and I thought it would be nice to show them as examples of how presentation can make a great product out of something stale or seemingly too simple.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/making-a-fresh-and-wonderful-product-out-of-something-old-and-stale/48/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/making-a-fresh-and-wonderful-product-out-of-something-old-and-stale/48/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 01:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-48-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/making-a-fresh-and-wonderful-product-out-of-something-old-and-stale/48.rss">Making a fresh and wonderful product out of something old and stale</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
