<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Daniel, and I have a question about videos</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-daniel-and-i-have-a-question-about-videos/5984</link>
    <description>Long-time lurker here.

My daytime job is technical coach. I teach tech teams how to run faster. I also teach large-ish organizations how to manage bunches of tech teams. I do coding, web design,microservice, and so forth. I&#39;m not an expert, I just know enough to get what I want done and I know the patterns used by good teams to kick ass.

I have been studying startups for several years, trying to figure out how they make things people want -- that&#39;s a critical part of any tech team, whether they realize that or not.

As part of that, I just finished my first long-form book, Info-Ops, back in April. It&#39;s all about organizing all of your project information. Now I&#39;m starting a blog series on learning pure functional programming in F# in a practical, pragmatic way. Working title is: Programming F# Like A Stupid Person.

I&#39;m getting some traction on this second series since it seems to be the only intermediate architecture book on the market for OO guys making the switch. So I&#39;m thinking about switching from a blog series over to a video series with a subscription/purchase option.

Any idea how I should go about funding? I&#39;d probably need between 10 and 50k depending on the parameters of the first several videos in the series. GoFundMe? Pre-paid using something like Gumroad?

Yes, I know I can do basically zero funding, but I&#39;ve found that video production is a huge hunka work, and there&#39;s a tremendous opportunity cost in dropping that much time and effort into it, so I can&#39;t do it that way.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 07:02:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-daniel-and-i-have-a-question-about-videos/5984.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Daniel, and I have a question about videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[skmurphy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>If you just did voice over screen captures a tool like Camtasia costs about $300/yr  (See <a href="https://www.techsmith.com/store/camtasia">https://www.techsmith.com/store/camtasia</a> ) and video hosting on Vimeo (<a href="http://www.vimeo.com">http://www.vimeo.com</a>) will only run you another $300/yr. A site like <a href="https://www.123rf.com/">https://www.123rf.com/</a> has stock sound (there are many others) so I think you could get start much more cheaply than you have calculated. The kind of technical content you are talking about developing should be a good fit for a voice over screen capture approach. We have done several demo videos for <a href="http://www.beamwise.com/">BeamWise</a> using this approach</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-daniel-and-i-have-a-question-about-videos/5984/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-daniel-and-i-have-a-question-about-videos/5984/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 07:02:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-5984-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-daniel-and-i-have-a-question-about-videos/5984.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Daniel, and I have a question about videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Daniel, and I have a question about videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[DanielBMarkham]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Long-time lurker here.</p>
<p>My daytime job is technical coach. I teach tech teams how to run faster. I also teach large-ish organizations how to manage bunches of tech teams. I do coding, web design,microservice, and so forth. I’m not an expert, I just know enough to get what I want done and I know the patterns used by good teams to kick ass.</p>
<p>I have been studying startups for several years, trying to figure out how they make things people want – that’s a critical part of any tech team, whether they realize that or not.</p>
<p>As part of that, I just finished my first long-form book, Info-Ops, back in April. It’s all about organizing all of your project information. Now I’m starting a blog series on learning pure functional programming in F# in a practical, pragmatic way. Working title is: Programming F# Like A Stupid Person.</p>
<p>I’m getting some traction on this second series since it seems to be the only intermediate architecture book on the market for OO guys making the switch. So I’m thinking about switching from a blog series over to a video series with a subscription/purchase option.</p>
<p>Any idea how I should go about funding? I’d probably need between 10 and 50k depending on the parameters of the first several videos in the series. GoFundMe? Pre-paid using something like Gumroad?</p>
<p>Yes, I know I can do basically zero funding, but I’ve found that video production is a huge hunka work, and there’s a tremendous opportunity cost in dropping that much time and effort into it, so I can’t do it that way.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-daniel-and-i-have-a-question-about-videos/5984/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-daniel-and-i-have-a-question-about-videos/5984/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 15:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-5984-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-daniel-and-i-have-a-question-about-videos/5984.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Daniel, and I have a question about videos</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
