<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>When I raised my B2B SaaS&#39;s prices</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/when-i-raised-my-b2b-saass-prices/7017</link>
    <description>When I launched Feature Upvote, my B2B SaaS, in 2017, the price was $29/month, with a 20% discount for paying yearly. I chose that price  arbitrarily, but also because it is what I felt I would pay for a similar service. 

After [hearing repeatedly that developers who start businesses need to charge more](https://www.kalzumeus.com/2006/08/14/you-can-probably-stand-to-charge-more/), I wanted to experiment with a small increase.

I delayed doing this until I had enough new customers each month to really be sure of the price change&#39;s effect.

In January 2019 I put the price up to $35/month, a 20% increase.

Why such a small increase? I knew in theory that I should charge significantly more, but in practice I wasn&#39;t confident about it. I am, after all, still a developer :) .

What happened? The conversion rate stayed roughly the same. That is, the same number of new customers per month, but each paying more.

Nobody complained. Ever. Not a single person questioned the change in our pricing.

A year later, in January 2020 I got bolder. I put the price up to $49/month, a 40% increase.

What happened? The conversion rate initially dropped a little but not much. It might have just been statistical noise, or the post-Christmas lull.

I was  getting fewer new customers, but they were paying more. Pricing experts say that customers who pay more tend to remain customers longer, resulting in a much higher customer life time value, so this seemed okay.

Then the pandemic started and we were all in shock and sales stalled for a little while. So it was really hard to tell the true effect of the price increase.

But now, six months later, I&#39;m signing up more new customers than ever, at the conversion rate we had before the price increase.

As with the first price change, nobody complained. Ever.

## What about existing customers?

I&#39;ve never put up prices for existing customers. I&#39;m okay with people getting the price they started with indefinitely. It is the way I&#39;d want to be treated as a customer. Anyway, within a couple of years, as existing customers churn, the &quot;problem&quot; of older customers paying less will simply go away.

## Has the customer base changed?

Yes. As the price goes up we tend to get larger organisations as customers. Unfortunately, they are also more likely to ask for custom legals, T&amp;Cs, and security audits. In all cases, I say no. That may change in the future.

## What did I tell existing customers about the price change?

Nothing. I probably should have, but it fell off my to-do list.

To make sure existing trial customers weren&#39;t shown one price and charged another, I did the following:

1. December 2019: change the prices listed on our pricing page, but still charge new customers the old pricing.
2. January 2020: start actually charging the new prices.

## Other pricing plans

I have bootstrapper pricing at $19/month (with a 20% discount when paying yearly). I&#39;ve had this pricing since the very start, and never changed it. It is an easy way to answer would-be customers who write &quot;I want to use Feature Upvote, but it is too expensive for me.&quot;

For charities or non-profits who ask, we have a plan that&#39;s 25% cheaper. Almost no-one asks for this plan. I don&#39;t know why, because it is featured on our pricing page.

Just about any Open Source project that asks can use us for free. There are a couple of stipulations, but I tend not to check too carefully.

## Do I charge enough?

I don&#39;t know. I&#39;m content with the pricing now, and have no plans to change it in the near future. Next year I might add a much more expensive enterprise plan, for those people who ask about custom legals, T&amp;Cs, and security audits.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 20:13:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/when-i-raised-my-b2b-saass-prices/7017.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>When I raised my B2B SaaS&#39;s prices</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Dmitry]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Similar experience here, raised prices 2x a year ago - it simply doubled the monthly income <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> Same for discounts by the way, last time I did a discount (it was for one-off desktop software purchase) the result was disappointing: got the same amount of customers who pay less. It was like 10 years ago - no more discounts since then.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/when-i-raised-my-b2b-saass-prices/7017/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/when-i-raised-my-b2b-saass-prices/7017/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 20:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-7017-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/when-i-raised-my-b2b-saass-prices/7017.rss">When I raised my B2B SaaS&#39;s prices</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>When I raised my B2B SaaS&#39;s prices</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>When I launched Feature Upvote, my B2B SaaS, in 2017, the price was $29/month, with a 20% discount for paying yearly. I chose that price  arbitrarily, but also because it is what I felt I would pay for a similar service.</p>
<p>After <a href="https://www.kalzumeus.com/2006/08/14/you-can-probably-stand-to-charge-more/">hearing repeatedly that developers who start businesses need to charge more</a>, I wanted to experiment with a small increase.</p>
<p>I delayed doing this until I had enough new customers each month to really be sure of the price change’s effect.</p>
<p>In January 2019 I put the price up to $35/month, a 20% increase.</p>
<p>Why such a small increase? I knew in theory that I should charge significantly more, but in practice I wasn’t confident about it. I am, after all, still a developer <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> .</p>
<p>What happened? The conversion rate stayed roughly the same. That is, the same number of new customers per month, but each paying more.</p>
<p>Nobody complained. Ever. Not a single person questioned the change in our pricing.</p>
<p>A year later, in January 2020 I got bolder. I put the price up to $49/month, a 40% increase.</p>
<p>What happened? The conversion rate initially dropped a little but not much. It might have just been statistical noise, or the post-Christmas lull.</p>
<p>I was  getting fewer new customers, but they were paying more. Pricing experts say that customers who pay more tend to remain customers longer, resulting in a much higher customer life time value, so this seemed okay.</p>
<p>Then the pandemic started and we were all in shock and sales stalled for a little while. So it was really hard to tell the true effect of the price increase.</p>
<p>But now, six months later, I’m signing up more new customers than ever, at the conversion rate we had before the price increase.</p>
<p>As with the first price change, nobody complained. Ever.</p>
<h2>What about existing customers?</h2>
<p>I’ve never put up prices for existing customers. I’m okay with people getting the price they started with indefinitely. It is the way I’d want to be treated as a customer. Anyway, within a couple of years, as existing customers churn, the “problem” of older customers paying less will simply go away.</p>
<h2>Has the customer base changed?</h2>
<p>Yes. As the price goes up we tend to get larger organisations as customers. Unfortunately, they are also more likely to ask for custom legals, T&amp;Cs, and security audits. In all cases, I say no. That may change in the future.</p>
<h2>What did I tell existing customers about the price change?</h2>
<p>Nothing. I probably should have, but it fell off my to-do list.</p>
<p>To make sure existing trial customers weren’t shown one price and charged another, I did the following:</p>
<ol>
<li>December 2019: change the prices listed on our pricing page, but still charge new customers the old pricing.</li>
<li>January 2020: start actually charging the new prices.</li>
</ol>
<h2>Other pricing plans</h2>
<p>I have bootstrapper pricing at $19/month (with a 20% discount when paying yearly). I’ve had this pricing since the very start, and never changed it. It is an easy way to answer would-be customers who write “I want to use Feature Upvote, but it is too expensive for me.”</p>
<p>For charities or non-profits who ask, we have a plan that’s 25% cheaper. Almost no-one asks for this plan. I don’t know why, because it is featured on our pricing page.</p>
<p>Just about any Open Source project that asks can use us for free. There are a couple of stipulations, but I tend not to check too carefully.</p>
<h2>Do I charge enough?</h2>
<p>I don’t know. I’m content with the pricing now, and have no plans to change it in the near future. Next year I might add a much more expensive enterprise plan, for those people who ask about custom legals, T&amp;Cs, and security audits.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/when-i-raised-my-b2b-saass-prices/7017/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/when-i-raised-my-b2b-saass-prices/7017/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 11:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-7017-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/when-i-raised-my-b2b-saass-prices/7017.rss">When I raised my B2B SaaS&#39;s prices</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
