<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Paul, founder of DonorElf</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462</link>
    <description>Hi everyone, I&#39;m Paul Yoder.

I founded [DonorElf](http://www.donorelf.com) a little over 3 and a half years ago. It&#39;s a SaaS product for missionaries who raise their own financial support to pay for their ministry and salary. 

There&#39;s a lot involved for missionaries to figure out which donors they need to be communicating with (e.g. send a thank you note to new donors, follow up with monthly donors that stopped giving, etc)

So DonorElf acts as a personal assistant for the missionary by analyzing their donations and letting the missionary know which donors they need to be communicating with.

I built it initially for my own benefit since I used to be with a missions organization and raised my own support. And it wasn&#39;t long before others wanted to start using it, so I rewrote it so many organizations could use it, and that&#39;s when I started bootstrapping DonorElf.
</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 20:04:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Paul, founder of DonorElf</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[paulyoder]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="4" data-topic="1462">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/stevemcleod/40/2640_1.png" class="avatar"> SteveMcLeod:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I’m intellectually curious about your view on making a good living from this site… Got a FAQ or feelings on this? Do you, for example, draw a capped income, and give the rest away?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>That’s a question I have thought about a lot as I’ve been working on DonorElf. And a question I had to ask myself even before that one is why charge for DonorElf at all?</p>
<p>I have a deep passion to help missionaries in their fundraising. I used to be a missionary myself and understand how overwhelming it can be.</p>
<p>Some people have pointed out why I don’t make DonorElf cheaper so I can help the missionaries out even more by not having them pay as much. And in the early days of working on DonorElf I was tempted to do this.</p>
<p>But I also realize if I don’t charge enough for DonorElf, then it’s not going to be worth my time, and as my life gets busier with a growing family, I would eventually stop working on it and abandon it. And it’s for this reason that I have no problem charging for DonorElf. I want DonorElf to be the best app for missionaries to help them raise support. And that means I need to charge so it is worth my time and so eventually I can go full time on it.</p>
<p>So I charge for DonorElf to make it the best app possible, and now to get to your question about how much of a ‘good living’ do I plan on making from DonorElf.</p>
<p>My first goal is to go full time on it, which I have no problem with. But after I am able to go full time and say it really takes off and I’m able to make a million a year on it. In that case I do plan to still charge for DonorElf and my plan is to have a set salary like you mentioned and give the extra money away. I’m actually already doing that since I’m currently working a full time job and have the income from DonorElf, we have extra money and give a lot away. And that makes it a lot of fun to work on DonorElf since we’re able to bless others.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462/5</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 20:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1462-5</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Paul, founder of DonorElf</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Paul, founder of DonorElf</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey Paul,</p>
<p>The site looks nice, and you’ve certainly found yourself a niche that you understand.</p>
<p>I’m intellectually curious about your view on making a good living from this site… Got a FAQ or feelings on this? Do you, for example, draw a capped income, and give the rest away?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462/4</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 13:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1462-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Paul, founder of DonorElf</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Paul, founder of DonorElf</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[paulyoder]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="2" data-topic="1462">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/gavin/40/1211_1.png" class="avatar"> gavin:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>How do you help your customers with their donor communication? Do you facilitate templates for print or emails?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>DonorElf lists the donors that the missionary should be communicating with. It’s up to the missionary to do the actual communication.</p>
<p>With that said, I do plan to add email newsletter integration with MailChimp and Constant Contact, which will make it easier to send emails out.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 02:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1462-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Paul, founder of DonorElf</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Paul, founder of DonorElf</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Very cool Paul. I’ll have to share this with some of my missionary friends.</p>
<p>I noticed your blog is all about support letters. How do you help your customers with their donor communication? Do you facilitate templates for print or emails?</p>
<p>Excited to hear more!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 00:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1462-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Paul, founder of DonorElf</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Paul, founder of DonorElf</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[paulyoder]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi everyone, I’m Paul Yoder.</p>
<p>I founded <a href="http://www.donorelf.com" rel="nofollow noopener">DonorElf</a> a little over 3 and a half years ago. It’s a SaaS product for missionaries who raise their own financial support to pay for their ministry and salary.</p>
<p>There’s a lot involved for missionaries to figure out which donors they need to be communicating with (e.g. send a thank you note to new donors, follow up with monthly donors that stopped giving, etc)</p>
<p>So DonorElf acts as a personal assistant for the missionary by analyzing their donations and letting the missionary know which donors they need to be communicating with.</p>
<p>I built it initially for my own benefit since I used to be with a missions organization and raised my own support. And it wasn’t long before others wanted to start using it, so I rewrote it so many organizations could use it, and that’s when I started bootstrapping DonorElf.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 21:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1462-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-founder-of-donorelf/1462.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Paul, founder of DonorElf</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
