<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Targeted tweets to people outside your followers</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/targeted-tweets-to-people-outside-your-followers/2064</link>
    <description>Curious, what do people think about tweeting to people purely based on searching twitter for terms. Spammy, slimey? I&#39;m thinking it&#39;s no worse than targeted ads. Possibly a useful way to get conversations going with prospects.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 18:30:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/targeted-tweets-to-people-outside-your-followers/2064.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Targeted tweets to people outside your followers</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[dgrigg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Agreed a generic or auto response would be spammy. I’m thinking more of finding those tweets where people are looking for help or a recommendation on a keyword that lines up with keywords I have identified. Once I have a some possible matches then replying individually. It’s sort of like people looking for answers on stackoberflow but not for technical things. It seems like Twitter is a place people can reach out for advice from the ‘public’</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/targeted-tweets-to-people-outside-your-followers/2064/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/targeted-tweets-to-people-outside-your-followers/2064/4</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 18:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2064-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/targeted-tweets-to-people-outside-your-followers/2064.rss">Targeted tweets to people outside your followers</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Targeted tweets to people outside your followers</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[perceptec]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I think a middle ground would involve first searching for terms, and then culling the results for tweets from users who directly ask for assistance, or at least seem receptive to feedback.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/targeted-tweets-to-people-outside-your-followers/2064/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/targeted-tweets-to-people-outside-your-followers/2064/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 16:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2064-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/targeted-tweets-to-people-outside-your-followers/2064.rss">Targeted tweets to people outside your followers</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Targeted tweets to people outside your followers</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[radiac]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I think it depends on the search terms you’re using, and your criteria for replying to the tweets.</p>
<p>On several occasions I’ve mentioned a topic in passing and had a sales tweet (or a sales follow), and I find it spammy and a bit creepy; it’s a negative experience, so I don’t think it’s a good way to introduce a company or product to a potential customer. Targetted ads are bad enough, but at least there the stalking and invasion of personal space is clearly done by a machine - it’s impersonal, the message doesn’t start with your name, and you accept that’s just part of the faustian deal you made when you signed up.</p>
<p>Of course, I think it’s a very different thing to watch for your company or product name, and answer questions or try to resolve complaints - but I think that’s because it comes under support rather than sales.</p>
<p>There is a grey area in between the two; for example, if you can directly answer a question and provide some sort of value to the potential customer (ie if your tweet is more than just “Buy this to solve that”), then you’re helping more than selling - I’ve seen some people do this without even mentioning their product. I have no idea how it would perform compared to more aggressive methods, but at least their first interaction with your company would be positive.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/targeted-tweets-to-people-outside-your-followers/2064/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/targeted-tweets-to-people-outside-your-followers/2064/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 07:42:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2064-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/targeted-tweets-to-people-outside-your-followers/2064.rss">Targeted tweets to people outside your followers</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Targeted tweets to people outside your followers</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[dgrigg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Curious, what do people think about tweeting to people purely based on searching twitter for terms. Spammy, slimey? I’m thinking it’s no worse than targeted ads. Possibly a useful way to get conversations going with prospects.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/targeted-tweets-to-people-outside-your-followers/2064/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/targeted-tweets-to-people-outside-your-followers/2064/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 22:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2064-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/targeted-tweets-to-people-outside-your-followers/2064.rss">Targeted tweets to people outside your followers</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
