<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>SMS greeting cards - Schedule SMS for important events</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/sms-greeting-cards-schedule-sms-for-important-events/7603</link>
    <description>I was thinking about how I usually forget about someone&#39;s bday or anniversary or such more important occasions. If there isn&#39;t for Facebook I wouldn&#39;t remember it all, unless I create a reminder on my phone.

How about a website or an app where people could order SMS greetings such as and subscribe to it annually.

For example:
- if my friend Anna has a birthday I would write personalised SMS which will be sent every year on her birthday.

- if I&#39;m a parent I might want to order some cool text from Santa Clause or some fictional character like Spiderman I can get it here and my kid will get that text message from fictional character

The problem here would be that the other person would get an SMS from unknown phone number.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 14:51:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Idea Pitches</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/sms-greeting-cards-schedule-sms-for-important-events/7603.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>SMS greeting cards - Schedule SMS for important events</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[SauvignonBlanc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I was thinking about how I usually forget about someone’s bday or anniversary or such more important occasions. If there isn’t for Facebook I wouldn’t remember it all, unless I create a reminder on my phone.</p>
<p>How about a website or an app where people could order SMS greetings such as and subscribe to it annually.</p>
<p>For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>if my friend Anna has a birthday I would write personalised SMS which will be sent every year on her birthday.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>if I’m a parent I might want to order some cool text from Santa Clause or some fictional character like Spiderman I can get it here and my kid will get that text message from fictional character</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The problem here would be that the other person would get an SMS from unknown phone number.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/sms-greeting-cards-schedule-sms-for-important-events/7603/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/sms-greeting-cards-schedule-sms-for-important-events/7603/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 14:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-7603-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/sms-greeting-cards-schedule-sms-for-important-events/7603.rss">SMS greeting cards - Schedule SMS for important events</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
