<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>The &quot;Windup&quot; Strategy</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-windup-strategy/6417</link>
    <description>@ian questions why we in the software industry feel the need to grow fast:

&gt; Why does your software company have to grow fast? 

&gt; Why is building fast assumed when discussing a new software company, regardless of if it&#39;s bootstrapped or VC backed?

&gt; Sure, the idea of not growing &quot;VC&quot; levels of fast has been baked into bootstrapping software companies from the start. But can we push it further?

Read the whole article here: https://thermostat.io/the-windup-strategy</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 03:48:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Interesting Links</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-windup-strategy/6417.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>The &quot;Windup&quot; Strategy</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[AndyDentPerth]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Do people outside the startup ecosystem really understand, or want, NPS?</p>
<p>I think Rahul’s series of questions seen in <a href="https://firstround.com/review/how-superhuman-built-an-engine-to-find-product-market-fit/">this article</a> make more sense. He repeated this presentation on stage at LAUNCH 2019 last month in Sydney. In particular, his process provides a guide for <strong>what to do about the numbers.</strong></p>
<p>NPS polls are annoying and becoming more frequent. I donated plasma yesterday (it’s a volunteer thing) and by evening had an NPS question about my experience!</p>
<p>I think they are becoming like any form of content marketing - the good being overwhelmed by the noise of frequent polling from every organisation you have touch with.</p>
<p>Back to Ian’s article, maybe this is a British/Australian idiom but “windup” here means either:</p>
<ol>
<li>You are closing down the business, “winding it up” like winding up a thread, or</li>
<li>A “Windup” is fooling someone for fun, like “pulling their leg”, telling them a “tall tale”.</li>
</ol>
<p>Is Windup some kind of US sporting analogy?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-windup-strategy/6417/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-windup-strategy/6417/4</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 03:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6417-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-windup-strategy/6417.rss">The &quot;Windup&quot; Strategy</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The &quot;Windup&quot; Strategy</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Yeah, I didn’t really get into the details of running an NPS survey software business in particular. I consider the license fee a relatively minor expense. They do maintain it pretty well so I’m not that worried about people using it who shouldn’t be. I suspect anyone building NPS survey tool who isn’t licensed gets contacted by them if they reach any sort of size.</p>
<p>I always try and do things by the book though and have been paying the license fee for a few years now even though we only recently started generating revenue.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-windup-strategy/6417/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-windup-strategy/6417/3</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 15:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6417-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-windup-strategy/6417.rss">The &quot;Windup&quot; Strategy</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The &quot;Windup&quot; Strategy</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[unboot]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/ian">@ian</a> 's approach is interesting. However he doesn’t write about one very important thing: In order to use the term NPS (trademarked), you need to pay a yearly fee of $2000 ($5000 from 2020). Only a couple of NPS providers (like <a href="http://thermostat.io">thermostat.io</a>) pay this fee, and many others don’t.<br>
So bootstrapping a NPS is expensive if you play by the rules. And pricewise, you can be undercut by the NPS services who don’t pay the license fee.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-windup-strategy/6417/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-windup-strategy/6417/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 14:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6417-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-windup-strategy/6417.rss">The &quot;Windup&quot; Strategy</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The &quot;Windup&quot; Strategy</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/ian">@ian</a> questions why we in the software industry feel the need to grow fast:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Why does your software company have to grow fast?</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Why is building fast assumed when discussing a new software company, regardless of if it’s bootstrapped or VC backed?</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Sure, the idea of not growing “VC” levels of fast has been baked into bootstrapping software companies from the start. But can we push it further?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Read the whole article here: <a href="https://thermostat.io/the-windup-strategy">https://thermostat.io/the-windup-strategy</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-windup-strategy/6417/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-windup-strategy/6417/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 18:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6417-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/the-windup-strategy/6417.rss">The &quot;Windup&quot; Strategy</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
