<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tool for gathering live feedback from my app?</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/tool-for-gathering-live-feedback-from-my-app/5904</link>
    <description>Hi guys,

I&#39;d like to have a tool that would allow something like [crisp](https://crisp.chat/en/), but for desktop apps. Namely, once I&#39;m online (me, the owner of the app), and there are users that are running my app, I would like them to see live feedback is available, and perhaps even start a conversation with them. 

I&#39;m using .net (C#) - is there something like this, or do I have to build it myself? :slight_smile:</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 08:05:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/tool-for-gathering-live-feedback-from-my-app/5904.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Tool for gathering live feedback from my app?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[photawe]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="2" data-topic="5904">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/kjk/40/3801_1.png" class="avatar"> kjk:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>You already have crisp on your website. I’m curious:</p>
<ul>
<li>how many times people used it so far?</li>
<li>did you get anything useful from those conversations (like an insight about your app that you didn’t already know)?</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p><strong>About crisp on the website</strong><br>
It’s clearly not heavily used. Kinda’ like 1 in 50-60 users will hit us up. The idea is to provide a meaningful experience even for mobile or for Mac users - if they want to ask us anything about the app before trying it.</p>
<p>Do note that you don’t need to be online all the time - when support is “offline”, people leave their email and you get notified, reply and they get notified.</p>
<p>What I really like about crisp is auto triggers - so that I can have some messages show up tweaked on the page the user is visiting.</p>
<p><strong>About what I want (on my desktop app)</strong><br>
About being disruptive - I totally agree about that. I’ve developed a tool about 10 years ago, and got swamped with customer requests over skype. However, this is very different. This tool - I only want to use it at the beginning - to gather feedback from early users.</p>
<p>The idea is to get the feedback while they’re using the app - so it’s even more meaningful. Clearly after the app gets more stable and I understand what/if I need to redesign stuff inside the app, I will remove this tool. Or, I can maybe have it so that I would appear online only for certain key users.</p>
<p>Even now, what I want is - to appear online only when I am at the computer.</p>
<p>Once the app is as intuitive as it should be, I will get back to an async method, as you suggest.<br>
(clearly, the app is insanely intuitive to me, but I’m insanely biased here <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:">)</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/tool-for-gathering-live-feedback-from-my-app/5904/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/tool-for-gathering-live-feedback-from-my-app/5904/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 08:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-5904-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/tool-for-gathering-live-feedback-from-my-app/5904.rss">Tool for gathering live feedback from my app?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tool for gathering live feedback from my app?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kjk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>You already have crisp on your website. I’m curious:</p>
<ul>
<li>how many times people used it so far?</li>
<li>did you get anything useful from those conversations (like an insight about your app that you didn’t already know)?</li>
</ul>
<p>Maybe you have a bigger team but as a solo person, I wouldn’t use a tool like this because:</p>
<ul>
<li>I’m not available for such chats; if they would happen often, they would be disruptive to other, more important work</li>
<li>maybe it’s just arrogance, but I usually have more ideas than time to implement them</li>
<li>and you have an additional wrinkle of being in an European time zone</li>
</ul>
<p>I’m not saying feedback from users is not important or that providing support is not important but I use async method for that i.e. I set up Discourse forum.</p>
<p>I did work at a company that used a service like crisp successfully but the context was different (the product was complex so there was a genuine reason to guide some people and they had a full-time support person during business hours).</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/tool-for-gathering-live-feedback-from-my-app/5904/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/tool-for-gathering-live-feedback-from-my-app/5904/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 21:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-5904-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/tool-for-gathering-live-feedback-from-my-app/5904.rss">Tool for gathering live feedback from my app?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tool for gathering live feedback from my app?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[photawe]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi guys,</p>
<p>I’d like to have a tool that would allow something like <a href="https://crisp.chat/en/" rel="nofollow noopener">crisp</a>, but for desktop apps. Namely, once I’m online (me, the owner of the app), and there are users that are running my app, I would like them to see live feedback is available, and perhaps even start a conversation with them.</p>
<p>I’m using .net (C#) - is there something like this, or do I have to build it myself? <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/tool-for-gathering-live-feedback-from-my-app/5904/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/tool-for-gathering-live-feedback-from-my-app/5904/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 09:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-5904-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/tool-for-gathering-live-feedback-from-my-app/5904.rss">Tool for gathering live feedback from my app?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
