<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521</link>
    <description>Greetings, fellow bootstrappers! I&#39;ve been building a product called [Snip][1] since January 2011. Snip lets hair stylists see their schedules from anywhere, and it does automatic appointment reminders to help cut down on time spent doing confirmation calls.

I have a modest 3 customers now, with a 4th in the process of getting (hopefully) on board. I did a lot of high-touch, in-person sales in the beginning and had some success with that, then I switched to online marketing and had some successes with that, and starting in October I&#39;m planning to switch back to the &quot;brute force&quot; of door-to-door sales because although it&#39;s not very scalable, I do know that it&#39;s effective. Once I have some profit from door-to-door sales I plan to reinvest that into better analytics, SEO tools, design, etc. and pick back up with the online marketing. I need 2 more salons (5 total) to be profitable.

I had a full-time job when I started building Snip, and then I got laid off, then I went freelance, then I got another job, and in October I&#39;m going freelance again. I&#39;ve found that it&#39;s easier to do sales when I&#39;m freelance because my schedule is then flexible enough to visit salons on the salon owners&#39; schedules. I have a wife and two kids, ages 4 months and 3 years, both boys.


  [1]: http://www.sniphq.com/</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 03:05:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[craigvn]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I also own a company that sells software to hair salons so know a lot about Jason’s pains in setting up <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> The main forum I would check out is <a href="http://www.salongeek.com" rel="nofollow noopener">www.salongeek.com</a>. There are quite a few threads on their from people asking about software. Reading that forum I would suggest that recommendations from other salon owners is considered highly as is price.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/14</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 03:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-521-14</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[FaisalSyed123]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="12" data-topic="521">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/jasonswett/40/2541_1.png" class="avatar"> jasonswett:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I don’t remember my reasoning at the time but my plan now is to do a little of everything each week. I frankly haven’t been doing canvassing and probably won’t again for a while. I might start again once I have some mail campaigns going. Talking face-to-face with prospects always helps me understand my customers’ motivations way better than anything on the computer could.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Do your potential customers hang out in the <em>online forums</em>? You can observe how they behave there and get a good idea about their pain points. That is just 1 way of doing it.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/13</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 23:26:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-521-13</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jasonswett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Wow. This post has gotten popular lately. First let me briefly summarize what’s happened since September 2013 when I posted this.</p>
<p>Instead of 3 customers I now have 6. I’m profitable now. All three of the new salons are local, and all three came from referrals. Two of the three required some sales work; one just jumped on board.</p>
<p>My sales and marketing plans are more sophisticated now. Instead of switching between canvassing and SEO, my plans include canvassing, SEO, PPC, direct mail, email marketing, cold calling and eventually more. Per marketing author Dan Kennedy’s advice, I plan to move all these channels forward simultaneously rather than execute on them serially.</p>
<p>It’s too early to tell yet how these marketing plans will work out since switching my marketing site from Rails to WordPress was a prerequisite to any kind of effective PPC, SEO or direct mail campaign, and it took me forever to build the site. But it’s up now and I’m excited to keep moving, and I’m about to get to the fun stuff: building opt-in pages and driving traffic to them.</p>
<p>And now I’ll attempt to respond to everyone…</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/lucyz">@lucyz</a> I acknowledge your Plivo sales pitch. <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/faisalsyed123">@FaisalSyed123</a> Good question. I don’t remember my reasoning at the time but my plan now is to do a little of everything each week. I frankly haven’t been doing canvassing and probably won’t again for a while. I might start again once I have some mail campaigns going. Talking face-to-face with prospects always helps me understand my customers’ motivations way better than anything on the computer could.</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/iammorton">@iammorton</a> Thanks. You’re totally right. Now that I switched my site from Rails to WP it will be a lot easier for me to add stuff like that, and it’s pretty high on the priority list as far as content goes.</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/tompowell">@tompowell</a> Yes, they’re pretty popular. I think I want to copy their level of professionalism design-wise but not their tactics. Their CTA should be above the fold, they should avoid using so many distracting photos and other visual embellishments…at least this is what I read in that book Landing Page Optimization.</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/tomlloyd">@tomlloyd</a> Thanks. I’m there, man!! And no need to be sorry. I’m aware there are dozens if not hundreds of competitors. I don’t believe the products that offer general scheduling but don’t focus exclusively on hair salons can really compete on my level. Hair salons have mind-blowingly unique and specific needs.</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/ckeck">@ckeck</a> You are very right! I’m planning to put some screenshots and videos as soon as I can. There are so many “top-priority” things. <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/12</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-521-12</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ckeck]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks for sharing Jason and best of luck – keep us posted.</p>
<p>One thing I wanted to mention regarding your website…get some screenshots up there! And better yet, a screencast/demo. The text is interesting…if people read it. A lot of great points about the value of the software, but you need to show it. It’s going to be hard to convert prospects to trial otherwise.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/11</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 04:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-521-11</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[tomlloyd]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Jason, best of luck with those final 2 to get you in profit, hope they come soon. Sorry to add to the growing list of competitors, but it’s good to see what others are doing I guess. I’ve seen these used regularly - <a href="http://www.gettimely.com" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.gettimely.com</a>. They seem to have some nice integrations like on this site (<a href="http://www.theblushbar.co.uk/book/" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.theblushbar.co.uk/book/</a>) which adds the whole booking interface onto their clients’ site.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/10</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 22:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-521-10</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[tompowell]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>These guys do a lot more than just scheduling but maybe you could get some ideas on marketing tactics and copy: <a href="http://www.salonbooker.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.salonbooker.com/</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/9</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 21:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-521-9</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[iammorton]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Jason.</p>
<p>Sounds like a very helpful idea for salons. Might be worthwhile to invest in more imagery on your product page. I find that imagery really helps less tech-savvy audiences understand your product better.</p>
<p>Good luck to you sir! Keep us updated on how Snip is doing.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/8</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 21:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-521-8</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[FaisalSyed123]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="521">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/jasonswett/40/2541_1.png" class="avatar"> jasonswett:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>then I switched to online marketing and had some successes with that, and starting in October I’m planning to switch back to the “brute force” of door-to-door sales because although it’s not very scalable,</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Hi Jason, why would you not continue with online marketing? Wouldn’t online marketing be much more effective and cost effective as opposed to “brute force”?<br>
Congratulations on your product!!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/7</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 19:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-521-7</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[lucyz]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Jason, how’s Snip? The best ideas are those that plug tech to solve an user problem. Have you heard of <a href="http://Plivo.com" rel="nofollow noopener">Plivo.com</a>? If you’re already trying out Twilio, you can easily make a few quick changes to the xml and use Plivo. It’s cheaper, more coverage, more features, and 24/7 tech support is free. Let me know if you have any questions. You can also check out our <a href="https://plivo.com/twilio-alternative/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://plivo.com/twilio-alternative/</a> page for the full comparison. Cheerio!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/6</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 19:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-521-6</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jasonswett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks, Ian. I believe you’re right on all counts. People have been asking a lot for text reminders in addition to email, so I plan to do a Twilio integration soon, and I definitely need a clear pricing page.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/5</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 14:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-521-5</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Looks pretty cool Jason. I think you should play up the money saving aspects of automated appointment reminders. It might also be interesting to add in phone reminders at some point also, since I imagine a fair number of a salon’s customers aren’t really email users or at least would prefer phone. Also, a salon probably has easier access to phone numbers than emails.</p>
<p>I also think having pricing someplace other than the free trial page would be good, people want to know what they’re getting into. Good luck!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/4</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 12:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-521-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jasonswett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks, Rob. I’d be interested to hear any challenges you’ve had with non-technical users. For me it pretty much means I become each customer’s IT department along with a Snip subscription (which is absolutely fine, just somewhat comical).</p>
<p>I am familiar with StyleSeat. I haven’t given much thought to tapping into their audience, but maybe I should. Thanks for the idea.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 03:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-521-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[rsobers]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Good luck, Jason.  I sympathize with you in that we’re both selling to non-technical audience that are used to doing things manually.</p>
<p>Have you heard of <a href="http://StyleSeat.com" rel="nofollow noopener">StyleSeat.com</a>?  They’re a popular venture-funded startup that does something very related: it helps you find and book beauty and wellness pros in your area.  I wonder if you could tap into their audience somehow, or at the very least see where they’re advertising via something like <a href="http://Mixrank.com" rel="nofollow noopener">Mixrank.com</a>.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 03:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-521-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jasonswett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Greetings, fellow bootstrappers! I’ve been building a product called <a href="http://www.sniphq.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">Snip</a> since January 2011. Snip lets hair stylists see their schedules from anywhere, and it does automatic appointment reminders to help cut down on time spent doing confirmation calls.</p>
<p>I have a modest 3 customers now, with a 4th in the process of getting (hopefully) on board. I did a lot of high-touch, in-person sales in the beginning and had some success with that, then I switched to online marketing and had some successes with that, and starting in October I’m planning to switch back to the “brute force” of door-to-door sales because although it’s not very scalable, I do know that it’s effective. Once I have some profit from door-to-door sales I plan to reinvest that into better analytics, SEO tools, design, etc. and pick back up with the online marketing. I need 2 more salons (5 total) to be profitable.</p>
<p>I had a full-time job when I started building Snip, and then I got laid off, then I went freelance, then I got another job, and in October I’m going freelance again. I’ve found that it’s easier to do sales when I’m freelance because my schedule is then flexible enough to visit salons on the salon owners’ schedules. I have a wife and two kids, ages 4 months and 3 years, both boys.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 02:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-521-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-jason-i-make-scheduling-software-for-hair-salons/521.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Jason. I make scheduling software for hair salons</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
