<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Pricing your SaaS in multiple prices and multiple currencies</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/pricing-your-saas-in-multiple-prices-and-multiple-currencies/6002</link>
    <description>Hello there!

As a company headquartered in the Netherlands, we had made the early conscious choice to price our [current Email Parsing SaaS](https://parseur.com) in euros. While that worked great with almost no complaint from overseas customers (most of them being from the US), we still wondered how our growth would look like if we would price our services in USDs. And why not, throw in some GBP prices there too for British customers (UK is our 3rd biggest market).

We developed an in-house tool to easily manage multi-currency plans for our Stripe account and localize our landing pages and marketing materials with minimal changes. We quite liked the result and thought maybe that would make a nice side project that other SaaS companies might be interested in as well!

**So we rolled out [Priceur.com](https://priceur.com/) that aims at creating and displaying multi-currency pricing a breeze for companies using Stripe.** This still an early MVP but we&#39;d love to hear some feedback from you guys. Especially if you ever considered going multi-currency (I remember seeing some conversations about this a while back on this forum).

Also, any comment on the perceived value for such product, marketing copy or feature would be awesome!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 15:06:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Show Bootstrapped</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/pricing-your-saas-in-multiple-prices-and-multiple-currencies/6002.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Pricing your SaaS in multiple prices and multiple currencies</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[SlyBridges]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello there!</p>
<p>As a company headquartered in the Netherlands, we had made the early conscious choice to price our <a href="https://parseur.com" rel="nofollow noopener">current Email Parsing SaaS</a> in euros. While that worked great with almost no complaint from overseas customers (most of them being from the US), we still wondered how our growth would look like if we would price our services in USDs. And why not, throw in some GBP prices there too for British customers (UK is our 3rd biggest market).</p>
<p>We developed an in-house tool to easily manage multi-currency plans for our Stripe account and localize our landing pages and marketing materials with minimal changes. We quite liked the result and thought maybe that would make a nice side project that other SaaS companies might be interested in as well!</p>
<p><strong>So we rolled out <a href="https://priceur.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">Priceur.com</a> that aims at creating and displaying multi-currency pricing a breeze for companies using Stripe.</strong> This still an early MVP but we’d love to hear some feedback from you guys. Especially if you ever considered going multi-currency (I remember seeing some conversations about this a while back on this forum).</p>
<p>Also, any comment on the perceived value for such product, marketing copy or feature would be awesome!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/pricing-your-saas-in-multiple-prices-and-multiple-currencies/6002/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/pricing-your-saas-in-multiple-prices-and-multiple-currencies/6002/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 15:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6002-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/pricing-your-saas-in-multiple-prices-and-multiple-currencies/6002.rss">Pricing your SaaS in multiple prices and multiple currencies</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
