<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Marco, working on hubdirector</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-marco-working-on-hubdirector/892</link>
    <description>Hi all,

as a few others who&#39;ve just posted I learnt about this forum on the recent HN thread and I&#39;m really looking forward to experience a forum similar to the old, beloved BoS.

I&#39;m currently working on [hubdirector][1] `&quot;Social Coding For Organizations Without The Pain&quot;` and/or `&quot;Bridging the gap between social coding and organizations&quot;` (of course I&#39;m still working on that tag line, I suspect social coding will disappear from it eventually).

Specifically I&#39;m in the customer discovery-customer validation loop. As of this week I&#39;m working on it full-time and about to bring on board a couple of friends. They will initially work in their spare time until such a time we will be able to either go all full-time, close shop or something in between :smile: I&#39;ve got a few ideas on how to manage equity split, I like the dynamic approach and decided to experiment with [Slicing Pie][2]. This will definitely go on our blog eventually ;-)

In parallel I&#39;m also working on our content marketing strategy and the other 100s of things that need doing.

Happy 2014 
Marco

 


  [1]: http://hubdirector.com/
  [2]: http://www.slicingpie.com/</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 19:41:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-marco-working-on-hubdirector/892.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Marco, working on hubdirector</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[abs]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Oliver!</p>
<p>I’m blessed with friends, acquaintances and previous clients who are my current target customers (this is also not my first business). I say my <em>“current”</em> target customers because you never know, that might change through the discovery process.</p>
<p>What are you working on?</p>
<p>Al the best<br>
Marco</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-marco-working-on-hubdirector/892/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-marco-working-on-hubdirector/892/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 19:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-892-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-marco-working-on-hubdirector/892.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Marco, working on hubdirector</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Marco, working on hubdirector</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Marco,</p>
<p>I’m new here too, and I will be going through that customer discovery/validation process for my second business very soon.</p>
<p>How are you going about finding potential customers and engaging with them? I have found twitter to be a good place to figure out who the influencers are in a given space. The influencer’s followers is a good list of potentially interested people.</p>
<p>Cheers and best of luck for 2014.</p>
<p>Olivier</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-marco-working-on-hubdirector/892/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-marco-working-on-hubdirector/892/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 19:27:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-892-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-marco-working-on-hubdirector/892.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Marco, working on hubdirector</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Marco, working on hubdirector</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[abs]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi all,</p>
<p>as a few others who’ve just posted I learnt about this forum on the recent HN thread and I’m really looking forward to experience a forum similar to the old, beloved BoS.</p>
<p>I’m currently working on <a href="http://hubdirector.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">hubdirector</a> <code>"Social Coding For Organizations Without The Pain"</code> and/or <code>"Bridging the gap between social coding and organizations"</code> (of course I’m still working on that tag line, I suspect social coding will disappear from it eventually).</p>
<p>Specifically I’m in the customer discovery-customer validation loop. As of this week I’m working on it full-time and about to bring on board a couple of friends. They will initially work in their spare time until such a time we will be able to either go all full-time, close shop or something in between <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"> I’ve got a few ideas on how to manage equity split, I like the dynamic approach and decided to experiment with <a href="http://www.slicingpie.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">Slicing Pie</a>. This will definitely go on our blog eventually <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
<p>In parallel I’m also working on our content marketing strategy and the other 100s of things that need doing.</p>
<p>Happy 2014<br>
Marco</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-marco-working-on-hubdirector/892/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-marco-working-on-hubdirector/892/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 14:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-892-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-marco-working-on-hubdirector/892.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Marco, working on hubdirector</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
