<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Elliott Bennett from Logic Media</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-elliott-bennett-from-logic-media/1218</link>
    <description>Hey everyone, I&#39;m Elliott. I have some specific questions about a new project, but I&#39;ll keep this just for the introduction.

My wife and I run [Logic Media][1], a website design and development shop in Louisville, Kentucky, USA. I&#39;ve been doing this for some 11 years, and it&#39;s going pretty good. 

But there&#39;s always been the itch to do something a bit more scaleable than selling hours. We had the idea about two years ago to create a flash sale e-commerce site, and recently launched [Ashford Fair][2]. This one isn&#39;t doing so good, but that&#39;s a topic for a different post.

Anyway, I&#39;m glad this community exists! It&#39;s already been a very helpful resource.

-Elliott


  [1]: http://www.logicmediazone.com
  [2]: http://www.ashfordfair.com</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 19:40:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-elliott-bennett-from-logic-media/1218.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Elliott Bennett from Logic Media</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[LogicMedia]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey everyone, I’m Elliott. I have some specific questions about a new project, but I’ll keep this just for the introduction.</p>
<p>My wife and I run <a href="http://www.logicmediazone.com" rel="nofollow noopener">Logic Media</a>, a website design and development shop in Louisville, Kentucky, USA. I’ve been doing this for some 11 years, and it’s going pretty good.</p>
<p>But there’s always been the itch to do something a bit more scaleable than selling hours. We had the idea about two years ago to create a flash sale e-commerce site, and recently launched <a href="http://www.ashfordfair.com" rel="nofollow noopener">Ashford Fair</a>. This one isn’t doing so good, but that’s a topic for a different post.</p>
<p>Anyway, I’m glad this community exists! It’s already been a very helpful resource.</p>
<p>-Elliott</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-elliott-bennett-from-logic-media/1218/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-elliott-bennett-from-logic-media/1218/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 19:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1218-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-elliott-bennett-from-logic-media/1218.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Elliott Bennett from Logic Media</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
