<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Introducing ConvertTalk</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-converttalk/4276</link>
    <description>Hello, my name is Paulo and I’m working on a SaaS product called ConvertTalk (www.converttalk.com).

ConvertTalk is a communication tool that aims to help e-commerce owners to drive more sales trough a conversational interface, and as you guys know, there&#39;s a plenty of big tools trying to solve this problem but I think our product is differentiated for being focused on the business side.

It’s a tool to convert client’s talks into sales for e-commerce owners. So we have our features focused on e-commerce, like:

* You can send products information to your clients, like attributes and photos, helping them to decide to buy.
* You can collect your customer’s data simply asking them for their name, email or physical addresses.
* You can create an order right on our tool and send it to your client review and pay.
* You can track you orders made through ConvertTalk.
* All your clients will receive automatic updates about theirs purchases.

All this in a mobile app connected to your store&#39;s API so you have the prices, products, orders, discount coupons, shipping tables, taxes, webhooks right on your hand helping you to convert a talk into a sale.

I decide to start connecting WooCommerce owners to Facebook Messenger, over time we have plans to connect others platforms and communication channels.

We’re almost finishing our product and I really appreciate some feedback about the idea and if you want to know more and participate in our private beta, please, sign up our launch list.

In a month I will start to send the first invites.

I really appreciate hearing any question of you guys!

And please visit our website https://www.converttalk.com

Thank you !
Paulo GR</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 21:06:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Show Bootstrapped</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-converttalk/4276.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Introducing ConvertTalk</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheez]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Love the idea. The key bit is integration with Woo Commerce which allows you to place the order on behalf of the customer. Anyone else doing it this way?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-converttalk/4276/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-converttalk/4276/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 21:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4276-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-converttalk/4276.rss">Introducing ConvertTalk</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Introducing ConvertTalk</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[paulogr]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello, my name is Paulo and I’m working on a SaaS product called ConvertTalk (<a href="http://www.converttalk.com" rel="nofollow noopener">www.converttalk.com</a>).</p>
<p>ConvertTalk is a communication tool that aims to help e-commerce owners to drive more sales trough a conversational interface, and as you guys know, there’s a plenty of big tools trying to solve this problem but I think our product is differentiated for being focused on the business side.</p>
<p>It’s a tool to convert client’s talks into sales for e-commerce owners. So we have our features focused on e-commerce, like:</p>
<ul>
<li>You can send products information to your clients, like attributes and photos, helping them to decide to buy.</li>
<li>You can collect your customer’s data simply asking them for their name, email or physical addresses.</li>
<li>You can create an order right on our tool and send it to your client review and pay.</li>
<li>You can track you orders made through ConvertTalk.</li>
<li>All your clients will receive automatic updates about theirs purchases.</li>
</ul>
<p>All this in a mobile app connected to your store’s API so you have the prices, products, orders, discount coupons, shipping tables, taxes, webhooks right on your hand helping you to convert a talk into a sale.</p>
<p>I decide to start connecting WooCommerce owners to Facebook Messenger, over time we have plans to connect others platforms and communication channels.</p>
<p>We’re almost finishing our product and I really appreciate some feedback about the idea and if you want to know more and participate in our private beta, please, sign up our launch list.</p>
<p>In a month I will start to send the first invites.</p>
<p>I really appreciate hearing any question of you guys!</p>
<p>And please visit our website <a href="https://www.converttalk.com" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.converttalk.com</a></p>
<p>Thank you !<br>
Paulo GR</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-converttalk/4276/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-converttalk/4276/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 13:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-4276-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-converttalk/4276.rss">Introducing ConvertTalk</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
