<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello, I&#39;m Noel McAvoy</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-noel-mcavoy/54</link>
    <description>Hi my name is Noel McAvoy and I currently work for the University of Connecticut (UConn) creating and maintaining reports for the College of Liberal Arts and Sciences as well as developing a web application to assist in the administration, monitoring, and forecasting of the college&#39;s finances. 

I&#39;m relatively new to the web application scene having previously built mostly basic websites for friends and very small local businesses. I recently became a member at tutsplus.com and started watching some of Jeffrey Way&#39;s courses on php web development with Laravel and immediately began rewriting everything in Laravel and haven&#39;t looked back since.

Now I&#39;m developing a new web application on the side in my free time. I&#39;m still in the planning phase but its just the beginning.
</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 03:00:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-noel-mcavoy/54.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hello, I&#39;m Noel McAvoy</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Awesome! Welcome aboard.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-noel-mcavoy/54/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-noel-mcavoy/54/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 03:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-54-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-noel-mcavoy/54.rss">Hello, I&#39;m Noel McAvoy</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hello, I&#39;m Noel McAvoy</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[noelmcavoy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi my name is Noel McAvoy and I currently work for the University of Connecticut (UConn) creating and maintaining reports for the College of Liberal Arts and Sciences as well as developing a web application to assist in the administration, monitoring, and forecasting of the college’s finances.</p>
<p>I’m relatively new to the web application scene having previously built mostly basic websites for friends and very small local businesses. I recently became a member at <a href="http://tutsplus.com" rel="nofollow noopener">tutsplus.com</a> and started watching some of Jeffrey Way’s courses on php web development with Laravel and immediately began rewriting everything in Laravel and haven’t looked back since.</p>
<p>Now I’m developing a new web application on the side in my free time. I’m still in the planning phase but its just the beginning.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-noel-mcavoy/54/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-noel-mcavoy/54/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 02:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-54-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-noel-mcavoy/54.rss">Hello, I&#39;m Noel McAvoy</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
