<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Paul, and I&#39;m learning about how to build products</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-and-im-learning-about-how-to-build-products/676</link>
    <description>Hi, I&#39;m Paul, I&#39;m a web developer from the small sliver of seacoast in New Hampshire (USA). I&#39;ve have been building side projects here and there to gauge my ability to launch a bootstrapped application.

Some of these side projects have received a bit of attention and I&#39;ve had the chance to write blog posts for both Twilio and Mailgun last year. Smashing Magazine retweeted one of my projects. I received job offers and emails and plenty of traffic which demonstrated the importance of  &quot;build stuff and tell people&quot;. (This may feel awkward at first, but a lot of folks are timid and afraid. If you show off your work and learn to ignore the trolls, you&#39;ll quickly stand out from the crowd)

A little less than a year ago, I wrote a blog post titled &quot;[What You Really Need Is A Market, Not An Idea][1]&quot; which struck a chord with the bootstrapper audience. It was the top post on HN for a day, I saw 15K visitors in &lt; 24hrs and I still get emails from people on the subject. It&#39;s become a great way to break in to the bootstrapper community and get to know some people.

I&#39;m currently building a [contract and invoice management tool][2] called Hourglass which is launching soon. Right now we have a blog that&#39;s seeing some traffic, a nice drip campaign/newsletter signup with &gt; 200 subscribers (and growing) and a recently launched ~50 page effort to test the waters of content generation (for long tail SEO purposes).

Looking forward to participating here and learning from those of you who&#39;ve successfully made the jump to full-time bootstrapper! 



  [1]: http://www.pfinn.net/markets-not-ideas-for-bootstrappers-founders.html
  [2]: http://www.gethourglass.com/ &quot;contract and invoice management&quot;</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 17:11:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-and-im-learning-about-how-to-build-products/676.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Paul, and I&#39;m learning about how to build products</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Ah, yeah perhaps not <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-and-im-learning-about-how-to-build-products/676/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-and-im-learning-about-how-to-build-products/676/4</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 17:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-676-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-and-im-learning-about-how-to-build-products/676.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Paul, and I&#39;m learning about how to build products</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Paul, and I&#39;m learning about how to build products</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pfinn]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks <a class="mention" href="/u/ian">@ian</a>.</p>
<p>NH seacoast is beautiful but it’s quickly becoming prohibitively expensive. Last months avg home sale price was just over $412K. (I rent). Not the best location for a bootstrappers budget <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-and-im-learning-about-how-to-build-products/676/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-and-im-learning-about-how-to-build-products/676/3</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 16:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-676-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-and-im-learning-about-how-to-build-products/676.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Paul, and I&#39;m learning about how to build products</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Paul, and I&#39;m learning about how to build products</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Awesome Paul, great to have you here! It sounds like you’re already well underway.</p>
<p>How do you like that area of NH? I’m always looking for interesting places to consider moving to (though it seems unlikely I ever actually will move)</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-and-im-learning-about-how-to-build-products/676/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-and-im-learning-about-how-to-build-products/676/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 16:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-676-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-and-im-learning-about-how-to-build-products/676.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Paul, and I&#39;m learning about how to build products</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Paul, and I&#39;m learning about how to build products</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pfinn]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi, I’m Paul, I’m a web developer from the small sliver of seacoast in New Hampshire (USA). I’ve have been building side projects here and there to gauge my ability to launch a bootstrapped application.</p>
<p>Some of these side projects have received a bit of attention and I’ve had the chance to write blog posts for both Twilio and Mailgun last year. Smashing Magazine retweeted one of my projects. I received job offers and emails and plenty of traffic which demonstrated the importance of  “build stuff and tell people”. (This may feel awkward at first, but a lot of folks are timid and afraid. If you show off your work and learn to ignore the trolls, you’ll quickly stand out from the crowd)</p>
<p>A little less than a year ago, I wrote a blog post titled “<a href="http://www.pfinn.net/markets-not-ideas-for-bootstrappers-founders.html" rel="nofollow noopener">What You Really Need Is A Market, Not An Idea</a>” which struck a chord with the bootstrapper audience. It was the top post on HN for a day, I saw 15K visitors in &lt; 24hrs and I still get emails from people on the subject. It’s become a great way to break in to the bootstrapper community and get to know some people.</p>
<p>I’m currently building a <a href="http://www.gethourglass.com/" title="contract and invoice management" rel="nofollow noopener">contract and invoice management tool</a> called Hourglass which is launching soon. Right now we have a blog that’s seeing some traffic, a nice drip campaign/newsletter signup with &gt; 200 subscribers (and growing) and a recently launched ~50 page effort to test the waters of content generation (for long tail SEO purposes).</p>
<p>Looking forward to participating here and learning from those of you who’ve successfully made the jump to full-time bootstrapper!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-and-im-learning-about-how-to-build-products/676/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-and-im-learning-about-how-to-build-products/676/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 14:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-676-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-paul-and-im-learning-about-how-to-build-products/676.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Paul, and I&#39;m learning about how to build products</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
