<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi! I&#39;m Reuven! I teach Python all over the world... and also online</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-reuven-i-teach-python-all-over-the-world-and-also-online/6553</link>
    <description>Hi, everyone!  I&#39;ve had my own consulting business since 1995, when I moved from the US to Israel. My business has gone through a few iterations, but for at least 10 years, I&#39;ve mainly been doing Python training.   

Most days, I&#39;m teaching Python on site to high tech companies; my repeat clients include Apple, Cisco, Ericsson, IBM, Intel, Western Digital and VMWare.    In the last year, I&#39;ve taught in the US, Europe, Israel, India, and China.

But I also have a growing online business, selling recorded Python courses and also a set of courses I call &quot;Weekly Python Exercise.&quot; Each WPE course (there are currently 6 different ones) involves getting a new problem on Tuesday and the solution on the following Monday, with a private forum and monthly office hours.  

I also have a weekly newsletter (&quot;Better Developers,&quot; with about 13k subscribers) with weekly 1500-word Python lessons, a much smaller newsletter (Trainer Weekly) about the business of training, and a YouTube channel where I frequently post Python tips.  I was, until it shut down last month, a monthly columnist for Linux Journal since 1996. And I continue to be a panelist on the Freelancers Show podcast, where we talk about... freelancing.

I continue to be amazed by the fact that I&#39;ve been in business for so long, and that things continue to go well -- we paid off our mortgage a few years ago, I&#39;m married with three kids, and we&#39;re doing OK.  But I&#39;m always looking for new ideas and techniques for growing my online business so that I can teach less in person and concentrate on creating new content and courses.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 19:12:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-reuven-i-teach-python-all-over-the-world-and-also-online/6553.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi! I&#39;m Reuven! I teach Python all over the world... and also online</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[unboot]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Reuven,<br>
Remember you from the ancient times when I read a Linux Journal in print.  Liked your articles very much!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-reuven-i-teach-python-all-over-the-world-and-also-online/6553/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-reuven-i-teach-python-all-over-the-world-and-also-online/6553/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 19:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6553-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-reuven-i-teach-python-all-over-the-world-and-also-online/6553.rss">Hi! I&#39;m Reuven! I teach Python all over the world... and also online</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi! I&#39;m Reuven! I teach Python all over the world... and also online</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[reuven]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi, everyone!  I’ve had my own consulting business since 1995, when I moved from the US to Israel. My business has gone through a few iterations, but for at least 10 years, I’ve mainly been doing Python training.</p>
<p>Most days, I’m teaching Python on site to high tech companies; my repeat clients include Apple, Cisco, Ericsson, IBM, Intel, Western Digital and VMWare.    In the last year, I’ve taught in the US, Europe, Israel, India, and China.</p>
<p>But I also have a growing online business, selling recorded Python courses and also a set of courses I call “Weekly Python Exercise.” Each WPE course (there are currently 6 different ones) involves getting a new problem on Tuesday and the solution on the following Monday, with a private forum and monthly office hours.</p>
<p>I also have a weekly newsletter (“Better Developers,” with about 13k subscribers) with weekly 1500-word Python lessons, a much smaller newsletter (Trainer Weekly) about the business of training, and a YouTube channel where I frequently post Python tips.  I was, until it shut down last month, a monthly columnist for Linux Journal since 1996. And I continue to be a panelist on the Freelancers Show podcast, where we talk about… freelancing.</p>
<p>I continue to be amazed by the fact that I’ve been in business for so long, and that things continue to go well – we paid off our mortgage a few years ago, I’m married with three kids, and we’re doing OK.  But I’m always looking for new ideas and techniques for growing my online business so that I can teach less in person and concentrate on creating new content and courses.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-reuven-i-teach-python-all-over-the-world-and-also-online/6553/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-reuven-i-teach-python-all-over-the-world-and-also-online/6553/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 16:48:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6553-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-reuven-i-teach-python-all-over-the-world-and-also-online/6553.rss">Hi! I&#39;m Reuven! I teach Python all over the world... and also online</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
