<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Trying an Ask Me Anything a la Holman</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/trying-an-ask-me-anything-a-la-holman/1383</link>
    <description>This isn&#39;t really a product show &amp; tell, rather a concept show &amp; tell.

A few weeks back I mentioned on Twitter that I was considering having weekly &quot;office hours&quot;. I&#39;d make myself available on a Google Hangout and people could come in and ask me questions about business, development, DNSimple, whatever. At least one response mentioned Zach Holman&#39;s feedback repository, which is basically a place where people can open Github issues and ask questions and Zach (or other people) can answer them.

I&#39;ve decided to give this a try myself, so I&#39;ve opened up [github.com/aeden/ama](http://github.com/aeden/ama). If you&#39;re interested feel free to drop in and ask a question and I&#39;ll do my best to answer. I&#39;ll post back here in a few weeks to let everyone know how this experiment goes.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 01:32:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Show Bootstrapped</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/trying-an-ask-me-anything-a-la-holman/1383.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Trying an Ask Me Anything a la Holman</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[aeden]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This isn’t really a product show &amp; tell, rather a concept show &amp; tell.</p>
<p>A few weeks back I mentioned on Twitter that I was considering having weekly “office hours”. I’d make myself available on a Google Hangout and people could come in and ask me questions about business, development, DNSimple, whatever. At least one response mentioned Zach Holman’s feedback repository, which is basically a place where people can open Github issues and ask questions and Zach (or other people) can answer them.</p>
<p>I’ve decided to give this a try myself, so I’ve opened up <a href="http://github.com/aeden/ama" rel="nofollow noopener">github.com/aeden/ama</a>. If you’re interested feel free to drop in and ask a question and I’ll do my best to answer. I’ll post back here in a few weeks to let everyone know how this experiment goes.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/trying-an-ask-me-anything-a-la-holman/1383/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/trying-an-ask-me-anything-a-la-holman/1383/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 19:24:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-1383-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/trying-an-ask-me-anything-a-la-holman/1383.rss">Trying an Ask Me Anything a la Holman</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
