<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Online mentoring</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/online-mentoring/2739</link>
    <description>I&#39;ve been thinking about the idea of online mentoring recently. I feel like I&#39;d like to maybe mentor developers or founders that are earlier on in their career. 

Also thinking about building a site of some sort to facilitate this. Did a bit of searching around online mentoring and there don&#39;t seem to be awesome options readily available. 

Of course there are forums like this where you can get advice. But I&#39;m imagining something a bit more direct / intentional. 

I&#39;ve heard a lot of people say that you should just reach out to people that you want to receive mentorship and advice from. But my hunch is that most people are probably a bit shy to do that. 

And sometimes you feel like you&#39;re imposing if you reach out. So I think it would be powerful for mentors to somehow indicate their availability / the types of things they&#39;re willing to help with. 

There are communities like fizzle that are amazing. Maybe they&#39;re already solving this problem. Not sure.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 02:34:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Discussions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/online-mentoring/2739.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Online mentoring</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’ve been thinking about the idea of online mentoring recently. I feel like I’d like to maybe mentor developers or founders that are earlier on in their career.</p>
<p>Also thinking about building a site of some sort to facilitate this. Did a bit of searching around online mentoring and there don’t seem to be awesome options readily available.</p>
<p>Of course there are forums like this where you can get advice. But I’m imagining something a bit more direct / intentional.</p>
<p>I’ve heard a lot of people say that you should just reach out to people that you want to receive mentorship and advice from. But my hunch is that most people are probably a bit shy to do that.</p>
<p>And sometimes you feel like you’re imposing if you reach out. So I think it would be powerful for mentors to somehow indicate their availability / the types of things they’re willing to help with.</p>
<p>There are communities like fizzle that are amazing. Maybe they’re already solving this problem. Not sure.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/online-mentoring/2739/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/online-mentoring/2739/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 02:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2739-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/online-mentoring/2739.rss">Online mentoring</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
