<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Introducing FormulaDesk</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662</link>
    <description>Hi Bootstrappers

I&#39;d like to introduce FormulaDesk [ www formuladesk com ] (sorry, I can&#39;t post a proper link due to forum rules) 

FormulaDesk is an Excel add-in that adds new capabilities to Excel to make working with formulas easier and quicker.

The current feature-set is aimed at beginner and intermediate Excel users, although I&#39;m sure that Excel experts will find it useful as well.

Pain it addresses:

 - Debugging complex/long formulas is quite difficult and time-consuming:
- *How is the final value calculated?* **FormulaDesk** shows the intermiate steps/values.
- *Tracking where an error occurs in a long/complex formula is difficult.* **FormulaDesk** shows the user exactly where the error is.
 - *Viewing the precedents/descendents of a cell is more time-consuming that it should be. To see their value, precedent cells must be navigated to, then navigated back from.* **FormulaDesk**  displays precedents in a live mode - just click other cells and it continually updates. It also displays a screenshot of cells as you hover over the arrow so you don&#39;t need to navigate there.
 - *Complex formulas can be easier to understand if broken into many sub-formulas. **FormulaDesk** will do this for you, and write to a new sheet.

Anyway, I&#39;d love to hear any suggestions/adivice/thoughts at all, but especially regarding marketing ideas, the product itself and the website.

Thanks so much!
Gareth.


  [1]: http://www.formuladesk.com
  [2]: http://www.formuladesk.com</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:46:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Show Bootstrapped</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Introducing FormulaDesk</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Gareth]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Josh. Thanks for reaching out to me. FormulaDesk is totally free at the moment - I’m just concentrating on growing the user-base and ironing out any bugs, improve performance etc. I do plan on releasing a ‘Pro’ version, or maybe even splitting it up into three or four smaller add-ins that are more targeted.</p>
<p>The best way to stay informed is to sign up to the newsletter, which I actually only use to send alerts when a new version is available. I’ll also use this to announce a Pro version, when it arrives.</p>
<p>When installed, FormulaDesk performs a silent update check once a day and informs you if there’s a newer version, however you obviously won’t see this alert if you uninstall it, or if you don’t open Excel for a few days. The best is still to subscribe to the newsletter.</p>
<p>You can subscribe on the download page: <a href="https://www.formuladesk.com/download" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.formuladesk.com/download</a></p>
<p>Please let me know how it goes, and if you have any suggestions or advice for improvements.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/8</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2662-8</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662.rss">Introducing FormulaDesk</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Introducing FormulaDesk</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Josh_Walker]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello, Gareth!</p>
<p>Just letting you know that your model is working to some degree, at least-- I have a particularly hairy workbook to unravel from a previous IT director, and a quick google search for “visualize excel formula” lead me to your utility. It looks excellent-- I’m about to use it. I was just doing a brief scan of the chatter to ensure it wasn’t a malware vector (seems pretty generous to give it out for free). If you do have a premium version, or when you roll one out, how do/will I get it?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/7</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 17:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2662-7</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662.rss">Introducing FormulaDesk</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Introducing FormulaDesk</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Gareth]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The installer doesn’t require admin privileges, and also isn’t an msi installer, so hopefully it should be able to be installed in more environments than most installers.</p>
<p>An idea I had for marketing is to make it a great tool for people answering questions on forums to take a screenshot of the ‘explanation view’ of a formula to include in their answers, and include a little watermark on the image with the website address. If that became well used, then more and more forums will start having ‘links’ to the website.</p>
<p>But yes, you are right, and my lack of good marketing ideas is what’s concerning me.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/6</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 00:12:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2662-6</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662.rss">Introducing FormulaDesk</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Introducing FormulaDesk</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhino]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="4" data-topic="2662">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/gareth/40/2547_1.png" class="avatar"> Gareth:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>why wouldn’t you install it?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Why? Because you can’t! Seriously, a lot of corporates will have their desktops locked down by Mordac (see dilbert).</p>
<p>re: Marketing - How will you get them interested in the free version initially?</p>
<p>My worry for you is that is that there is no obvious path where people will find this tool - what would they type into Google for example I would imagine its going to be a bazillion long tail terms. Outbound marketing also neigh on impossible (apart from perhaps advertising on Excel focused sites if there is  such a thing).</p>
<p>The Content Marketing play on this would be to produce a bunch of good content that would get inbound traffic that you can then shill your tool to - templates, cheat sheets, how to guides, “10 Excel ninja moves to make your job easier” etc.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/5</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 23:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2662-5</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662.rss">Introducing FormulaDesk</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Introducing FormulaDesk</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Gareth]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks Rhino and Dave</p>
<p>I’m planning on having a free version (limited features) and a pro version ($$). I’m going to be adding some features that will appeal to businesses. At that point I’ll launch the pro version. I’m hoping to grow the user-base via the free version, then promote the pro version to these free users at a later stage, with notifications and offers in the app itself, not via a mailing list, hence my desire to grow the user-base.</p>
<p>I’d like the free version to become a default install option for anyone using Excel ie: it adds so much value, and is free - why wouldn’t you install it?</p>
<p>Thoughts?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/4</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 18:52:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2662-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662.rss">Introducing FormulaDesk</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Introducing FormulaDesk</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Dave]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I really like this!</p>
<p>I can see that if you are a heavy Excel user (and there are lots of them) it could save you a lot of time and therefore be valuable to you.</p>
<p>Are you planning to keep it completely free?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/3</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 12:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2662-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662.rss">Introducing FormulaDesk</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Introducing FormulaDesk</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhino]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Link - <a href="http://www.formuladesk.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.formuladesk.com/</a></p>
<p>Nice idea for an add in and site does a good job of explaining what its about - no pricing though?</p>
<p>Whats your plan for marketing?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 09:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2662-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662.rss">Introducing FormulaDesk</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Introducing FormulaDesk</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Gareth]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Bootstrappers</p>
<p>I’d like to introduce FormulaDesk [ www formuladesk com ] (sorry, I can’t post a proper link due to forum rules)</p>
<p>FormulaDesk is an Excel add-in that adds new capabilities to Excel to make working with formulas easier and quicker.</p>
<p>The current feature-set is aimed at beginner and intermediate Excel users, although I’m sure that Excel experts will find it useful as well.</p>
<p>Pain it addresses:</p>
<ul>
<li>Debugging complex/long formulas is quite difficult and time-consuming:</li>
<li>
<em>How is the final value calculated?</em> <strong>FormulaDesk</strong> shows the intermiate steps/values.</li>
<li>
<em>Tracking where an error occurs in a long/complex formula is difficult.</em> <strong>FormulaDesk</strong> shows the user exactly where the error is.</li>
<li>
<em>Viewing the precedents/descendents of a cell is more time-consuming that it should be. To see their value, precedent cells must be navigated to, then navigated back from.</em> <strong>FormulaDesk</strong>  displays precedents in a live mode - just click other cells and it continually updates. It also displays a screenshot of cells as you hover over the arrow so you don’t need to navigate there.</li>
<li>*Complex formulas can be easier to understand if broken into many sub-formulas. <strong>FormulaDesk</strong> will do this for you, and write to a new sheet.</li>
</ul>
<p>Anyway, I’d love to hear any suggestions/adivice/thoughts at all, but especially regarding marketing ideas, the product itself and the website.</p>
<p>Thanks so much!<br>
Gareth.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 03:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2662-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-formuladesk/2662.rss">Introducing FormulaDesk</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
