<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Meredith – virtual assistants for busy business owners</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/meredith-virtual-assistants-for-busy-business-owners/3282</link>
    <description>Hi all,

I have recently unveiled my latest project, a virtual assistants service. I know a bunch of people that didn&#39;t get into business to spend all day doing bookkeeping and the like. I have a couple of people lined up (who are very good, very experienced assistants) ready to take on clients. I wanted to create a personal brand around someone that could care about your business as much as you do, and realise that we&#39;re helping you operate a business and if we do our job badly, then you might not do as well as you could and then we lose you as a client.

I don&#39;t want to say too much here, because that might give you extra info that I might&#39;ve missed on the site and then I won&#39;t get honest feedback! :) My main competitor is timeetc.co.uk – which is a £1.5 million turnover business, so I know the market is there and I know people are willing to pay for a UK based quality virtual assistant. Any thoughts and feedback will be greatly welcomed, and if you&#39;re in the market for a VA, shoot me an email hello@meredith.io – or tell me why my site doesn&#39;t fill you with confidence.


Thanks all.

[https://meredith.io][1]


  [1]: https://meredith.io</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 13:12:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Show Bootstrapped</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/meredith-virtual-assistants-for-busy-business-owners/3282.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Meredith – virtual assistants for busy business owners</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[uibreakfast]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/adam_griffiths">@adam_griffiths</a> The niche seems to be very promising for content marketing! Quality and authority seem to be the only natural way to differentiate yourself from a bunch of low-cost oDesk alternatives. You can branch off with guides (and even training) for other people’s assistants — this way you’ll be always <span class="hashtag">#1</span> go-to source.</p>
<p>Good example: Joanna Wiebe from <a href="http://copyhackers.com" rel="nofollow noopener">Copy Hackers</a> has <a href="http://snapcopy.co/" rel="nofollow noopener">Snap</a> blooming as a service, while providing training for all other writers in the world.</p>
<p>Does this make sense?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/meredith-virtual-assistants-for-busy-business-owners/3282/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/meredith-virtual-assistants-for-busy-business-owners/3282/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 13:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3282-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/meredith-virtual-assistants-for-busy-business-owners/3282.rss">Meredith – virtual assistants for busy business owners</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Meredith – virtual assistants for busy business owners</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[adam_griffiths]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi, thanks for the reply. I actually started with a much longer landing page that included price tiers for monthly packages and a list of example tasks we can carry out. I might switch back to that but also include the “Start now for £25” option for those not ready to invest a larger amount in a service until they can see the quality.</p>
<p>Also noted on the FAQ, I also had some client quotes on the original landing page. I shall reinstate it tonight with some additions.</p>
<p>Cheers.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/meredith-virtual-assistants-for-busy-business-owners/3282/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/meredith-virtual-assistants-for-busy-business-owners/3282/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 12:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3282-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/meredith-virtual-assistants-for-busy-business-owners/3282.rss">Meredith – virtual assistants for busy business owners</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Meredith – virtual assistants for busy business owners</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[shantnu]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>A few quick points:</p>
<p>A few case studies would be nice. You charge £25 for 1 hours work. Can that be anything? Accounting, phoning, typing? What are the charges after that one hour?</p>
<p>Your website is a bit too sparse. While it’s good to have simple, clean websites, you can go in the other extreme and have  it so simple it doesn’t explain anything.</p>
<p>At the minimum, you need a pricing page (with everything <strong>clearly</strong> explained),  case studies and a FAQ.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/meredith-virtual-assistants-for-busy-business-owners/3282/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/meredith-virtual-assistants-for-busy-business-owners/3282/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 09:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3282-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/meredith-virtual-assistants-for-busy-business-owners/3282.rss">Meredith – virtual assistants for busy business owners</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Meredith – virtual assistants for busy business owners</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[adam_griffiths]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi all,</p>
<p>I have recently unveiled my latest project, a virtual assistants service. I know a bunch of people that didn’t get into business to spend all day doing bookkeeping and the like. I have a couple of people lined up (who are very good, very experienced assistants) ready to take on clients. I wanted to create a personal brand around someone that could care about your business as much as you do, and realise that we’re helping you operate a business and if we do our job badly, then you might not do as well as you could and then we lose you as a client.</p>
<p>I don’t want to say too much here, because that might give you extra info that I might’ve missed on the site and then I won’t get honest feedback! <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> My main competitor is <a href="http://timeetc.co.uk" rel="nofollow noopener">timeetc.co.uk</a> – which is a £1.5 million turnover business, so I know the market is there and I know people are willing to pay for a UK based quality virtual assistant. Any thoughts and feedback will be greatly welcomed, and if you’re in the market for a VA, shoot me an email <a href="mailto:hello@meredith.io">hello@meredith.io</a> – or tell me why my site doesn’t fill you with confidence.</p>
<p>Thanks all.</p>
<p><a href="https://meredith.io" rel="nofollow noopener">https://meredith.io</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/meredith-virtual-assistants-for-busy-business-owners/3282/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/meredith-virtual-assistants-for-busy-business-owners/3282/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 19:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3282-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/meredith-virtual-assistants-for-busy-business-owners/3282.rss">Meredith – virtual assistants for busy business owners</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
