<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Greetings from Atlanta!</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/greetings-from-atlanta/6292</link>
    <description>Hi everyone,

My name is Aleksandr (aka Alexander or 亚历山大 in Chinese; but usually I go by Aleks or Alex). :-) As you likely have figured out already, I currently live and work in sunny Atlanta, Georgia. Originally from Eastern Europe, I have been living in US for almost 20 years.

I&#39;m happy to join this community. I&#39;m a seasoned IT professional (but have a wide range of interests) and have had a number of startup ideas for a while (haven&#39;t had a chance to work on them for various reasons). The most recent and most serious idea that I&#39;ve been working on is science-focused (still in the planning phase) - that&#39;s all I can say for now. While (and, actually, **because**) I&#39;m quite well familiar with the VC ecosystem, I plan to grow my startup organically, in a bootstrap fashion (at least, for as long as possible). I look forward to sharing my knowledge and insights as well as learning from people in this nice community.

Best wishes,
Aleks</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 10:14:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/greetings-from-atlanta/6292.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Greetings from Atlanta!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ablekh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I appreciate your welcome, Steve! And thank you for letting me know about the Arabic version of my name - that’s interesting, I was unaware of that … Languages and cultures are fascinating topics.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/greetings-from-atlanta/6292/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/greetings-from-atlanta/6292/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 10:14:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6292-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/greetings-from-atlanta/6292.rss">Greetings from Atlanta!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Greetings from Atlanta!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Welcome Aleksander/Alexander/亚历山大!</p>
<p>When I spent some time in Arabic-speaking countries, I noticed Alexander had turned into “Iskandar”. I guess it is because the “Al” sounds like the definite article in Arabic.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/greetings-from-atlanta/6292/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/greetings-from-atlanta/6292/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 09:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6292-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/greetings-from-atlanta/6292.rss">Greetings from Atlanta!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Greetings from Atlanta!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ablekh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi everyone,</p>
<p>My name is Aleksandr (aka Alexander or 亚历山大 in Chinese; but usually I go by Aleks or Alex). <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=6" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> As you likely have figured out already, I currently live and work in sunny Atlanta, Georgia. Originally from Eastern Europe, I have been living in US for almost 20 years.</p>
<p>I’m happy to join this community. I’m a seasoned IT professional (but have a wide range of interests) and have had a number of startup ideas for a while (haven’t had a chance to work on them for various reasons). The most recent and most serious idea that I’ve been working on is science-focused (still in the planning phase) - that’s all I can say for now. While (and, actually, <strong>because</strong>) I’m quite well familiar with the VC ecosystem, I plan to grow my startup organically, in a bootstrap fashion (at least, for as long as possible). I look forward to sharing my knowledge and insights as well as learning from people in this nice community.</p>
<p>Best wishes,<br>
Aleks</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/greetings-from-atlanta/6292/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/greetings-from-atlanta/6292/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 23:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-6292-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/greetings-from-atlanta/6292.rss">Greetings from Atlanta!</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
