<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello, I&#39;m Charlie</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627</link>
    <description>Hi All,
I&#39;ve posted a few questions on here but not introduced myself, so it&#39;s time to fix that.

I&#39;m Charlie, a freelancer from sunny Wales in the UK, been out on my own for about a year now, which financially can be hard especially when your trying to support a family with 2 kids, but the benefits far outweigh the downsides. 

Alongside client work, I have got a few games in both the Android and IOS app stores, but the mobile space is getting much harder since the big boys have moved in. My stuff is largely based on ad revenue and the advertisers just aren&#39;t paying much any more and I don&#39;t earn much from sales or IAP. They still earn around $500/month, but this is down from over $2k. So I&#39;ve decided to try my hand at a SAAS app and see if I can grow something into a real business. I have loads of abandoned projects on my harddrive so I&#39;ve decided to pick one of them and get it finished and go from there, at the moment I&#39;m keeping quiet about what it is, but lets just say that there aren&#39;t too many similar products in the space and the ones that are appear to be lucrative. 

But like everyone else, the coding isn&#39;t the problem, although security needs to be super tight on my project, so that&#39;s worrying, but the marketing is going to be the real tough bit.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 12:52:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hello, I&#39;m Charlie</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Heh, we’re working on it <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"> it’s amazing how much time they take to do!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627/5</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 12:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-627-5</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627.rss">Hello, I&#39;m Charlie</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hello, I&#39;m Charlie</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Charlie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks Ian, it’s a good thing you’ve got going here. It’s about time you had another Podcast out though <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627/4</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 09:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-627-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627.rss">Hello, I&#39;m Charlie</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hello, I&#39;m Charlie</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Welcome Charlie, great to have you on board.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627/3</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 00:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-627-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627.rss">Hello, I&#39;m Charlie</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hello, I&#39;m Charlie</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[najafali]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Charlie!</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="627">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/charlie/40/1357_1.png" class="avatar"> Charlie:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>although security needs to be super tight on my project</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Not a pentester, but if it’s a programming language/framework that I understand then I’d be happy to give your codebase a quick once over. Not promising that I’ll catch any vulnerabilities but an extra pair of eyes can’t hurt.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="627">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/charlie/40/1357_1.png" class="avatar"> Charlie:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>but the marketing is going to be the real tough bit</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Yep! I have a simple rule: if I haven’t been paid for a bit of software (pre-order) by a real customer, I don’t start work on coding it. This forces me to go out and actually sell things before building them.</p>
<p>Good hunting!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 10:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-627-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627.rss">Hello, I&#39;m Charlie</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hello, I&#39;m Charlie</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Charlie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi All,<br>
I’ve posted a few questions on here but not introduced myself, so it’s time to fix that.</p>
<p>I’m Charlie, a freelancer from sunny Wales in the UK, been out on my own for about a year now, which financially can be hard especially when your trying to support a family with 2 kids, but the benefits far outweigh the downsides.</p>
<p>Alongside client work, I have got a few games in both the Android and IOS app stores, but the mobile space is getting much harder since the big boys have moved in. My stuff is largely based on ad revenue and the advertisers just aren’t paying much any more and I don’t earn much from sales or IAP. They still earn around $500/month, but this is down from over $2k. So I’ve decided to try my hand at a SAAS app and see if I can grow something into a real business. I have loads of abandoned projects on my harddrive so I’ve decided to pick one of them and get it finished and go from there, at the moment I’m keeping quiet about what it is, but lets just say that there aren’t too many similar products in the space and the ones that are appear to be lucrative.</p>
<p>But like everyone else, the coding isn’t the problem, although security needs to be super tight on my project, so that’s worrying, but the marketing is going to be the real tough bit.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 09:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-627-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hello-im-charlie/627.rss">Hello, I&#39;m Charlie</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
