<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hey, I&#39;m starting a lean hacker school at my university called 0xA</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-starting-a-lean-hacker-school-at-my-university-called-0xa/2056</link>
    <description>I&#39;m starting a school to help students learn better CS concepts and try to gain momentum to start a full blown alternative to university here. My goal is to take my fellow students much better programmers and hopefully help make my area have better programmers. 

I&#39;m using a lean approach: For now I&#39;m just tutoring using this brand and will eventually offer workshops. If those are successful, I&#39;ll try to create a course or two and build from there.

I created a landing page at https://oxa.cmp.is, and I&#39;m having people sign up for the mailing list (sign up if you want, but unless you go to FAU I&#39;d prefer you didn&#39;t. I won&#39;t prevent/remove you though) to figure out if people want to do the workshops.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 19:54:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-starting-a-lean-hacker-school-at-my-university-called-0xa/2056.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hey, I&#39;m starting a lean hacker school at my university called 0xA</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[CMPDEV]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m starting a school to help students learn better CS concepts and try to gain momentum to start a full blown alternative to university here. My goal is to take my fellow students much better programmers and hopefully help make my area have better programmers.</p>
<p>I’m using a lean approach: For now I’m just tutoring using this brand and will eventually offer workshops. If those are successful, I’ll try to create a course or two and build from there.</p>
<p>I created a landing page at <a href="https://oxa.cmp.is" rel="nofollow noopener">https://oxa.cmp.is</a>, and I’m having people sign up for the mailing list (sign up if you want, but unless you go to FAU I’d prefer you didn’t. I won’t prevent/remove you though) to figure out if people want to do the workshops.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-starting-a-lean-hacker-school-at-my-university-called-0xa/2056/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-starting-a-lean-hacker-school-at-my-university-called-0xa/2056/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 19:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2056-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-starting-a-lean-hacker-school-at-my-university-called-0xa/2056.rss">Hey, I&#39;m starting a lean hacker school at my university called 0xA</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
