<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Teardown my new product site &quot;WP Offload S3&quot;</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/teardown-my-new-product-site-wp-offload-s3/3422</link>
    <description>Hey folks,

We just soft launched our 2nd product yesterday along with the new site. I&#39;m looking for feedback and tips on specific things I could add, remove, or change to increase conversions. So, if you could take a look and post your feedback, that would be awesome. I&#39;ll be A/B testing any changes I make and can share the results here. I&#39;m mostly interested in feedback on the following two pages:

* [Features](https://deliciousbrains.com/wp-offload-s3/)
* [Pricing](https://deliciousbrains.com/wp-offload-s3/pricing/)

If you have any comments on our pricing as well, I&#39;m happy to receive it.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 17:39:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Show Bootstrapped</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/teardown-my-new-product-site-wp-offload-s3/3422.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Teardown my new product site &quot;WP Offload S3&quot;</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[daverodenbaugh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Congrats on the launch!</p>
<p>Couple of weird things I noticed.</p>
<p>On the Features page–your speed vs. abandonment rate graph looks off.  There’s just no way that a page load time of 3 milliseconds suddenly has a 50% abandonment rate, but your text talks about the Akamai study for 3 seconds.  You’ll want to fix that graph image to use the right units.  <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
<p>On the Pricing page, 5 plans feels like a lot to process there, especially with the different sizes of each fee plan column.  I kept scanning my eyes back and forth across the plans trying to compare them in a meaningful way–the sizing of the Bronze and Silver vs. the rest makes the overall effect hard to read.  Maybe convert that to a table format instead?  One single table, features listed on the left, plan names across the top, checkmarks in the middle for each plan, a Buy Now at the bottom for each?  That seems more reader-friendly.</p>
<p>Hope the launch rolls in a bunch of new sales!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/teardown-my-new-product-site-wp-offload-s3/3422/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/teardown-my-new-product-site-wp-offload-s3/3422/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 17:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3422-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/teardown-my-new-product-site-wp-offload-s3/3422.rss">Teardown my new product site &quot;WP Offload S3&quot;</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Teardown my new product site &quot;WP Offload S3&quot;</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[bradt]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey folks,</p>
<p>We just soft launched our 2nd product yesterday along with the new site. I’m looking for feedback and tips on specific things I could add, remove, or change to increase conversions. So, if you could take a look and post your feedback, that would be awesome. I’ll be A/B testing any changes I make and can share the results here. I’m mostly interested in feedback on the following two pages:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://deliciousbrains.com/wp-offload-s3/" rel="nofollow noopener">Features</a></li>
<li><a href="https://deliciousbrains.com/wp-offload-s3/pricing/" rel="nofollow noopener">Pricing</a></li>
</ul>
<p>If you have any comments on our pricing as well, I’m happy to receive it.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/teardown-my-new-product-site-wp-offload-s3/3422/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/teardown-my-new-product-site-wp-offload-s3/3422/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 15:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3422-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/teardown-my-new-product-site-wp-offload-s3/3422.rss">Teardown my new product site &quot;WP Offload S3&quot;</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
