<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>New free course on UI/UX strategy</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/new-free-course-on-ui-ux-strategy/3757</link>
    <description>My dear bootstrapped friends,

I&#39;m thrilled to introduce a new free course for SaaS founders called [The 1-Hour UI Audit.](http://uibreakfast.com/1hour/) I announced it at MicroConf Europe in Barcelona, collected plenty of sign-ups, then a lot of life happened, and now it&#39;s finally live.

The course (and [the whole book](http://uibreakfast.com/audit)) is hugely inspired by discussions here. Particularly I realized the fact that design is never a priority, and the best path to change is to make small functional improvements.

As this course is very applicable to most of you, I&#39;d love to hear your opinion. What would you like to further learn in the book? What is your biggest trouble when it comes to UI design of your product?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 12:49:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Show Bootstrapped</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/new-free-course-on-ui-ux-strategy/3757.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>New free course on UI/UX strategy</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[uibreakfast]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>My dear bootstrapped friends,</p>
<p>I’m thrilled to introduce a new free course for SaaS founders called <a href="http://uibreakfast.com/1hour/" rel="nofollow noopener">The 1-Hour UI Audit.</a> I announced it at MicroConf Europe in Barcelona, collected plenty of sign-ups, then a lot of life happened, and now it’s finally live.</p>
<p>The course (and <a href="http://uibreakfast.com/audit" rel="nofollow noopener">the whole book</a>) is hugely inspired by discussions here. Particularly I realized the fact that design is never a priority, and the best path to change is to make small functional improvements.</p>
<p>As this course is very applicable to most of you, I’d love to hear your opinion. What would you like to further learn in the book? What is your biggest trouble when it comes to UI design of your product?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/new-free-course-on-ui-ux-strategy/3757/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/new-free-course-on-ui-ux-strategy/3757/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 12:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3757-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/new-free-course-on-ui-ux-strategy/3757.rss">New free course on UI/UX strategy</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
