<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hey, I&#39;m Ben from ExposureHQ</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-ben-from-exposurehq/433</link>
    <description>Hello, I&#39;m Ben. I have been trying to create a startup for years but never really had enough follow-through to finish it. I was on the BOS forums back when they were popular and got lots of great ideas. I finally had an epiphany and have been working on my product for the last six months in the evenings and weekends when I am not at my day job.

My product came from my wife&#39;s recent job change. She decided to quit her profession and start a photography business. Since I had the business knowledge it was easy for her to focus on what she loved while I did the back-end work. That works great for her but when I started looking around for tools to help her run the business herself, I noticed that there were plenty of individual tools that could accomplish much more than she needed but nothing integrated. So my product, [ExposureHQ][1], is designed for photography businesses and lets them keep client info, scheduling, sales, web, social media and finances all in one integrated application with lots of automation.

I figure I am about half done with the core features and I plan to launch a beta later in the fall and the full product sometime early next year.


  [1]: http://www.exposurehq.com/</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 18:19:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-ben-from-exposurehq/433.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hey, I&#39;m Ben from ExposureHQ</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Interesting niche, I dig it. Welcome!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-ben-from-exposurehq/433/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-ben-from-exposurehq/433/3</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 18:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-433-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-ben-from-exposurehq/433.rss">Hey, I&#39;m Ben from ExposureHQ</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hey, I&#39;m Ben from ExposureHQ</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[andrey]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello Ben. Welcome to the forums.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-ben-from-exposurehq/433/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-ben-from-exposurehq/433/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 14:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-433-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-ben-from-exposurehq/433.rss">Hey, I&#39;m Ben from ExposureHQ</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hey, I&#39;m Ben from ExposureHQ</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[benk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello, I’m Ben. I have been trying to create a startup for years but never really had enough follow-through to finish it. I was on the BOS forums back when they were popular and got lots of great ideas. I finally had an epiphany and have been working on my product for the last six months in the evenings and weekends when I am not at my day job.</p>
<p>My product came from my wife’s recent job change. She decided to quit her profession and start a photography business. Since I had the business knowledge it was easy for her to focus on what she loved while I did the back-end work. That works great for her but when I started looking around for tools to help her run the business herself, I noticed that there were plenty of individual tools that could accomplish much more than she needed but nothing integrated. So my product, <a href="http://www.exposurehq.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">ExposureHQ</a>, is designed for photography businesses and lets them keep client info, scheduling, sales, web, social media and finances all in one integrated application with lots of automation.</p>
<p>I figure I am about half done with the core features and I plan to launch a beta later in the fall and the full product sometime early next year.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-ben-from-exposurehq/433/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-ben-from-exposurehq/433/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 12:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-433-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-ben-from-exposurehq/433.rss">Hey, I&#39;m Ben from ExposureHQ</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
