<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944</link>
    <description>What do you think of very crowded markets... like... Dating Sites.... lol 

Told you it was stupid... but:

I am an older single person ... have used everything out there ... they all suck... now, I wonder if one that sucked less and was more modern (not the traditional structure) would get enough critical mass to be viable... hopefully without faking memberships in the beginning like all of them do... 

The level if dissatisfaction in those sites is real... I would say 90% of users are dissapointed with their results... That is a real problem to solve... no one has the right answer yet, and I know why... but it is a very big market... 

Wonder if it is worth my time...</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 07:30:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Idea Pitches</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[samh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Well that’s that sorted then.</p>
<p>If Buggy is against it it’s a sure thing that someone will make over a billion from it in the next 18 months.</p>
<p><img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/27</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 07:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-27</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[buggy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>There are already apps trying to make it easier for older people to find companions. One example is <a href="http://www.stitch.net/" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.stitch.net/</a> that received over $1 million in funding (they’re at the co-working space I work from). I’m not saying it can’t be done as a bootstrapped business but you really need to find something that everyone wants and that only you do. Also, unless you have a lot of friends looking for someone I think you’re going to struggle to create a market.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/26</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 23:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-26</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[PhilS]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="21" data-topic="3944">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/craigvn/40/2889_1.png" class="avatar"> craigvn:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I do agree dating sites are mostly made from the perspective of men though.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>You are probably right. There was an interesting article on BBC recently about a woman starting a lesbian dating app. It’s interesting because it sheds some light on the female perspective and it contains some bootstrapping stuff on getting a dating app off the ground. Here it is:<br>
<a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-36202226" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.bbc.com/news/business-36202226</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/25</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 08:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-25</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[samh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Serge,</p>
<p>I am on board with your thinking.</p>
<p>Yes there’s a lot of competition and yes it’s a market place that only works when you have a critical mass of people using it but boy oh boy if you could create something that worked significantly better than the existing sites and you got that critical mass you would have a monster on your hands.</p>
<p>Some thoughts :</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Does it have to explicitly be a dating site ?</strong> In real life checking out potential romantic interests usually happen in a group context with no explicit acknowledgement that that’s what’s happening. Could the site superficially come across as something else providing plausible deniability even if everyone knows what the deal is.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In order to get started could you <strong>target a specific geographic location and a specific segment of people who have particular selection criteria</strong>. I think some research and thought could come up with an under served group but the first ones that come to mind are already being served eg. vegetarians, specific religious, political and philosophical groups.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is there a way to make it <strong>more group oriented</strong>, so you don’t match couples you match dinner groups and people can join as a group. So a woman and her 2 friends can join and be matched with 2 guys and they all go to dinner. <strong>Safety is an issue for women in way that we men don’t understand</strong>. Making it a group activity where a woman brings her friends might be significant.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I think <strong>older women are an interesting market for dating sites</strong>. I’m 37 but I know 5 women between 50-65 who are looking for a man. A technology that really engages them might look quite different to what dating sites currently look like.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>More and more older people are <strong>playing games</strong> on their phones and computers. Could it be a <strong>role playing game that extends out into real life meet ups and dating</strong>. What about letting users create a parallel fake/fantasy profile to go along with their real profile, people communicate much more freely when ‘playing a chracter’. One of the over 50 women I know who is looking plays Clash of Clans on her phone. If there was some game that also gave her the chance of getting a date I think she would try it.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I think there are some deep psychological insights about human mating that could allow great innovation here, not sure exactly what they are though <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>Thanks</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/24</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 01:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-24</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ken]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="22" data-topic="3944">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/rwillmer/40/1302_1.png" class="avatar"> rwillmer:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>There’s 2 problems with the dating agency idea where the end-goal is finding a life-partner:</p>
<ol>
<li>It’s a 2-sided marketplace (generally recognised as a Really Hard Business Model)</li>
</ol>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>First, yes, a marketplace is really tough to approach as a bootstrapper. And, not especially appealing for investors.</p>
<p>As a personal example, with <a href="https://MastermindJam.com" rel="nofollow noopener">https://MastermindJam.com</a> I effectively run a dating site.</p>
<p>…</p>
<p>For polygamists.</p>
<p>…<br>
…<br>
.</p>
<p>Let me explain.</p>
<p>I set four strangers up on what amounts to a blind date into a peer-driven business mastermind group.</p>
<p>Much like eHarmony, I use around 30 points of data to make the best possible match that can be made with the candidates on hand.</p>
<p>Thus, the network effect, marketplace problem. These matching algorithms work fantastic when you’re dealing with a large number of signups, but everything falls apart with a slow traffic month.</p>
<p>I might say that MastermindJam has a problem that’s even more onerous than the one facing a dating site that matches people 1:1. I’m matching 4 people into groups. If one of these groups has a jerk in the mix, then the other three members walk away feeling they didn’t get their money’s worth and have a negative opinion of the service—for something that I have no control over.</p>
<p><em>(Because there’s just no good way to ask people in a questionnaire if they’re an asshat or not. Trust me, I’ve tried.)</em></p>
<p>So yeah, I can attest that bootstrapping a marketplace (or any business relying on network effect or matching humans with one another) is really, really difficult.</p>
<p>On to Rachel’s second point…</p>
<p>[quote=“rwillmer, post:22, topic:3944”]2) When you achieve Customer Success, your revenue stops (usually you’d expect more money at this point)<br>
[/quote]</p>
<p>I don’t agree. I mean, yeah, this <em>does</em> happen, but it doesn’t <em>have</em> to happen.</p>
<p>A great counterexample of Rachel’s assertion would be the wedding-centric website <a href="https://www.theknot.com" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.theknot.com</a></p>
<p><strong>The Knot</strong> helps you plan literally every aspect of your wedding. Seating charts, picking out groomsman outfits, invitations… everything!</p>
<p>And you’d think they lose a customer at the passing of every wedding date.</p>
<p>But not so.</p>
<p>After your wedding date, a clever sequence transitions you to their other properties:</p>
<p><strong>The Nest</strong> <a href="https://www.thenest.com" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.thenest.com</a> helps the newlyweds build a happy life together with advice, content, products, and services on housing, furnishings, cooking, budgeting, pets, and travel.</p>
<p><strong>The Bump</strong> <a href="http://www.thebump.com" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.thebump.com</a> Yes, you guessed it. After you’re married, you’ve got the perfect home and personal life, many of The Knot customers will find baby advice useful at The Bump where they provide products and content around getting pregnant, fertility, pregnancy, newborns, infants, toddlers, kids, schooling, fashion and parenting.</p>
<p>Clearly, The Knot sees their customer differently. If they earned your trust in helping to plan a wedding, you’re pretty likely to trust them in many of these other areas, too.</p>
<p>I think more dating sites should take that approach, frankly, but it requires a long-term vision most don’t care for.</p>
<p>With a dating site, you could easily emulate the existing dating sites like OkCupid, and then after a successful match start offering services, content, and products to move them to engagement products, wedding products (divorce products <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> ), and so forth.</p>
<p>But first, you have to have the guts and the strategy for solving the marketplace conundrum.</p>
<p>I’d love to hear more fresh ideas on how to defeat the marketplace dragon inherent in these matching services, personally. Is it absolutely a requirement to have a warchest of cash to throw at marketing, or are there other ways short of taking out a Super Bowl ad?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/23</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 21:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-23</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[rwillmer]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>There’s 2 problems with the dating agency idea where the end-goal is finding a life-partner:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>It’s a 2-sided marketplace (generally recognised as a Really Hard Business Model)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When you achieve Customer Success, your revenue stops (usually you’d expect more money at this point)</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Not saying you shouldn’t do it, but those are the 2 problems I think you need to think about really seriously</p>
<p>Rachel</p>
<p>P.S. If you haven’t listened to Series 2 of the “Startup” podcast, it would be worth a listen; the company they follow is a dating agency.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/22</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 15:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-22</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[craigvn]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="19" data-topic="3944">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse.org/v2/letter/c/3bc359/40.png" class="avatar"> Cheez:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>So we’re all fucked.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Cheer up dude <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>I do agree dating sites are mostly made from the perspective of men though.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/21</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 09:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-21</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[globalwj]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I wonder if there is some way to run a dating site like the TV shows Bachelor/Bachelorette. You vet one person yourself (they get it free with the qualification that they have to go on a date with the person they select out of the bracket) while 16 or 32 people enter the bracket to go on a date with them.</p>
<p>Maybe run multiple brackets at a time and sell one entry for $10.</p>
<p>If they are open to the public maybe let other members contact people that didn’t get selected in other brackets that they watched.</p>
<p>Not saying it is better but might be different.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/20</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 01:07:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-20</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheez]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>TL;DR Don’t do a dating website.</p>
<p>Dating sites are an exercise in futility. You will not find fulfillment in a dating site for the simple reason that most people on dating sites have absolutely no idea on how to enter a relationship. Here is it how it works in the real world:</p>
<ol>
<li>I see you</li>
<li>I think you’re hot</li>
<li>We hang out and do it ASAP</li>
<li>Instant relationship (ok, hookup culture has changed this to FWB, but I’m old school)</li>
<li>Marriage</li>
<li>Kids</li>
<li>Divorce</li>
<li>Homelessness/Alcoholism</li>
<li>Death</li>
</ol>
<p>Dating sites think that you can move steps 1,2 online. Haha. No. Do you know what women find attractive? Hint: it’s absolutely NOT the visual. I’ve dated women way out of my physical league who absolutely adore me years after we dated and I am quite possibly the ugliest fucker you’ll meet. They think about me even after they are in relationships which makes me uncomfortable but hey…</p>
<p>Dating sites are made by stupid men who don’t understand how attraction works. Yes, the muscle bro will most definitely get dates and has a leg up. But that’s not the average dude who is usually on such sites.</p>
<p>Quite frankly, women don’t know what attracts them until they see it either.</p>
<p>So we’re all fucked.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/19</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 14:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-19</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>hahahahahahaha.  As they say, “always have a plan B”.  As they also always say, “Always make sure your plan B isn’t a dating site”.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/18</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 17:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-18</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Serge,</p>
<p>I remembered seeing an article that ID’d some challenges with dating sites. This is probably it:<br>
<a href="http://andrewchen.co/why-investors-dont-fund-dating/" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://andrewchen.co/why-investors-dont-fund-dating/</a></p>
<p>Some of these issues are investor-specific but still good to know.</p>
<p>Here’s the HN discussion of it, which should provide more opinions:<br>
<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9606572" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9606572</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/17</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 05:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-17</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pjc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Kalen let’s just say that my domain name <a href="http://Judge.me" rel="nofollow noopener">Judge.me</a> lends itself very well to a dating service like this and that’s why I may have put some thought into this before deciding on B2B product reviews <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/16</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 02:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-16</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Wow I <em>love</em> those ideas!  Never even used a dating site before but sounds very interesting!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/15</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 02:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-15</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jls]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Dating sites suffer from the user participation problem as any other site that’s reliant on the network effect. The problems are similar to trying to start a forum or message board: Most users are passive. Only a small part of them takes part in discussions and only an even smaller part creates new discussions. But to get those active users you already need to have some content.</p>
<p>And with a dating site you have the added difficulty of trying to get people to pay for your “message” board.</p>
<p>Now no one is going to join an empty message board. And surely no one will pay for using an empty dating site. So you got a problem here: You need to seed the “community”. Most dating sites create fake female profiles, etc. But that’s where your dating site begins to suck for users who really want to find a date there.</p>
<p>Imho dating sites are that bad because that’s how the market dynamics in that niche work. Sure in theory you could do it better - but in practice will you be able to? (Also add the problems the other posters mentioned and you must decide if you could do something better with your time than trying to get a dating site off the ground).</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/14</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 11:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-14</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Almost certainly a waste of your time. Dare I say, it would be “stupid”? <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> (I feel rude writing that, but you did ask…)</p>
<p>The reason online dating sites generally suck is that they are trying to solve a really hard problem. Probably as hard as the real-life version of dating.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/13</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 09:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-13</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pjc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>One thing that would have value is one time background and id/picture check before joining the service. Then free forever. Charge guys only, girls get it for free. Charge at level to get 50/50 ratio and market this benefit to guys. Market safety aspect (and verified income level) to girls.</p>
<p>That’s how I would do it.</p>
<p>Edit: you could upsell recurring background checks also.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/12</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 06:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-12</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kalenjordan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I think a productized service in this space could be interesting. See if you can get 100 people to pay $100/month for basically a curated matchmaking service.</p>
<p>That would allow you to get some cash flow sooner than later and provide clear differentiation from the self serve services that have a lot of issues and pain points.</p>
<p>Then long term you try to build a full on product out of it it this could give you a decent path to it.</p>
<p>That said - doing something b2b would probably be much more advisable.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/11</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 02:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-11</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Serge]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I really enjoyed this article… Thanks… that is quite a nice blog you have there… I enjoyed the article about how you are not a typical software entrepreneur… lol</p>
<p>Thanks for this…</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/10</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 01:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-10</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Serge]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Oh I know it’s a trap… lol but darn… the current offerings are so bad… but sometimes I wonder if they are bad because their users are bad… lol</p>
<p>I am flying to a customer today… will read the linked material when I am at the hotel…</p>
<p>Thanks for the good words… lol</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/9</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 20:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-9</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Clay_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This deserves TWO LIKES!!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/8</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 16:56:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-8</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[earlybits]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/serge">@Serge</a> please listen to the second session of the startup podcast to understand why this is a difficult market to enter</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/7</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 16:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-7</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="3" data-topic="3944">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/serge/40/2473_1.png" class="avatar"> Serge:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Maybe I am drunken by the size of the market…</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://secure.gravatar.com/blavatar/948a0589cb38d1d19bd209aa8afb18b6?s=32" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://successfulsoftware.net/2013/03/11/the-1-percent-fallacy/" target="_blank" title="05:06PM - 11 March 2013" rel="nofollow noopener">Successful Software – 11 Mar 13</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://secure.gravatar.com/blavatar/948a0589cb38d1d19bd209aa8afb18b6?s=200&amp;ts=1513727744" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="200" height="200">

<h3><a href="https://successfulsoftware.net/2013/03/11/the-1-percent-fallacy/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">The 1% fallacy</a></h3>

<p>Here is how to make a fortune writing software: Pick a large and established software market e.g. back-up, anti-virus or customer relationship management (CRM) software. Write a new product for tha…</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/6</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-6</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[tnorthcutt]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><em>Note: you did say stop you, and called it stupid yourself.</em></p>
<p>Two-sided marketplace businesses are notoriously difficult to build. Why would you set yourself up for failure by starting on a difficulty setting of “every bad guy is replaced with the final boss from the final level”? Your <em>only</em> advantage is that you’re part of your target market. So what? That describes what, 50% of businesses? You wouldn’t hear someone say “I love bread so I’m going to open a bakery” and think “now that’s a decision based on sound business principles!”, would you?</p>
<p>Start on a lower difficulty setting. Don’t try to build a two-sided marketplace.</p>
<p><a href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/8231936/gifs/ackbar-trap.jpg" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/8231936/gifs/ackbar-trap.jpg</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 15:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-5</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[shantnu]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="3944">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc3.discourse-cdn.com/business6/user_avatar/discuss.bootstrapped.fm/serge/40/2473_1.png" class="avatar"> Serge:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>it is a very big market…</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>The size of the market doesn’t matter, unless you can sell into it.</p>
<p>To start off, do you know <strong>why</strong> the current <em>dating sites fail</em>?</p>
<p>For that matter, why does most dating fail in the real world?</p>
<p>Is this a problem that can be solved by technology?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 09:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Stop me from doing something stupid</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Serge]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I just don’t understand why these sites don’t simply shut down some country’s IPs…</p>
<p>I am just wondering… . It is a real problem that is out there to solve… however one could argue that with all the solutions out there it just might be unsolvable…</p>
<p>Eharmony… Elite singles… darn… have you seen how much those companies rake up?</p>
<p>Maybe I am drunken by the size of the market…</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 21:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-3944-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/stop-me-from-doing-something-stupid/3944.rss">Stop me from doing something stupid</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
