<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Introducing Corrello - Simple Trello dashboards for teams</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-corrello-simple-trello-dashboards-for-teams/2976</link>
    <description>Hi folks,

I&#39;ve been bootstrapping products in my spare time for a few years but haven&#39;t hit any major financial success yet. I left my full time job in January when voluntary redundancy came up and have been full time on my own projects since then. 

I&#39;m close (a matter of days) to completing v1 of my first project [Corrello][1], a dashboard and reporting tool for teams using Trello. I&#39;d love to hear any feedback people have on the landing page, concept or product itself. The landing page should hopefully explain what it does so I&#39;ll not repeat it all here :smile: .

Cheers,
Robin

  [1]: http://getcorrello.com</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 10:29:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Show Bootstrapped</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-corrello-simple-trello-dashboards-for-teams/2976.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Corrello - Simple Trello dashboards for teams</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[robinwarren]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi folks,</p>
<p>I’ve been bootstrapping products in my spare time for a few years but haven’t hit any major financial success yet. I left my full time job in January when voluntary redundancy came up and have been full time on my own projects since then.</p>
<p>I’m close (a matter of days) to completing v1 of my first project <a href="http://getcorrello.com" rel="nofollow noopener">Corrello</a>, a dashboard and reporting tool for teams using Trello. I’d love to hear any feedback people have on the landing page, concept or product itself. The landing page should hopefully explain what it does so I’ll not repeat it all here <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"> .</p>
<p>Cheers,<br>
Robin</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-corrello-simple-trello-dashboards-for-teams/2976/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-corrello-simple-trello-dashboards-for-teams/2976/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 10:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2976-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/introducing-corrello-simple-trello-dashboards-for-teams/2976.rss">Introducing Corrello - Simple Trello dashboards for teams</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
