<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Mark the new guy</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-the-new-guy/2258</link>
    <description>Greetings to all,

For at least the last 10 years I&#39;ve developed in PHP, writing various back-end scripts, a couple websites, etc.  I tried several frameworks (CakePHP, CI, and others) but struggled building a full-blown site.  Almost 2 years ago I was introduced to Laravel and not only was I able to build a site pretty easily, but I actually understood how it worked. :smile:

About that same time, a family member came to me with a need for a central database for a ministry they maintain.  They were using spreadsheets and documents to store their information, and an online storage company to share the data.  It became a nightmare to manage.  With a heavy DB background and PHP experience under my belt, I set off to develop a site using Laravel to manage their data.   About a year later, I had a full site working for them.  With a full-time job, that required a lot of nights and weekends!  I knew I wouldn&#39;t get paid for this job, and I doubted that it would ever be used by anyone else, but hoped to use this experience later.

As I was getting close to launching that project, a good friend of mine was experiencing a similar discomfort of managing a healthcare based business with spreadsheets and documents, using e-mail to share them, etc.  I saw  an opportunity to take what I&#39;ve already done and conform it to their business.  Again using Laravel, I created a site and they were on a beta version not long after the launch of the first site.  In fact, we just celebrated a year since the launch!

This last site has huge potential to become a profitable SaaS.  I&#39;ve got a couple of milestones that I need to reach before a full public launch.  Unfortunately, with a full-time job and a thriving family, time is very hard to come by.  But I&#39;m staying diligent with finding time in hopes that it will pay off.

Finding this discussion group has been a blessing.  Lots of good information and encouragement.  I hope to contribute my experiences in hopes to help others as well.

Thanks!
Mark Pemberton
North Carolina, USA</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 18:27:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-the-new-guy/2258.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Mark the new guy</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[coreysnipes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Welcome Mark, sounds like things are happening for you!  I look forward to hearing more.  “They were using spreadsheets and email and it was a nightmare” almost always leads to a good SaaS opportunity.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-the-new-guy/2258/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-the-new-guy/2258/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 18:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2258-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-the-new-guy/2258.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Mark the new guy</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Mark the new guy</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[mpemberton5]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Greetings to all,</p>
<p>For at least the last 10 years I’ve developed in PHP, writing various back-end scripts, a couple websites, etc.  I tried several frameworks (CakePHP, CI, and others) but struggled building a full-blown site.  Almost 2 years ago I was introduced to Laravel and not only was I able to build a site pretty easily, but I actually understood how it worked. <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
<p>About that same time, a family member came to me with a need for a central database for a ministry they maintain.  They were using spreadsheets and documents to store their information, and an online storage company to share the data.  It became a nightmare to manage.  With a heavy DB background and PHP experience under my belt, I set off to develop a site using Laravel to manage their data.   About a year later, I had a full site working for them.  With a full-time job, that required a lot of nights and weekends!  I knew I wouldn’t get paid for this job, and I doubted that it would ever be used by anyone else, but hoped to use this experience later.</p>
<p>As I was getting close to launching that project, a good friend of mine was experiencing a similar discomfort of managing a healthcare based business with spreadsheets and documents, using e-mail to share them, etc.  I saw  an opportunity to take what I’ve already done and conform it to their business.  Again using Laravel, I created a site and they were on a beta version not long after the launch of the first site.  In fact, we just celebrated a year since the launch!</p>
<p>This last site has huge potential to become a profitable SaaS.  I’ve got a couple of milestones that I need to reach before a full public launch.  Unfortunately, with a full-time job and a thriving family, time is very hard to come by.  But I’m staying diligent with finding time in hopes that it will pay off.</p>
<p>Finding this discussion group has been a blessing.  Lots of good information and encouragement.  I hope to contribute my experiences in hopes to help others as well.</p>
<p>Thanks!<br>
Mark Pemberton<br>
North Carolina, USA</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-the-new-guy/2258/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-the-new-guy/2258/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 14:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-2258-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-the-new-guy/2258.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Mark the new guy</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
