<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Mark from PilotLight.io</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-from-pilotlight-io/5042</link>
    <description>Hi All,

Like many, I&#39;ve been lurking for some time and wanted to introduce myself.  

I&#39;ve been involved in startups for the last 25 years and a few years ago started [PilotLight.io](http://www.pilotlight.io).  It&#39;s a one person show and I&#39;ve bootstrapped everything myself (development, marketing, sales, operations, etc.).  A little over a year ago I left a local company to go back out full-time on my own mixing consulting work (to pay the bills) and grow PilotLight.  I&#39;ve got roughly 15 long-term paying customers and with a new version of the service plan to grow it to where it provides all my income along with the ability to work anywhere.

I attended my first MicroConf - Starter this year and have built a small network of mentors here in Boulder, CO that I lean on for guidance on everything from tech to accounting, life-hacking as an entrepreneur, sales and pricing techniques, and more.  

When I&#39;m not in front of the computer toiling away I teach people how to ride their big adventure motorcycles off-road; in particular, BMW adventure bikes.  

Looking forward to learning and sharing with you all!

Mark</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 13:22:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-from-pilotlight-io/5042.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Mark from PilotLight.io</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian_O_Neill]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Mark, it is an interesting product. I assume you are competing with google alerts? Mind you i never get results from google alerts it does not seem to be very active.</p>
<p>I assume you use some kind of custom spider to keep an eye on the forums?</p>
<p>One suggestion. The site design looks really dated, I would give it a new look. You can use a theme to save time <a href="https://themeforest.net/item/stack-multipurpose-html-with-page-builder/19337626" rel="nofollow noopener">https://themeforest.net/item/stack-multipurpose-html-with-page-builder/19337626</a></p>
<p>Best of luck with the service.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-from-pilotlight-io/5042/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-from-pilotlight-io/5042/4</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 13:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-5042-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-from-pilotlight-io/5042.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Mark from PilotLight.io</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Mark from PilotLight.io</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[SteveMcLeod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Welcome Mark. (I’ve edited your post to make your site clickable.)</p>
<p>Your product sounds really good. I used to pay a friend to do something similar for me - to go through a bunch of forums every day looking for discussions of my product and alerting me to where I could respond or intervene. So I can certainly see the value of your product.</p>
<p>I like that you are bold enough to charge decent money for your product.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-from-pilotlight-io/5042/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-from-pilotlight-io/5042/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 12:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-5042-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-from-pilotlight-io/5042.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Mark from PilotLight.io</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Mark from PilotLight.io</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Eccountability]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Mark.<br>
You should explain what PilotLight is and does. I had to cut and paste to go to the website.</p>
<p>Good luck with your project<br>
Ronan</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-from-pilotlight-io/5042/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-from-pilotlight-io/5042/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 05:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-5042-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-from-pilotlight-io/5042.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Mark from PilotLight.io</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m Mark from PilotLight.io</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[mark5280]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi All,</p>
<p>Like many, I’ve been lurking for some time and wanted to introduce myself.</p>
<p>I’ve been involved in startups for the last 25 years and a few years ago started <a href="http://www.pilotlight.io" rel="nofollow noopener">PilotLight.io</a>.  It’s a one person show and I’ve bootstrapped everything myself (development, marketing, sales, operations, etc.).  A little over a year ago I left a local company to go back out full-time on my own mixing consulting work (to pay the bills) and grow PilotLight.  I’ve got roughly 15 long-term paying customers and with a new version of the service plan to grow it to where it provides all my income along with the ability to work anywhere.</p>
<p>I attended my first MicroConf - Starter this year and have built a small network of mentors here in Boulder, CO that I lean on for guidance on everything from tech to accounting, life-hacking as an entrepreneur, sales and pricing techniques, and more.</p>
<p>When I’m not in front of the computer toiling away I teach people how to ride their big adventure motorcycles off-road; in particular, BMW adventure bikes.</p>
<p>Looking forward to learning and sharing with you all!</p>
<p>Mark</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-from-pilotlight-io/5042/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-from-pilotlight-io/5042/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 17:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-5042-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-mark-from-pilotlight-io/5042.rss">Hi, I&#39;m Mark from PilotLight.io</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
