<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m David and I work on LiberWriter</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874</link>
    <description>I realized that I never posted an introduction here, as I discovered this forum just before going to MicroConf Europe.

I&#39;m from Oregon in the US, but reside in Padova (Padua) Italy, where I do consulting and also work on http://www.liberwriter.com - which to date is profitable, but not quite enough to quit my day job, yet.  It&#39;s been a very fun project and I&#39;ve learned a ton with it.  Another thing I keep hoping to kick into gear is this: http://www.therealitaly.com/ - but  what with the two things I&#39;ve already got and kids, progress is slow!

As per my standing offer on other forums (I also hang out on HN), I&#39;m always happy to show people around Padova a bit and have a drink.  It&#39;s a nice town, and not far from Venice.

</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 12:55:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m David and I work on LiberWriter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[davidw]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>MicroConf was, as far as I’m concerned, about as good as a conference can be.</p>
<p>The problem was that the amount of really good information I got far, far outstripped my bandwidth to actually do anything with it once I got home, which was frustrating.  Not their fault, of course, but perhaps a reason to skip it if you’re reasoning with your wallet, and not “because it’s fun”.  I think for someone like you who (IIRC) is working on their business full time, it’d be money and time well spent.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 12:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-874-5</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874.rss">Hi, I&#39;m David and I work on LiberWriter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m David and I work on LiberWriter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[rachelandrew]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m hoping to get to MicroConf Europe this year. I find sometimes with the conferences that the benefit is a bit more subtle than just what you can learn - which of course you can get online usually. I find that I come back refreshed and really ready to get down to work when returning from a good conference. If I’m plotting and scheming in my to do lists on the airplane home that’s usually a good sign!</p>
<p>Being around like-minded people is, I think, really valuable. The hallway track is usually the most useful thing.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874/4</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 06:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-874-4</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874.rss">Hi, I&#39;m David and I work on LiberWriter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m David and I work on LiberWriter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[davidw]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks!</p>
<p>Not sure I’ll go back to MicroConf (Europe) or not.  It’s a really, really great conference, but there was so much information, and so little time for me to actually implement it as a bootstrapper, that I think I could have picked up enough from the internet reports of the conference, had an extra weekend to actually work on the product, and saved a bundle of cash.  This is absolutely not a knock on the conference, which is really good and was a whole lot of fun at a personal level.  Mike, Rob, and company put on a really good event!  I am going to write more about this topic sometime, I think, as it’s kind of a conundrum: as a person, I had a lot of fun there and enjoyed it a bunch.  As a homo economicus, I’m not sure it paid for itself.</p>
<p>Sometimes I forget that for a lot of people the idea of living in Italy would be amazing… I guess that’s “hedonistic adaptation” ( <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hedonic_treadmill" rel="nofollow noopener">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hedonic_treadmill</a> ) at work!  I’ve been here long enough that it’s mostly ‘normal’!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 22:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-874-3</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874.rss">Hi, I&#39;m David and I work on LiberWriter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m David and I work on LiberWriter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[anon3850446]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Welcome David! Hope to meet you at MicroConf one day!</p>
<p>Took a look at your LiberWriter web site. That product is a great idea. Writing an ebook that can be sold on multiple platform is a very daunting task.</p>
<p>Coding &amp; living in Italy w/ the whole family – now that’s the dream… <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 16:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-874-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874.rss">Hi, I&#39;m David and I work on LiberWriter</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hi, I&#39;m David and I work on LiberWriter</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[davidw]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I realized that I never posted an introduction here, as I discovered this forum just before going to MicroConf Europe.</p>
<p>I’m from Oregon in the US, but reside in Padova (Padua) Italy, where I do consulting and also work on <a href="http://www.liberwriter.com" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.liberwriter.com</a> - which to date is profitable, but not quite enough to quit my day job, yet.  It’s been a very fun project and I’ve learned a ton with it.  Another thing I keep hoping to kick into gear is this: <a href="http://www.therealitaly.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.therealitaly.com/</a> - but  what with the two things I’ve already got and kids, progress is slow!</p>
<p>As per my standing offer on other forums (I also hang out on HN), I’m always happy to show people around Padova a bit and have a drink.  It’s a nice town, and not far from Venice.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 15:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-874-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hi-im-david-and-i-work-on-liberwriter/874.rss">Hi, I&#39;m David and I work on LiberWriter</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
