<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hey, I&#39;m Kacper from Scrapbook</title>
    <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-kacper-from-scrapbook/7082</link>
    <description>Hey guys,

I&#39;m surprised I found this great community only now!

I&#39;m a growth marketer currently working full-time at Prowly PR software (prowly.com), leading a small team of 2. Before that, I got some agency experience at Ladder.

My latest (and first) side-project that I&#39;m mostly focused on right now is Scrapbook (getscrapbook.com) which is a database of over 250 growth tactics that I&#39;ve been collecting for the last 2 years or so. Initially, it was for personal use only, but after sharing it with some friends and getting great feedback, I decided to create a product out of it.

Looking forward to some meaningful conversations with other bootstrappers!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 21:14:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-kacper-from-scrapbook/7082.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hey, I&#39;m Kacper from Scrapbook</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[KacperStaniul]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey guys,</p>
<p>I’m surprised I found this great community only now!</p>
<p>I’m a growth marketer currently working full-time at Prowly PR software (<a href="http://prowly.com">prowly.com</a>), leading a small team of 2. Before that, I got some agency experience at Ladder.</p>
<p>My latest (and first) side-project that I’m mostly focused on right now is Scrapbook (<a href="http://getscrapbook.com">getscrapbook.com</a>) which is a database of over 250 growth tactics that I’ve been collecting for the last 2 years or so. Initially, it was for personal use only, but after sharing it with some friends and getting great feedback, I decided to create a product out of it.</p>
<p>Looking forward to some meaningful conversations with other bootstrappers!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-kacper-from-scrapbook/7082/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-kacper-from-scrapbook/7082/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 21:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.bootstrapped.fm-post-7082-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.bootstrapped.fm/t/hey-im-kacper-from-scrapbook/7082.rss">Hey, I&#39;m Kacper from Scrapbook</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
